<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Around the world in 80 days</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/</link><description>Blog for an 80 day coding and exercise experiment.</description><atom:link href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/rss.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2014 20:52:31 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Global Hackathon, Team Bermuda</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/global-hackathon-team-bermuda.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last weekend I took part in the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/worlds-first-global-hackathon.html"&gt;global hackathon&lt;/a&gt; run by
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/https//koding.com"&gt;koding.com&lt;/a&gt; as part of Team Bermuda aka &lt;em&gt;Three&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=aceboy"&gt;ace-boys&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;and an&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Acegirl"&gt;ace-girl&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other members of the team were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nick Hoskins, the one who told us all about it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beckett Simmons, residing &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/https//koding.com"&gt;koding.com&lt;/a&gt; expert&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Veronica Windus, working remotely from the frozen wastes of Canada&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea was to create a web based application in 48 hours.  There
were five themes to choose from, we chose:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
No one reads the fine print (ie TOS, EULA, legal documents) anymore
yet every site has them. Devise a creative/interactive solution.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, before we could start we needed a name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the average EULA is about as easy to read as the classic, James
Joyce' &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ulysses_%28novel%29"&gt;Ulysees&lt;/a&gt; we took the liberty of borrowing the name, and then
abusing it and came up with, &lt;em&gt;Eulasees&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a tenuous link with Bermuda in that many songs of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thomas_Moore"&gt;Thomas
Moore&lt;/a&gt; who lived in Bermuda for a while, are cited in the works of
James Joyce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, back to the hackathon.  This nominally started at 4am Bermuda time
on Saturday 6th December.  Team Bermuda hence decided to start work at
10am, gathering at the Watford Sports Club.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, things got off to a slow start due to several factors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;lack of coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, there was coffee, but we only had a tiny bodum to make it
in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;A fellow &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sheffield_United_F.C."&gt;Blade&lt;/a&gt; turned up at the sports club.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, blades are rare as hen's teeth, so progress came to a
complete standstill whilst yours truly reminisced about the good old
days when the Mighty Blades were in the heady heights of the first
division (technically, they are still in the first division, it is
just that now first really means third, English footy uses a weird
number system).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;At least one of us working on a laptop that was missing lots of the
standard development packages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Flaky wifi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;No real idea what we were going to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was very much a &lt;em&gt;make it up as you go along&lt;/em&gt; event.   We talked
about a few ideas, delegated lots of stuff to our ace-girl, who was
presumably still digging out from under a snow storm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rough plan was a to create a restful API with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.djangoproject.com/"&gt;django&lt;/a&gt; and build
an &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://angularjs.org/"&gt;angular.js&lt;/a&gt; front end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea was to load EULA's into the system, allow users to highlight
areas of text and apply &lt;em&gt;tags&lt;/em&gt; to these areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These &lt;em&gt;tags&lt;/em&gt; would have a short name indicating what the contract
clause really meant and a longer text body explaining what it was all
about really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we had this and some data in the system the plan was to create
some views allowing users to see which EULA's had which clauses and
other such fun stuff.  One idea was to add a quiz, getting people to
guess whose EULA had which clause, possibly using &lt;cite&gt;django quiz&lt;/cite&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most of Saturday we pretty much ignored the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/https//koding.com"&gt;koding.com&lt;/a&gt; virtual
machine, we were having enough other problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, the &lt;em&gt;angular&lt;/em&gt; stuff was going quite well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The django side was going a bit slower.  We were using &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://cookiecutter.readthedocs.org/en/latest/"&gt;cookiecutter&lt;/a&gt;
to create all the base files for our django apps and project.  This
works really well, but does come with a lot of extra goodness that we
probably did not need at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;pip install&lt;/em&gt; kept failing on obscure compile errors due to missing
&lt;em&gt;-dev&lt;/em&gt; packages.  I love pip, but with a big requirements list and a
dodgy wifi connection the downloads were taking way too long and I
couldn't get it to cache things reliably.  More on this later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having said that, being able to do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
python setup.py register
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Followed by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
python setup.py publish
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make the django app available on PyPi (and hence &lt;em&gt;pip install&lt;/em&gt;
magic just works), was very cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things went well on the Saturday.   Mid-evening we stopped for food
and more coffee (by now Nick had brought a decent sized bodum down
from his house, so the coffee shortage was averted).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to work until we were too tired, then get some sleep ready
to code until 4am on Monday morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is all a bit of a blur now, but at some point we decided we should
see if any of our stuff actually works on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/https//koding.com"&gt;koding.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sure the koding.com IDE is a joy to use, but now was not the time
to learn it.  Fortunately, Beckett had given us the number one pro-tip
for using koding.com:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Getting ssh to koding working is well worth the effort&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further, it didn't involve anything more than adding an ssh key to the
&lt;em&gt;~/.ssh/.authorized_keys&lt;/em&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suddenly &lt;em&gt;pip install&lt;/em&gt; was flying along.  Clearly, we should have been
doing everything on the koding machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having noted how well the koding VM was working, of course, we
continued to work locally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were, in fact, so effective at this that it was midnight on Sunday
before we decided it would be a good idea if the angular front end
could talk to the django rest API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No prizes for guessing the answer to this: hell no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Angular was either failing completely to connect to the django API
giving obscure messages about &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cross-site_request_forgery"&gt;cross-site request forgery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point we probably should have left the angular front end as an
example of where we were heading and just fed it some toy data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead we learnt way more about csrf's than we ever wanted to know,
in between cursing django for its attentiveness to security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After much thrashing around &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/ottoyiu/django-cors-headers"&gt;django cors&lt;/a&gt; came to the rescue.  By
now, however, it was past 3am and Nick was having to use a new
function to make the restful API calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got the two pieces talking, but ran out of time to fix up enough of
the angular code to get a viable front end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project code is on github, as &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/swfiua/eulasees"&gt;eulasees&lt;/a&gt;, with the the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/swfiua/django_eulasees"&gt;django
eulasees&lt;/a&gt; app in a separate repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also view the docs for the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://swfiua.koding.io:8000/docs/"&gt;eulasees API&lt;/a&gt; that was created.
These are created with the amazing &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/marcgibbons/django-rest-swagger"&gt;django rest swagger&lt;/a&gt; and allow
you to try out the API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did manage to load some data into the system, with the django admin
system coming to the rescue as the user interface of last resort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should probably apologise to google, since their &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/terms/"&gt;terms of
service&lt;/a&gt; was the toy example we decided to use.  You can actually get
all the data that we entered with this &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://swfiua.koding.io:8000/eulasees/everythingforeula/4/"&gt;one API call&lt;/a&gt;.  So, if there
are any google lawyers reading: we love you really, we know you are
not &lt;em&gt;evil&lt;/em&gt;.  Just one question: what is with the paragraphs IN ALL
CAPS?  ARE WE BACK IN THE 90's ON A SHOUTY FORUM?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remarkably, we got an email yesterday informing us we made it through
to the next round of the competition.  We can only assume that pretty
much everyone that got any sort of site up got through the first
round.  You can even &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hackathon.koding.com/entries/team-bermuda"&gt;VOTE FOR US&lt;/a&gt; :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>hackathon</category><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/global-hackathon-team-bermuda.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2014 22:37:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Using gnus for Gmail</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/using-gnus-for-gmail.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;My primary email account is with Gmail.  Overall it works pretty
well.  In particular, it works well on the phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I have been finding email less and less effective as a
communication medium of late, for a number of reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;There is too much clutter there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not really spam, but over the years too many organisations have got
my email address.  Sometimes this is good: booking flights or hotels
or whatever, the emails they send are useful, but then they send a
bundle of spam and special offers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Some key contacts don't really use email.  Not naming names, but
the younger you are the less likely it is that email will be your
default way to communicate electronically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;The Gmail interface in chrome is a resource hog.  Further it does
not make good use of the real estate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;The editor for writing emails is ok, but rather limited&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Some simple things are hard/impossible to do.  For example,
sometimes I am working on a draft and want to share the draft with
someone else, leaving the draft in the drafts folder.  No can do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;I started using the amazing &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://vimium.github.io/"&gt;vimium&lt;/a&gt; plugin in Chrome.  For Gmail
to work you have to switch off Vimium, but then you are left with
tabs where the Vimium shortcuts don't work.  So, I think it is best
to read email elsewhere.  I tried a browser window just for email,
but I end up opening new tabs, so that quickly fails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many years back I used to use RMAIL in emacs.  It was a powerful
client and I am left with my favourite editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, asking google for &lt;em&gt;emacs email client&lt;/em&gt; the answer that comes back
is gnus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.emacswiki.org/emacs/GnusGmail"&gt;quickstart&lt;/a&gt; on EmacsWiki was enough to get me as far as seeing
my gmail in emacs.  I even managed to read a few emails and may have
replied to one or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have dabbled in gnus before, but it seems to have taken on a whole
new life since then.  I suspect a large part of the rest of this week,
or maybe this month is going to go on figuring out how it all works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far though, I am liking it, so it is a good start.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/using-gnus-for-gmail.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 22:17:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>More on django-allauth</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/more-on-django-allauth.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Armed with the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.sarahhagstrom.com/2013/09/the-missing-django-allauth-tutorial/"&gt;missing django-allauth tutorial&lt;/a&gt; I have made some
progress getting auth working with &lt;em&gt;google&lt;/em&gt; doing as the
authentication provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sarah's guide pretty much covered everything I needed to know.  It
also encouraged me to work towards pushing out a bare-bones &lt;strong&gt;80
days&lt;/strong&gt; site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This actually makes sense as I don't need the whole site up and
running just for users to register for the competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The missing tutorial uses &lt;em&gt;facebook&lt;/em&gt; as the example.  Unfortunately, I
could not figure out how to register my application and get the
necessary keys on facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, I decided to have a go at using &lt;em&gt;google&lt;/em&gt;.   I quickly found
this &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://developers.google.com/+/quickstart/python"&gt;google guide&lt;/a&gt; which was enough to get my application registered
and get the necessary keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then it was back to the missing manual.   I actually used the &lt;em&gt;django
admin&lt;/em&gt; interface to update the django database, rather than run the
SQL as per the tutorial.  This was just a matter of going to this url:
&lt;em&gt;http://127.0.0.1:8000/admin/socialaccount/socialapp/&lt;/em&gt; and entering a
new record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still had a couple of errors to get by.  First, I copy/pasted the
configuration information from the missint tutorial and had to remove
the &lt;em&gt;publish_stream&lt;/em&gt; scope as google does not support that (at least I
assume that is what the problem is).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next I had to go back to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://console.developers.google.com"&gt;Google Developer Console&lt;/a&gt; and register
the callback url that my application was trying to use.  Bingo,
everything works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, with this setup, new users can just sign in with their google
account and the application will set up a user registration for them
if one does not already exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The down side with all this is that there are a plethora of
authentication providers I should probably support:  facebook,
twitter, yahoom, linkedIn, github, etc, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really, this whole system is horribly broken.  Every social media site
has its own identity management implementation and it, naturally,
wants everyone to use their identity management.   In short, they all
want to own your identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we really need is for users to be able to manage their own
identity, without need to for a central authority.  The central
authority is a critical security weakness as if that authority is
compromised all users using that authority are compromised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A secondary problem is that the current OAuth/OpenID solutions result
in everybody wanting to be the central authority and hence users are
faced with either balkanisation of identiy management or having to
manage multiple identities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, I do not see an end to this in the short term, not least
because the current mess suits all the current incumbents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/more-on-django-allauth.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 20:34:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bootstrap css, allauth and initial site</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/bootstrap-css-allauth-and-initial-site.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Write your post here.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/bootstrap-css-allauth-and-initial-site.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 18:05:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Django allauth</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/django-allauth.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the 80 days project I decided to use the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django-allauth.readthedocs.org/"&gt;django-allauth&lt;/a&gt; package
to handle authentication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I say I decided, the decision was actually made by the django
project &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://cookiecutter.readthedocs.org/en/latest/"&gt;cookiecutter&lt;/a&gt; I used to create the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should provide lots of goodness in that it will allow users to
register and log in to the site using social media OpenID
authentication.  At least, I think that what it does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time to read the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.sarahhagstrom.com/2013/09/the-missing-django-allauth-tutorial/"&gt;missing-django-allauth-tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/django-allauth.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 21:04:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The imitation game</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/the-imitation-game.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The other day, Nick Hoskins posted a link to an intriguing puzzle, the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://imitationgame.withgoogle.com/"&gt;Imitation Game Puzzle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried very hard not to click on the link.  There was a picture of
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alan_Turing"&gt;Alan Turing&lt;/a&gt;, a puzzle and a competition.  Oh, and it was all run
by the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://google.com"&gt;Chocolate Factory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2084970/"&gt;The Imitation Game&lt;/a&gt; film has just been released, hence the timing of
the puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I clicked on the link.   Pictures of the bombe's that were used to
break Enigma in the Second World War.  Another picture of Alan Turing
and a little piece about the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turing_test"&gt;Turing Test&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, one of the premises of the puzzle was to prove you are not a
computer, in effect a reverse Turing Test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I clicked on the link to download the pdf with the details of the
puzzle.  I was delighted to find what looked like a scan of a
type-written document.  This reminded me of working on puzzles with my
mum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mum loved crosswords.  Her favourite was to find a puzzle in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.theguardian.com/uk"&gt;The
Guardian&lt;/a&gt; compiled by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Galbraith_Graham"&gt;Araucaria&lt;/a&gt;.  I can still recall her telling
me how araucaria is the Latin name for tne &lt;em&gt;monkey puzzle&lt;/em&gt; tree, with
a twinkle in her eye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At holiday times Araucaria would often create a special, puzzle.  The
puzzles could keep you amused for days.   We would both take a look at
them, get a few clues, then give up in despair.  Mum would usually be
more persistent than me.   Maybe she would be cooking dinner and I
would be sat talking to her in the kitchen.  Happiness was solving a
clue together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I learnt from this is that talking to others about problems
helps you see them more clearly.  My mind works that way for sure.  It
doesn't matter if the person you are talking fully understands, so
long as they are engaged and interested it helps you find out what
assumptions you are making, it raises questions and you get a second
perspective on the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mum used to subscribe to special puzzles that Araucaria produced a few
times a year.   They would arrive in the post, printed on paper and
looked like they were copies of an original from a type-writer -- just
like the Imitation Game puzzle.   I was hooked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year I visited Bletchley Park with my wife and family.
The two boys are very interested in history and know way more than
anyone of their age normally does about the world wars.  Indeed, if a
Turing Test was done on either of them you might well conclude that
they are in fact computers since no human being could reasonably be
expected to know as much as they do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The visit to Bletchley was a bit disappointing, our timing was bad as
they were just putting the finishing touches to some new exhibits so
parts of the museum were closed.  However, we did get to see the
re-constructed bombe working.   These bombe's were basically
electro-mechanical special purpose parallel computers.  They allowed
vast numbers of enigma settings to be tried as the initial part of an
attack on the Enigma ciphers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The competition is still on-going, so I should not spoil the fun.
Suffice to say, the puzzle came at just the right time for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been going through a very difficult time, so to be able to get
away from everything for a few hours and immerse myself in the puzzle
was very therapeutic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My poor wife had to put up with an entire weekend of bizarre questions
about a whole range of strange subjects.  She was an immense help as I
worked through the puzzle.  I was reminded of sitting round the
kitchen table with my mother, happy times indeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Araucaria would have been proud of this puzzle, many thanks to those
at Google that created the puzzle and helped me through this very
difficult time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/the-imitation-game.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 14:22:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Star Trek universal translator</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/star-trek-universal-translator.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This theme from the global &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://koding.com/Hackathon"&gt;hackathon&lt;/a&gt;  really interests me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
Challenges associated with real time communication and translation
(Star Trek universal translator anyone?)
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am finding computer interfaces becoming more and more annoying.  I
interact with computers through different interfaces: mobile phones,
tablets, infra-red remotes, workstations etc etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each application has its own idea of how it wants me to work with it.
Some have discoverable interfaces.  Some are close to unusable from a
mobile phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I am thinking is what we need is a layer that sits between input
devices and applications.   I guess we already have this, it is called
an operating system.   But currently, all these tend to do is
implement the drivers needed to talk to the input device and simply
pass on the events to applications running on the O/S.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Events tend to be pretty low level things like &lt;em&gt;button click&lt;/em&gt;,
&lt;em&gt;keyboard keypress&lt;/em&gt; etc etc.   If we had more sophisticated input
devices, or rather a layer listening to existing inputs (for instance
why not use the webcam too to observe what the user is doing, or the
mic to listen.  With this information it ought to be easier to guess
what the user is really trying to do.   Applications could then be
build that accepted a much richer set of events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;go to next page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;go back, I just clicked the screen by mistake&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;damn you autocorrect, stop guessing and just enter the word I have
typed three times already&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OK, usually when he does this he wants out of netflix and into xbmc,
so why don't I just offer to take him there?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;of course, the OS should learn from you as you interact with it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and we don't want to end up with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Office_Assistant"&gt;clippy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there is social media, I am signed up to way to many sevices:
twitter, email, google+, github, facebook, koding.com, irc, blogs etc
etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ttwick.com/"&gt;ttwick&lt;/a&gt; looks like it might have a solution to the problem of keeping
track of everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a whole bunch of privacy issues to worry about here.  Any
interface listening to user inputs is seeing some very personal
information.  My guess is the way you type on a keyboard is a pretty
unique identifier, perhaps as distinctive as your DNA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for apps to really behave well for you they might need to know this
information that identifies who you are.  But who do you really want
to share that information with?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now if the OS translated the inputs coming from devices into a
standard, rich event stream then it might be that it could do it in
such a way as the event stream was less of a personal marker and so we
could get a double win of greater privacy and a more unified interface
to interact with computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This whole area is really an accessibility thing.  But for too long
accessibility has been some extra thing you do to support people with
disabilities.  It isn't built into apps from the ground up.  Further,
it singles out those with disabilities: poor vision, paralysis, poor
motor skills, etc etc.   The reality is that everyone needs better
interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we out a layer between our input devices and our applications we
can start working on those better interfaces.  For everybody.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am reminded of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OWyMA_bT7UI"&gt;Tavis Rudd&lt;/a&gt; at PyCon 2014 talking about controlling
emacs with his voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So again, all we need here is a layer listening to his voice and
converting the voice into instructions for emacs.  Now if that layer
could learn as it was used, we might have something special.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/star-trek-universal-translator.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 18:26:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World's first global hackathon</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/worlds-first-global-hackathon.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/https//koding.com"&gt;koding.com&lt;/a&gt; they are running a global hackathon for the
weekend of 6/7 December.   It is an exciting project, with people
participating all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is for teams of up to 5 to work on projects along the
following 5 themes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Problems facing our planet, explained using interactive data visualization. (e.g. climate change, earthquakes, food/water waste, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introducing software development to a beginner (games!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No one reads the fine print (ie TOS, EULA, legal documents) anymore yet every site has them. Devise a creative/interactive solution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HTML5 games that are educational and learning oriented. (multiplayer preferred)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Challenges associated with real time communication and translation
(Star Trek universal translator anyone?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some great themes there, many of them relate directly to
Bermuda.   For example, maybe we could build a simple hurricane model,
using data from the recent storms to allow people to explore the
impact of global warming on Bermuda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, I have been working on this 80 days project.  Progress is
proving difficult due to the amount of wonderful stuff there is out
there that can be used in the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am hoping to be able to use the hackathon to learn a couple more
tools and to start making real progress on 80 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would also be interesting to try and work with hackers on other
small islands.  One challenge here in Bermuda is, at least for now,
our numbers are small.  Other small islands have similary issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be good if we could perhaps work with people at the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hackerspaces.org/wiki/Cyberhippietotalism"&gt;Lanzarote
hackbase&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a personal point of view, I also have some contacts in Ireland,
so maybe we could stretch the definition of small a little to include
Ireland too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there are the Azores and the Caribbean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Theme 5 is all about translation.  It would be cool if we could make
our site multi-lingual:  English, Portuguese, Bermudian slang etc,
etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One suggestion is to actually work towards having another hackathon
event in the near future, a &lt;em&gt;Small Island Hackathon&lt;/em&gt;.   Is there any
interest in using the global hackathon as an opportunity to build a
site for a small island event.   Perhaps we could have it coincide
with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bermudaraceweekend.com/site/"&gt;Bermuda Race Weekend&lt;/a&gt; January 16-18th 2015.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/worlds-first-global-hackathon.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 18:01:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Nikola, django packages, cookiecutter and other goodness</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/nikola-django-packages-cookiecutter-and-other-goodness.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have been spending some time looking at tools to help with the 80
days project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="nikola"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;nikola&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up on the list was &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://getnikola.com/"&gt;nikola&lt;/a&gt;.   This is a static site generator.
I was mostly interested in it because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it plays nicely with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pages.github.com/"&gt;gh-pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it allows you to write blog entries with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ipython.org/notebook.html"&gt;ipython notebooks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it is built in python.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran into one problem with nikola, see this &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/getnikola/nikola/issues/1496"&gt;nikola_issue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happily, within three minutes of reporting the problem the maintainer
posted a solution, even though the issue I reported was a dupe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="django-packages-and-cookiecutter"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;django packages and cookiecutter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I am working on a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.djangoproject.com/"&gt;django&lt;/a&gt; project I took a look at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.djangopackages.com/"&gt;django
packages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My attention was quickly drawn by &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://cookiecutter.readthedocs.org/en/latest/"&gt;cookiecutter&lt;/a&gt; in the featured
grid. Cookie cutter creates projects from templates, so saving a lot
of tedious work.  It comes with a list of available cookiecutters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a bit spoilt for choice, but I decided to give the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/pydanny/cookiecutter-djangopackage"&gt;cookiecutter
djangopackage&lt;/a&gt; a go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far I am pleased with this choice.  The docs led me through
creating the django app, adding it to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django-eighty-days.readthedocs.org/en/latest/"&gt;readthedocs&lt;/a&gt; and registering
it with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pypi.python.org/pypi?%3Aaction=pkg_edit&amp;amp;name=django-eighty-days"&gt;PyPi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, a very painless way to get lots of goodies up and running
for the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I just need to write some actual code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/nikola-django-packages-cookiecutter-and-other-goodness.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 17:23:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Calculating 80 days from now</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/calculating-80-days-from-now.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div tabindex="-1" id="notebook" class="border-box-sizing"&gt;
    &lt;div class="container" id="notebook-container"&gt;

&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="checking-when-80-days-from-the-start-of-the-project-is"&gt;Checking when 80 days from the start of the project is&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first commit to github was done on 15th November 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I had been working on the project for a couple of days by then, so I will take 13th November 2014 as the start date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing code_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="input"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
In [1]:
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
    &lt;div class="input_area"&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;datetime&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing code_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="input"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
In [3]:
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
    &lt;div class="input_area"&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;start&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;datetime&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;date&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;2014&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;11&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;start&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;isoformat&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="output_wrapper"&gt;
&lt;div class="output"&gt;


&lt;div class="output_area"&gt;&lt;div class="prompt output_prompt"&gt;
    Out[3]:&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class="output_text output_subarea output_pyout"&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
'2014-11-13'
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now calculate 80 days from the start date&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing code_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="input"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
In [4]:
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
    &lt;div class="input_area"&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;start&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;datetime&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;timedelta&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;days&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;80&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check that the 80 days of coding ends on 1st February 2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing code_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="input"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
In [5]:
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
    &lt;div class="input_area"&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;isoformat&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="output_wrapper"&gt;
&lt;div class="output"&gt;


&lt;div class="output_area"&gt;&lt;div class="prompt output_prompt"&gt;
    Out[5]:&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class="output_text output_subarea output_pyout"&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
'2015-02-01'
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What day of the week does the competition start on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing code_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="input"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
In [14]:
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
    &lt;div class="input_area"&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;strftime&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;"%A"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="output_wrapper"&gt;
&lt;div class="output"&gt;


&lt;div class="output_area"&gt;&lt;div class="prompt output_prompt"&gt;
    Out[14]:&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class="output_text output_subarea output_pyout"&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
'Sunday'
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
</description><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/calculating-80-days-from-now.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2014 23:09:46 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>