<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Around the world in 80 days</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/</link><description>Blog for an 80 day coding and exercise experiment.</description><atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/rss.xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 18:19:06 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Mercurial Adjustment</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/mercurial-adjustment.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;So careful observers will note the project is running a little late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim was to launch the site on February 1st.  I am not quite ready
to go live yet.   I want a few more features implemented first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am also aware that there is a lot still to do.  But it was always
the plan to build features through the 80 day running of the
competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project has been a very interesting experience for me.  At the
start, I had a task that I knew I could get done in a few days.  With
stuff I had used in the past.  But, I wanted to learn some knew
stuff.  &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://angularjs.org/"&gt;angular.js&lt;/a&gt; was one thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like python and have enjoyed working with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.djangoproject.com/"&gt;django&lt;/a&gt; over the
years.  It has been a struggle at times.  I've always loved what the
project is doing, it has been a constantly evolving project.  Often,
knew releases would break old sites.  This was actually a good thing,
a bit of reading and you could find the solution.  And if you
implemented it, your code was generally better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have loved &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/1.7/topics/migrations/"&gt;django migrations&lt;/a&gt;.  I like to develop sites as they
are being run.  Now one tricky bit is knowing when you can (or should)
let others loose on the site.  They might put work into it that would
be lost by changes you want to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where these migrations come in very handy.  Over the course of
what I have been doing I have been running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
python 80days/manage.py makemigrations
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and/or:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
python 80days/manage.py migrate
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;more or less at random (as I got to know what the errors really mean,
so less random as time went on.  And what has been cool is that pretty
much every time they have lead me through the process and done exactly
what I wanted with pretty minimal fuss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Murphy's law dictates that I will now encounter a nightmare with
migrations, at some, inconvenient point.  The good news is I have good
confidence in these migrations.  In particular, I love the way you get
the code for the migration.  So, if I am doing something scary, or if
it all breaks, then I can take a look at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="angular"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Angular&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has been a rocky ride at times.  On the face of it, it is doing
something elegant and simple.   But it is doing what it does inside
the DOM model as implemented by various browsers.  These browsers are
trying to be helpful.  So I spent an afternoon wrestling with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/angular/angular.js/issues/1459"&gt;angular
directives for table rows&lt;/a&gt;.  I just wanted to write a partial piece
of html for each row.  Now it seems this is really tricky to do in
angular because of the way browsers try to be helpful with broken
table code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I am happy with where things are.  There are a lot of areas
I would like to learn more about.  I need to spend an afternoon with
the node/angular testing setup.  I really do need to start writing
those tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, there are a lot of things I know can be done better, but
most are good enough for now and I can work on the pain points as they
become more aparent,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="summary"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news is that after all the research and experimenting I have
found a lot of the gotchas.  In short, I have the tools and have
figured enough about how they work that I should be quite productive
from here on in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was cookiecutter a good idea?  Very much so.  It introduced me to lots
of things that I would not of explored at this point otherwise.  Some
bits I have pretty much forgotten about, but I think most of the stuff
I have explored is mentioned in this blog somewhere, or in &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/swfiua/"&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;.
So, if nothing else, it is there if I need to refer to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="and-finally"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;And finally..&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the mercurial adjustment works like this.  Every software project
runs late.  They run late for lots of reasons.  Most of them good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mercury_%28planet%29"&gt;planet mercury&lt;/a&gt; orbits the sun in just under 88 days.  But
here on planet earth, in that time the earth moves, so that it is
actually nearly 116 days before the earth, mercury and sun are in a
similar alignment.  This probably needs to be done in a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/jupyter"&gt;jupyter
notebook&lt;/a&gt;, so for now, the deal is that depending on your frame of
reference and definition of a day, 80 days could arguably be deemed to
be a shade over 105 days as most of us here on earth know them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So next time your n day software project is running late, come into
work dressed as Mercury ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/mercurial-adjustment.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 19:47:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Are we nearly there yet?</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/are-we-nearly-there-yet.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As of last night I have competition entry all working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see all the competions being run.  If a competition has not
started yet or is still in progress you can enter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To enter, just give the nickname you want to use for the competion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next job is to add code to allow competitors to create and join teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This shouldn't take too long given what I now have.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>angular django python 80days</category><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/are-we-nearly-there-yet.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 15:43:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Angular velocity</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/angular-velocity.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;So it has been a while since I blogged about the 80 day project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is largely due to most of my free time has been spent working on
the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just to recap, 77 days into the project I still had quite a bit to
do.  Most of the work up to that point had been on getting pieces
together, decide what tools to use, learning those tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next job was to move the angular code around a bit and try and get
django serving it all.  In particular, I had decided it was probably
worthwhile to have the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://angularjs.org/"&gt;angular.js&lt;/a&gt; partial html pieces go through
the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.djangoproject.com/"&gt;django&lt;/a&gt; template engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting npm up and running, with a recent enough version can be
tricky, but there was an excellent guide on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/joyent/node/wiki/Installing-Node.js-via-package-manager#debian-and-ubuntu-based-linux-distributions"&gt;Installing npm on Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With moving all the files around, &lt;strong&gt;.bowerrc&lt;/strong&gt; needed editing a few
times to point it at where the bower_components were now made to be
installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/global-hackathon-team-bermuda.html"&gt;Global Hackathon, Team Bermuda&lt;/a&gt; I have had mild
paranoia that cross-site-request-forgery is going to bite me at some
point.  I am hoping that by serving everything under django I will
avoid that nightmare.  In the meanwhile, I did at this &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/swfiua/80days/commit/678ae25e432b8633230bf67f8168a8f8188717b1"&gt;csrf fix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A previous post, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/nginx-on-kodingcom.html"&gt;Nginx on koding.com&lt;/a&gt; came in useful for setting
up postgres on koding.com as I decided it was more than time to get
this thing running on a cloud based machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have not found myself using &lt;em&gt;django-angular&lt;/em&gt;, but the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django-angular.readthedocs.org/en/latest/integration.html"&gt;django
angular integration&lt;/a&gt; docs have been an enormous help in highlighting
issues in integrating django and angular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In amongst all this I decided it was time to add &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/tomwalker/django_quiz/"&gt;django quiz&lt;/a&gt; to
the mix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was mostly painless, following the django-quiz docs, but when I
fired up the server it failed.  The problem was down to me using
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django-allauth.readthedocs.org/"&gt;django-allauth&lt;/a&gt; which effectively removes &lt;em&gt;auth.User&lt;/em&gt;. The fix is to
use &lt;em&gt;settings.AUTH_USER_MODEL&lt;/em&gt; if you want to reference the &lt;em&gt;User&lt;/em&gt;
model in your own models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/tomwalker/django_quiz/commit/9416c05cd447e3aa40a2351684f2105dafa95e13"&gt;user model fix&lt;/a&gt; and made a pull request.  Happily, the
project maintainer actioned the request within the hour (many thanks
Tom!) and I was able to update to the new version with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
pip install git+https://github.com/tomwalker/django_quiz.git
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By February 1st I was starting to get comfortable with angular and the
pieces were coming together.  I have some simple partials, I have
angular calling the django rest API and I have the beginnings of some
views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next task is to display competitions a user can enter and provide
an enter button.   At this point I did a bit more thinking and
reading.  Deciding what logic to put in angular and what to put in
django views and api calls needs a little thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here the plan is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;get the competion list and competion entry features working&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;get team creation and team membership features implemented&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;get the site up and running in the cloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a simple test server on koding.com, but want to run the actual
site on a different instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>angular javascript django 80days</category><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/angular-velocity.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 14:36:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Got the ingredients, lets cook this thing</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/got-the-ingredients-lets-cook-this-thing.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This post is likely going to be a bit of a mixture.  It started out as
an account of what I am doing today, but I think it might turn into an
account of why a 3 day project can take 80 days and why that isn't
always a bad thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I have had this goal for 80 days to create a website.  Now this
hasn't been my only goal in this period.  Actually, I have had a lot
of other stuff going on.  Oh, and there was Christmas and New Year and
of course the annual flu/cold/sore throat fun to deal with.  Also,
this is supposed to be a fun project and I have other fun things I
have been doing at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also been using it to learn some new stuff.  Now this is always
a dilemma with IT: learn to do things the &lt;em&gt;proper&lt;/em&gt; way, learn about
the latest tools or just use what you already know?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could have built this thing with pure django and simple html
templates in 2-3 days I am sure.  Well not quite that because I need
all these things too:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;authentication, user registration, preferably supporting third party
openID management.  That is where &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django-allauth.readthedocs.org/"&gt;django-allauth&lt;/a&gt; comes in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;database migrations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deployment to cloud.  I think I will use &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/https//koding.com"&gt;koding.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;code generation.  I wrote some simple code generators. I should be
able to include these in a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://cookiecutter.readthedocs.org/en/latest/"&gt;cookiecutter&lt;/a&gt; so my next project will
be much quicker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am learning &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://angularjs.org/"&gt;angular.js&lt;/a&gt;.  I already see the promise in this and
it should strengthen my javascript skills which will help with the
next phases of the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I have the ingredients together.  I think I know most of the
problems I will have, just have to put this thing together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First thing: &lt;cite&gt;angular dates are in milliseconds&lt;/cite&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now with this knowledge I have the angular showing today's date,
80 days from now and 80 days ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next stop is to get a form to register a team.  There is quite a bit
to learn here.  I will need to figure out how angular calls REST api's
and of course deal with the form stuff too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK, so thanks to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://campus.codeschool.com"&gt;codeschool&lt;/a&gt; I now have a good idea of how most of
this angular stuff hangs together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next task is to see if I can get data from the django rest
services.  Before I do that I think it is time to re-organise the code
so that it can all be served by the django server.  I suspect this
might get tricky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I should be in town in the morning, so I decided this would
be a good time to see if I can get this thing running on Gonzalo,
otherwise known as the &lt;cite&gt;laptop without an escape key&lt;/cite&gt;.  This thing
also has a battery with a life of about 5 minutes.  But I like it in a
weird sort of way.  It needs more memory too, but that should be an
easy fix.  I think it might turn into that broom with 20 new heads and
five new handles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will be a good test of whether I can run everything on another machine
without too much pain.  With the screensaver doing the, "all work and
no play", I think it is time to take a break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/got-the-ingredients-lets-cook-this-thing.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 15:50:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Pink and Blue Limo</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/the-pink-and-blue-limo.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I first met &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Acegirl"&gt;ace-girl&lt;/a&gt; I was living in Ottawa.  One day she was
heading out into town on one of her missions.  I asked if she wanted
me to run her wherever she was going in the car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to confess, I don't really enjoy driving around Ottawa.  In
winter, when it is -25C outside then the car is a nice option to
have.  But I know I will spend a chunk of time stuck in traffic.
Plus, Ottawa is a grid system, there are traffic lights every block.
But, if ace-girl is running late then again the car can be handy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This day, she just responded, "Don't worry, I will just take the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.showbus.com/galcanada/octranspo.htm"&gt;Red and White Limo&lt;/a&gt;."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regular readers of this blog (if there are any! -- note to self, look
into google analytics) will know that I have a bit of a thing about
red and white, entirely due to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sheffield_United_F.C."&gt;Red and White Wizards&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my ears pricked up at the mention of red and white.  I was a little
concerned &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Acegirl"&gt;ace-girl&lt;/a&gt; seemed to be planning to take the limo to get where
she wanted.  Really, I would much rather run her there in the car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She quickly put my out of my misery.  The buses in Ottawa are red and
white, so &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Acegirl"&gt;ace-girl&lt;/a&gt; just referred to them as the red and white limo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have always liked the bus.  I grew up in Sheffield, UK at a time
when the bus service was quite excellent.  Being under 16 I could go
anywhere in town for just 2 new pence.  Adults had to pay the princely
sum of 10 new pence.  I would walk down to the bottom of our road and
a bus would always turn up within 10 minutes or so.  No need to check
the timetable: the buses were often 5 minutes or so off schedule, but
they were so regular that it didn't matter.  Sheffield buses were
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bus-and-coach-photos.com/picture/number3844.asp"&gt;Brown and Cream Limos&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not really my favourite colour scheme, red and white would have been
better, but then the blue and white half of the city might never have
taken a bus.  In any case, these things looked like giant ice-cream
sandwiches: a block of vanilla ice cream sandwiched between two
wafers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ride into town was always fun.  I would sit upstairs, preferably
at the front where you could see everything.  My journey was down
Abbeydale Road.  It felt like you could literally find anything you
wanted on Abbeydale Road.  Looking out of the bus I would always
notice new things.  There was the cycle shop that had a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Penny-farthing"&gt;penny
farthing&lt;/a&gt; mounted above the shop window.   A bit further down there
was Bardwell's electronics store.  This was like a little hardware
store only it sold electronic components:  resistors, capacitors and
these new fangled things called transistors.  Oh, and you could still
get valves there too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well move on 30 or so years and I am now in Bermuda with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Acegirl"&gt;ace-girl&lt;/a&gt;.
Nowadays she takes the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bermuda-online.org/bermudabus.jpg"&gt;Pink and Blue Limo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For anyone who enjoys buses, the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bermuda-online.org/bermudabus.jpg"&gt;Pink and Blue Limo&lt;/a&gt; has to be one
of the best bus experiences in the world.  First of all, the buses are
pink and blue.  Pink to match the sand on the beaches, blue to match
the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bus stops are marked by pink or blue poles.  Pink means the bus is
heading in to town, blue means it is heading away from town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am lucky, I live at the top of a hill between South Shore and Middle
Road.  I can walk down to South Shore and take the 7, or I can go to
Middle Road and take the 8.  There is a bus every half hour, happily
at my point in the island the buses are off cut by 15 minutes, the
result is average waiting time should be less than 10 minutes most of
the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have a moped.  This is a great way to get around the island,
but on occasion I head into town and end up having a couple of beers.
One such occasion was last Wednesday.  The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sheffield_United_F.C."&gt;Red and White Wizards&lt;/a&gt;
were playing Tottenham Hotspur in the first leg of the League Cup
semi-final.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Blades are two divisions below Spurs.  Just getting to this semi
was quite an achievement.  I headed in to town with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Acegirl"&gt;ace-girl&lt;/a&gt; to
watch the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can expect, for such a major fixture the bar was packed out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/Blades/packed_out_at_the_hood.jpg" src="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/galleries/Blades/packed_out_at_the_hood.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 400px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was fearing the worst.  The Blades have actually been doing really
well in the cups since &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nigel_Clough"&gt;Nigel Clough&lt;/a&gt; took over as manager.  But
after years of following the Blades I know not to get my hopes up.  I
really just hoped that the game wouldn't be over in 20 minutes with us
3-0 down and the prospect of a pointless game at Bramall Lane the
following week.  In fact, first half the blades looked in control,
even had a couple of half chances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The longer the game went on, the more I dared to hope.  Spurs did get
a penalty, which they scored, but the game finished 1-0.  As this is
two legs, the blades are just 1-0 down at half-time with the second
leg due to be played in front of a sell-out crowd at the Lane.
Tomorrow could be fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, suffice to say, riding home on the bike was not an option.  We
left the bike with one of the people working in the bar.  His bike was
off the road due to a scary accident, happily he just had a bit of
road rash and some bruises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day I took the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bermuda-online.org/bermudabus.jpg"&gt;Pink and Blue Limo&lt;/a&gt; in to town to collect
the bike.  I walked down to the 7, but was sat on the wall admiring
the view and looking for my ticket when the bus sailed past.  Not the
driver's fault, I wasn't at the actual stop.  Fortunately, I had time
to walk over the hill, getting there just in time to admire the view
before the 8 turned up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bermuda bus etiquette is quite complex.  The buses are smaller than
normal buses and only single decker, mainly because the roads here are
pretty narrow.  If you are on the bus you wait until it has come to a
stop before getting up from your seat to get off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The school children always give up their seat to older people.
Everyone greets the driver as they get on the bus.  Usually, there are
a bunch of regulars on the bus.  It is Bermuda, everyone knows
everyone and you see people catching up on news as they encounter
friends and relatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always like to get a seat by the window.  On the number 7 the views
of the South Shore beaches are breathtaking.  On the number 8 you are
inland for much of the journey, but it is never dull.  You
will get glimpses of the ocean, but also see lots of the wonderful
coloured houses and of course all the plants and trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the hurricanes Gonzalo and Fay, back in October there has been
lots more to look at.  First, there was all the damage to the trees as
well as some property damage.  Within a couple of days everything was
pretty much running as normal, but everywhere you looked there were
people helping clean up.  Either soldiers in the regiment, those
working for the government as well as many proud Bermudians working
together to get the island back on its feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the hurricanes took out a lot of trees, so now you can see things
you never knew were there.  The older Bermudians just smile, they have
seen it before, after Fabian or Emily or Felix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journey is a good time to think, to slow down, experience
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vbVyE6hZjCU"&gt;another world that is Bermuda&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am writing this post today in part because the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bermuda-online.org/bermudabus.jpg"&gt;Pink and Blue Limo&lt;/a&gt;
is off the road.  Unfortunately, the government here is short of
money.  As a result, they have been trying to reduce the wage bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is coming at a time when the island is full of excitement having
won the right to host the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.americascup.com/"&gt;America's Cup&lt;/a&gt; in 2017.  There is a lot of
work to do to get the island ready for this.  But the government is
broke.  And to deal with that they made an agreement with the unions
to cut wages in return for days of &lt;em&gt;furlough&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know the ins-and-outs of it all, but the hope was this would
be a temporary measure and that after a year or so the budget would
begin to balance and hours would be restored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This now doesn't look like happening and so the last two days there
have been peaceful demonstrations in town in protest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is hoping that all parties will get around the table and work out
a solution that works for all of Bermuda and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Acegirl"&gt;ace-girl&lt;/a&gt; can get back
to her &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bermuda-online.org/bermudabus.jpg"&gt;Pink and Blue Limo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and if the blades could somehow pull off a miracle tomorrow, that
would also be good ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bermuda bus ottawa sufc</category><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/the-pink-and-blue-limo.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 18:57:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Angular Momentum</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/angular-momentum.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Friday I got to the point that the angular seed app is now checked
into my 80days repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today's mission is to start turning that into the app I really want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the first things I want to do is fix up angular so that it uses
different markers for its template substitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.djangoproject.com/"&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt; uses '{{' and '}}' to mark blocks that the template engine
needs to pay attention to and do substitutions.  Actually, the &lt;cite&gt;django
template languate&lt;/cite&gt; has two escape patterns:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;{{ and }} are used to mark variables to be expanded&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;{% and %} are used to mark django template tags.  These get used for
things like marking &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt; loops and the like&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now by an unhappy coincidence, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://angularjs.org/"&gt;angular.js&lt;/a&gt; also uses {{ and }} to
mark stuff for expansion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happily, angular allows you to over-ride these markers, as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code javascript literal-block"&gt;
&lt;span class="kd"&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nx"&gt;my_app&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nx"&gt;angular&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;module&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'MyApp'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;config&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kd"&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;$interpolateProvider&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nx"&gt;$interpolateProvider&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;startSymbol&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'{$'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nx"&gt;$interpolateProvider&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;endSymbol&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'$}'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, since I already had some code in my &lt;em&gt;app.js&lt;/em&gt; I just added the
extra config code, so my &lt;em&gt;app.js&lt;/em&gt; now looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code javascript literal-block"&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'use strict'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="c1"&gt;// Declare app level module which depends on views, and components
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;angular&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;module&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'myApp'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'ngRoute'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'myApp.view1'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'myApp.view2'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'myApp.version'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;]).&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nx"&gt;config&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;([&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'$routeProvider'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kd"&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;$routeProvider&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="nx"&gt;$routeProvider&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;otherwise&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;({&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;redirectTo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'/view1'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}]).&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="nx"&gt;config&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kd"&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;$interpolateProvider&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nx"&gt;$interpolateProvider&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;startSymbol&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'{$'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nx"&gt;$interpolateProvider&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;endSymbol&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'$}'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, making some progress, but I still can't figure out this controller
thing and how to tie it all together.  Time to go back to
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://campus.codeschool.com"&gt;codeschool&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, their &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://campus.codeschool.com/courses/shaping-up-with-angular-js"&gt;shaping up with angular&lt;/a&gt; introduction.  I had
to register with codeschool.  Thankfully, that was painless bar having
to create yet-another-password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it has been worth it.  You can watch the videos at 1.5x or 2.0x or
slow them down.  It would be great if they took the mythtv trick and
shifted the frequency of voices down so that the presenters don't
sound like chipmunks on speed when you speed things up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good bit is you can click on "Start Challenges" as soon as you are
bored with the video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once in the challenges, the "check my work" button is genius and
extraordinarily helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="angular-date-filter"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Angular date filter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just fell in love with the angular date filter.  Feed it a unix
datetime and it does the right thing.  Eg Unix time began 1969/12/31 @
8:00PM in Bermuda, note the four our offset from UTC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See this &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/swfiua/80days/commit/04a9b8a64f9cb402c434ad1f6b6224757ca09182"&gt;github commit&lt;/a&gt; for some code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="thanks"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thanks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to @ergoemacs on twitter who posted a link to their excellent
mini tutorial on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ergoemacs.org/emacs/emacs_magit-mode_tutorial.html"&gt;magit-mode&lt;/a&gt;: git mode for emacs.  I had this
installed already, but never quite plucked up the courage to try it.
Wow: git in emacs: lovely jubbly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And thanks to stack exchange for this tip on how to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/17798109/how-can-i-diff-a-single-file-with-magit"&gt;diff a single
file with magit&lt;/a&gt;,  Answer: just hit tab in the magit status buffer on
the line for the file you want to diff.  More &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=lovely+jubbly"&gt;lovely-jubbly&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, thanks to Snowy, who helped with the coding:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/Snowy/coding.jpg" src="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/galleries/Snowy/coding.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 400px;"&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>javascript angular django</category><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/angular-momentum.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 16:44:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>I met Bill's Gates and got the t-shirt</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/i-met-bills-gates-and-got-the-t-shirt.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those who know me probably think that Bill Gates is not exactly on my
top ten list of people I would like to meet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been an free and open software enthusiast for longer than I care
to remember.  Let's just say that over the years Bill hasn't exactly
been a friend of open source.  To be fair, it pretty much threatened
to destroy his rather lucrative business model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To some extent it has.  Bill has moved on, so has Steve "linux is a
cancer" Balmer.  Microsoft is making more and more code available as
open source.  I would guess they have realised that if you want to be
relevant in today's software world you need your stuff to run on
linux, or at least play nicely with that platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a lot going on in the tech world, it isn't clear how it is
all going to pan out.  But free and open source is stronger than
ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night, my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Acegirl"&gt;ace-girl&lt;/a&gt; and I wandered down the hill to the local
hostelry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/the-music-from-uncle.html"&gt;blogged&lt;/a&gt; a few weeks back, Saturday there is a DJ at this place
and it is often a fun night.  We were planning to meet another friend
who had just got back to the island.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived and things were still quiet.  They were showing some
highlights from the FA Cup on the TV.  I love the FA Cup, always have
done.  It is when the lower league teams get a chance to show what
they can do against higher clubs.  Yesterday was a great day for the
underdogs.  Bradford City, also known as the &lt;em&gt;Bantams&lt;/em&gt; (curiously,
google in their soccer info used the name &lt;em&gt;Bantams&lt;/em&gt; rather than
Bradford City.  It was odd, because every other club was listed by
their more formal name.  It was Sheffield United, not the Blades
playing a Preston.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were quite a few people having dinner at the place and 2-3 were
celebrating birthdays.  DJ Uncle was doing his round of the room,
figuring out his audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around this time a guy walked by wearing a t-shirt and a silver tie,
all sparkles and glitter, obviously top quality as it was ready-tied
and held around his neck by a piece of elastic.   I saw the words,
"Bill's Gates" on his t-shirt.   My curiousity was peaked and we got
talking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It soon became clear it was the guy's birthday.  He introduced himself
as Bill Gates (or it might have been Bill's Gates).  There may have
been some alcohol involved, so details are a little blurry.  But the
gist was he was founder member of "BFBC".  The F is along the same
lines as the f in swfiua.  So it was "Bill's F* Boat Club".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly, this was my chance to be photographed with the man himself:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/Gates/Me%20with%20Bill's%20Gates.jpg" src="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/galleries/Gates/Me%20with%20Bill's%20Gates.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 400px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can report that Bill was a fine upstanding character and was even
kind enough to give me one of his t-shirts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/Gates/i_got_the_t_shirt.jpg" src="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/galleries/Gates/i_got_the_t_shirt.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 400px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now in case you haven't heard Bermuda has been chosen as the venue for
the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.americascup.com/en/news/131_Bermuda-is-the-home-of-the-2017-America-s-Cup.html"&gt;2017 America's Cup&lt;/a&gt;.  There is quite a bit of excitement about
the island due to this.  Maybe BFBC will enter the race :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, Uncle played &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=inS9gAgSENE"&gt;Happy Birthday&lt;/a&gt; for Bill and the others with
birthdays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been on a bit of a Springsteen kick that last week or so,
something to do with starting to learn some tunes from my "Bruce
Springsteen easy guitar":&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/Springsteen/Springsteen.jpg" src="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/galleries/Springsteen/Springsteen.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 400px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ace girl asked Uncle if he would play some.  And in light of the giant
killings in the FA Cup and with the hope of more to come from the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sheffield_United_F.C."&gt;Red
and White Wizards&lt;/a&gt; it was appropriate that he should choose &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6vQpW9XRiyM"&gt;Glory Days&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks Bill and everyone who helped make last night a fun time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/i-met-bills-gates-and-got-the-t-shirt.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2015 22:22:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Adventures in angular land</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/adventures-in-angular-land.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since this blog is the nearest thing I have of a record of what I am
doing, well I guess &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/swfiua/"&gt;github&lt;/a&gt; might have parts of the story, but in
general, if I want to recall what I did, here is where I come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- So, today was an adventure.  So lots of tutorials are videos --&gt;
&lt;!-- nowadays.  Lots of them.  Some are good --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started with a minor adventure of &lt;em&gt;node.js&lt;/em&gt; land, including package
managers (npm) and packages such as &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://gruntjs.com/"&gt;grunt&lt;/a&gt;.  At one point I had my
django site being served via grunt, which I undestand is another layer
of the onion.  Thinking this might be useful soon as I will be writing
code.  Live updates could be handy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this I still had to find some javascript with a pattern I could
follow.  By now I am getting a bit of a grasp on the parts.  It feels
like a really complicated way to render forms on a browser.  But as
that is something I've always found more painful that it should be, a
bit more pain to find a better solution might be worth the trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So &lt;cite&gt;Angular seed&lt;/cite&gt; came to the rescue.  I think in fact this is what
Nick was using a few weeks back at the global hackathon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after a bit more fun of installing &lt;em&gt;npm&lt;/em&gt; a few different ways and
something called &lt;em&gt;bower&lt;/em&gt; which seems to be package manager for
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://angularjs.org/"&gt;angular.js&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the best bit is that all this stuff actually did work.  And I
moved the app into my tree of code and that works under &lt;em&gt;npm&lt;/em&gt; there
too.  So, I think I am 80% of the way to finishing my kindling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/adventures-in-angular-land.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 19:58:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dancing in the dark</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/dancing-in-the-dark.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;So ten days to go until this project is supposed to be up and running.
Now, this is a software project, just something I have been doing
mostly for my own amusement, but it has a deadline and I am starting
to hear that whooshing sound that deadlines make as the come by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am 70 days in, so what do I have?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a simple &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Create,_read,_update_and_delete"&gt;CRUD&lt;/a&gt; api built in &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.djangoproject.com/"&gt;django&lt;/a&gt;.  It comes with data
migrations and code generators that mean adding new models should
require very little coding.  I have the api documented using
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/marcgibbons/django-rest-swagger"&gt;django rest swagger&lt;/a&gt;.  And I can manipulate tables using the
standard django admin interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also taken a look at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/tomwalker/django_quiz/"&gt;django quiz&lt;/a&gt; and it looks like it will
do a good job for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, so far no proper front end.  As far as the front end is
concerned I am &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UoPwqDW5750"&gt;Dancing in the Dark&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had two hurricanes here in Bermuda back in October.  It is winter
now.  Actually, a beautiful day today, 21C, sunny, few clouds and
beautiful blue oceans.  I just rode out of town on the bus.  Must be
one of the best bus rides in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, come evening, the sun disappears and a chill descends as the
dampness comes out of the walls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of wood around the island, branches broken by the
storms, whole trees knocked over.  In many cases, all the branches
have been cut off trees and the stumps set back up, green shoots of
recovery are starting to sprout from these stumps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, I have been gathering wood for fires most nights.  It
reminds me of happy days on scout camps way back when.  Summer camps
with the scouts were the best.  We would cook all week on an open
fire.  Between us, and guided by &lt;em&gt;Skip&lt;/em&gt;, we would figure out how to
light fires, how to get a good fire going and then let it die down a
little for cooking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing you learn right from the start is, &lt;em&gt;you can't start a fire
without a spark&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that is where &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://nedbatchelder.com//blog/201501/kindling_projects_page.html"&gt;kindling&lt;/a&gt; comes in. As I trim the bigger branches
to get logs for the fires the smaller twigs drop to the floor.  Once I
have logs you can gather up a bundle of smaller twigs.  This is the
kindling.  This is what lights the fire.  The tiny pieces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, today I am setting out on a little kindling project.  I want to
add a little box to the &lt;em&gt;Around the world in 80 days&lt;/em&gt; site with
today's date and a couple of other labels showing 80 days from now and
80 days before today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I could do this very quickly with django templates given the code
I already have.  But, I want to try &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://angularjs.org/"&gt;angular.js&lt;/a&gt;.  That way I will
have a new tool I can play with.  If it isn't working for me, then
maybe it will end up like the bow-saw that I find less fun to use than
the small hand axe, still useful, but not the tool I like to use most
of the time.  Or maybe, it will turn out to be a new and better hand
axe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, time to light the blue touch paper and stand well back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>kindling python github</category><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/dancing-in-the-dark.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 17:25:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Django Rest API code generation with cog</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/django-rest-api-code-generation-with-cog.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a good break for the holidays, a couple of weeks in the
frozen wastes of Canada complete with arriving home with a stinking
cold I am now at the, &lt;em&gt;"this code won't write itself"&lt;/em&gt; part of the 80 days
project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is quite a bit to do, but I am still finding distractions to
spend time on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been using &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.django-rest-framework.org/"&gt;django rest framework&lt;/a&gt; to create a REST api for
the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating serializers, api classes and url specs for these frameworks
is largely a matter of generating standard boiler plate code.  This is
the sort of stuff I hate doing: tedious and error prone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I originally wrote my own noddy code generator to help with some of
this, but was less than satisfied with the result: it was fine for my
immediate needs, but as I add more models to the application I would
need to do more autogeneration.  I had the inescapable feeling that my
code generator was probably more trouble than it was worth.  At the
same time, writing code like this by hand is deeply unsatisfying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, just when it was looking like I would have to start learning
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://angularjs.org/"&gt;angular.js&lt;/a&gt; and build the front end, Ned Batchelder came to the
rescue on Twitter by &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/swfiua/status/554742651082539010"&gt;posting&lt;/a&gt; a link to a new release of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://nedbatchelder.com/code/cog/"&gt;cog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ned described it as "a small tool that does a small job well".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure enough, it does.  It lets you embed python code (disguised as
comments) within your code to do the code generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few features in &lt;em&gt;cog&lt;/em&gt; that appealed to me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the code generator can be run in a way that over-writes the input
file with the newly generated code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it calculates checksums for the generated code and embeds them in
the output.  This is useful as it allows it to spot if you have
edited the code since it was generated and hence refuse to
re-generate that code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you can re-run and it will update the existing code, assuming the
checksums have not changed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armed with cog, I came up with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/swfiua/django_eighty_days/blob/master/django_eighty_days/codegen.py"&gt;codegen.py&lt;/a&gt; to generate the boring
bits of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/swfiua/django_eighty_days/blob/master/django_eighty_days/api.py"&gt;api.py&lt;/a&gt; as well as &lt;em&gt;urls.py&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;serializers.py&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am quite happy with the results.  Doug Hellmann had suggested maybe
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://cookiecutter.readthedocs.org/en/latest/"&gt;cookiecutter&lt;/a&gt; might be a better solution to this problem.  In my
case, I am using cookiecutter to get the base files for my django
application, but this code generation cannot take place until you add
some models, hence the need for cog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Better still would be to combine the two and add codegen.py and
suitable urls.py, serializers.py and api.py to the cookiecutter
template.  I'll add that to the list of things to do, if only to delay
the learning of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://angularjs.org/"&gt;angular.js&lt;/a&gt; ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>django python</category><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/django-rest-api-code-generation-with-cog.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 21:12:36 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>