<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Around the world in 80 days</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/</link><description>Blog for an 80 day coding and exercise experiment.</description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 15:36:06 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Magic Roundabouts and Geese</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/magic-roundabouts-and-geese.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Growing up as children we would watch The Magic Roundabout on the BBC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a five minute children's program with a carousel, Zebedee,
Dougal the dog and Dylan the rabbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each episode ended with Zebedee saying, "Time for bed", before
springing off, literally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we got older we might watch a bit of the news that followed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="roundabouts-around-the-world"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Roundabouts around the world&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around the world, traffic rules vary quite a bit.  Here are some
examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="france"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;France&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In France roundabouts used to be much less common than in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The early traffic rule was essentially, "priorite a la droite".  This
rule dated back to horses and carriages and mostly they could see each
other coming for a good way, it was simple to slow down and give way
to those from one side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another key rule, is which side of the road to drive on.  The French,
like most of continental Europe, drive on the right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looked at from above, the French go anti-clockwise around
roundabouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when they arrive at one, those already on the roundabout give way
to new arrivals, coming from the right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This works well with light traffic.  With heavy draffic, things can
fall apart: once the roundabout is full of cars nobody can go
anywhere, although if you are just taking the first right then you'll
probably be ok.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="arc-de-triomphe"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Arc de Triomphe&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now this is more like The Magic Roundabout.  I have no idea what the
rules are.   Rumour has it that insurance companies exclude any
accident that happens here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="british-isles"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;British Isles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here they drive on the left and go clockwise round roundabouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give way to those already on the roundabout.  Those already on can
keep going, those arriving have to wait for it to be safe to enter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, like the French you are giving way to those on the right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, it can work well it depends on the traffic volume and pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="swindon"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Swindon&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swindon actually has a Magic Roundabout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a crazy construction of five roundabouts with another roundabout
inside them all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UK rules apply, so once you get on the thing it is like a
roller-coaster, just go with the flow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the accidents happen, people are usually moving pretty slowly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="north-america"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;North America&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roundabouts used to be far less common in North America.  Four-way
stops are the order of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You arrive at the junction and stop.  If no-one else is there then you
can proceed, others arriving after you should give way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now this can lead to the &lt;em&gt;Canadian stand-off&lt;/em&gt;.   You arrive at a
roundabout just as someone else arrives.  There then follows an
elaborate dance where you both just sit there waiting for the other to
go first, often accompanied by hand-gestures.   Dead-lock is not
uncommon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="ottawa"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Ottawa&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a roundabout near the Experimental Farm that itself seems to
be a wonderful experiment in mixing British and French roundabout
rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in the day it was probably a four way stop, a simple cross-roads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's pretend there is a north-south (NS) road crossing east-west (EW)
and the NS is the bigger road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are travelling NS or SN, you can pretent your are French and
drive straight on to the roundabout.  Those coming from an EW
direction will give way to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are turning left, then you will have to give way to traffic
entering on the NS road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now if you arrive on the EW road you have to give way to traffic
already on the roundabout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is a complicated mixture of giving way to the left or right
depending on where you are on the roundabout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="going-backwards-round-the-magic-roundabout"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Going backwards round the magic roundabout&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* please don't try this *&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traffic arriving from east (or west) could do a Pierre Trudeau, behind
the Queen pirouette, turning 180 degrees to enter the roundabout
backwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this way, the &lt;em&gt;give way to traffic on your right&lt;/em&gt; rule ensures the
traffic that you need to giver way to is always coming from your right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once on the roundabout another pirouette should be done, having done
this, again give way to traffic entering from the North/South road,
which is again on your right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also ensures if you exit on this route you are facing the right
way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If continuing around the roundabout, another pirouette should be
performed after passing the north/south road.  Hence, you will again
be going backwards on the magic roundabout.   With your right side to
the centre of the roundabout there is no need to give way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was much younger my mother one night announced she felt a
little typsy.  As a curious child I asked what that was like.  She
said, "it is like I am going backwards on the magic roundabout".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like I said, don't try this on the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="johnny-barnes"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Johnny Barnes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Hamilton, Bermuda there are several roundabouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there is one special one.  It is known as The Johnny Barnes
roundabout and has its own magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is indeed magic.  Every weekday, between 5am and 10am you will see
Johnny Barnes.  He has been waving to traffic and dispensing love
at the roundabout since retiring from the Bus company.  He is now in
his 90's.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bermuda has its own road rules.  Mostly following the British.  But
the horn only really gets used to say &lt;em&gt;hi&lt;/em&gt; to friends and cousins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you see a friend trying to get out of a small side road you might
well follow the "priorite a la droite" rule and wave for them to go
ahead of you, even though you have right of way.  The roads are
narrow, the speed limit is 20 mph and a little give and take makes it
a better place for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if you are new to the island, watch out for vehicles stopping to let
people out of tiny driveways and side roads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-about-the-geese"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What about the geese?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week the Mighty Blades played Swindon.  Those brave fans that
made the journey down to Swindon went there knowing they would have to
negotiate the Magic Roundabout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being Blades fans, they were probably expecting the worst and a heavy
defeat.  I believe all the fans got through the roundabout unscathed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the game, well the new manager, Nigel Adkins, played a
motivational video before the game.  Google "geese sufc" and you
should find it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It explains how geese are able to travel 70% further by flying in a V
formation.  How one goose will lead and when tired drop back into the
formation and let another take the lead.d&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a goose is tiring and struggling, two other strong geese will drop
down to the ocean with the struggler and stay with it until it either
dies or makes a recovery.  They will then fly together to rejoin the
flock, or tag onto another flock following behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="magic-roundabouts-and-mother-geese"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Magic Roundabouts and Mother Geese&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was younger, my mum was my Magic Roundabout.  She would watch
the world circling around her and find ways to change the paths of
those that needed to be on a different path, or gently put together
those that would benefit from each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I now have another Magic Roundabout in my life.  Mum's are magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bermuda</category><category>blades</category><category>france</category><category>ottawa</category><category>roundabouts</category><category>sufc</category><category>swindon</category><guid>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/magic-roundabouts-and-geese.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 14:54:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Census Survey</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/census-survey.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="section" id="introduction"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bermuda Government, Department of Statistics has put out a Request
for Proposal (RFP) for a &lt;em&gt;web-based solution to support on-line
census&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below are some thoughts on how Free Software could form the solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The census raises many complex issues of privacy, accessibility and
access to information.  In short, is has all the features of a
typical software project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="free-software-solution"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Free Software Solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most, if not all, of the pieces required to build this system already
exist as free software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This software is free in the sense that it gives you freedom.  Freedom
to examine the software, freedom to look how it works, freedom to
change it as you wish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freedom to pass the software on to others should you wish, so long as
you give them the same freedoms you received.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A prototype can be built from these pieces in around 20 hours of
development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are Bermudians with the skills to do this and the time to devote
to such a project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some cases they will be exploring new concepts, but that is the
nature of IT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many others they can call on to assist should they need
guidance, including the millions of people around the globe who
contribute to free software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="accessibility"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Accessibility&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accessibility is often neglected in software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many free software tools have good support for accessibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally, a framework is provided to address a wide range of
accessibility issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone has different challenges working with computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hearing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;motor movements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;speech&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;language processing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;writing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the software itself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;citizens access to information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bermuda is an international island.  English is the dominant
language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documents are generally produced in English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the island has many nationalities living here and also has
many Bermudians who have travelled and lived abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also distinct communities within Bermuda with their own
language, culture and history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, of course, Bermuda is a popular travel destination, with many
nationalities paying visits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet there is very poor support for languages other than English on
most Bermuda related websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A free software solution would accommodate translations.  Further, it
would allow anyone to contribute to those translations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free software: means you can adapt for differing needs, since you have
the code.  Without the code you are tied to a third party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further others can help you.  A free software census solution for
Bermuda may be usable in many other juristictions.  Bermudians who
develop such software would be able to work with others wherever in
the world they may be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="public-access-to-information"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Public Access To Information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Census data is invaluable in many ways.  It provides data that can
guide public policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TODO: Anology: vaccination: having your children vaccinated protects
them against illness, but also reduces the chance of epidemics
breaking out.  There are small risks to every vaccination, but the
benefits to society can be significant.  For example, consider the
elimination of polio, a disease that affect large numbers of people in
the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the UK there have been censuses since 1831 (may have been earlier).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collecting the data back in that day was a huge task.  At the time it
gave vast amounts of information about poplulation sizes, household
sizes and the age profile of the population and their occupations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the data was hand written.  Pages of data might have totals and
there were presumably clerks creating aggregate statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, genealogists find the census data both fascinating and
invaluable as they trace family history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UK has been digitising this data over the last few years and
making it available on line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A free software solution to the census would anticipate PATI requests
by building access to information into the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than wait for PATI requests and have to then examine data to
see what should be released, the decisions about what should be
released, when and to who will be made up front and built into the
solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A system can be built that will only release certain information after
some specified period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some data may need reviewing after some number of years and released
or re-sealed based on that review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="transparency-and-privacy"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Transparency and Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is assumed that aggregate data from the census will be made freely
available to citizens.  Our solution will include support for such
access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is recommended that any data of a sensitive nature be treated
appropriately, including the physical security of any computers
storing the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One possibility is to try to build a system that only stores
aggregrate information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should also be noted that in a small community like Bermuda
aggregate data, especially when combined with other similar data can
remove annonynimity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One recommendation would be to encourage community discussion about
the census questions and have the community guide the decisions
regarding privacy and access to information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collecting more personal data that will be stored in some sort of time
capsule for the benefit of future historians and genealogy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="computer-insecurity"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Computer insecurity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In view of all the high profile data breaches that the world has been
experiencing over recent months it should be apparent that storing
sensitive data on computers is not an easy task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our solution will recognise this fact and propose appropriate measures
for storing more sensitive data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it would be our recommendation to only collect data that the
residents of Bermuda are comfortable in sharing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="maintenance-and-development"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Maintenance and Development&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a free software solution future maintenance and development of
the software can be performed by anyone with the skills.  The local
poplulation will have all the tools they need, they just need to learn
the skills needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further, a well designed free software census would be usable in other
jurisdictions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If developed here in Bermuda by Bermudians it would create
opportunities for the team to work elsewhere in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="free-software-centre"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Free Software Centre&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="ownership-of-code"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ownership of code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The government, not the developers would own and code developed for
the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be noted most of the code already exists and is free
software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is suggested that any code written for the project be itself
released as a free software project using the GPL license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="existing-free-software-solutions"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Existing Free Software solutions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.census.gov/data/software.html"&gt;http://www.census.gov/data/software.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="appendix-a-python-and-django"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Appendix A: Python and Django&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="django"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Django&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="django-quiz"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Django Quiz&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="appendix-project-jupyter"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Appendix:  Project Jupyter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans in different parts of the world speak different languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans have also developed many different languages for communicating
with computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning these languages can take considerable time and effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most of the history of modern computing, communicating with other
languages has been difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In effect, the plethora of languages has worked to Balkanise the IT
world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://jupyter.org/"&gt;Project Jupyter&lt;/a&gt; is just one project that is helping languages work
together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jupyter is a tool that supports virtually seamless interoperability
between 50 different languages, from python, to perl, C++ to C#, Bash
to Brainfuck, erlang to lua, matlab to php.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="choosing-tools"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Choosing tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers invariably like to use the tools they know best.  They
understand them, know what they are capable of and know many of the
risks they will encounter using those tools to solve a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting a project with a new tool presents many additional risks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;will it work as advertised?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How much time will it take to learn?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For an organisation starting out in the free software world the choice
can be daunting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further, any large organisation will likely end up using many
different languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst there are inefficiencies in this approach, there are
advantages, just as with growing crops: monoculture leaves an
organisation vulnerable to anything which threatens that ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Variety gives resilience, but at some cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Projects such as Jupyter help support that variety and reduce the
costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a particular technology choice is proving hard to support, porting
to another Jupyter supported language is always an option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/census-survey.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 15:07:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fred Update</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/fred-update.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fred formed way in the east of the Atlantic.  I believe it was already
a hurricane going over the Cape Verde islands.  I was shown pictures
today of seas damaging a pier.  I have not heard too much more about
damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Six years ago, Fred formed around the same area a little further
south, but did not intensify as fast.  It did become a hurricane, then
dissipated as it curled, for a short while was heading easterly, then
got pushed back westward.  By this time it had fallen apart and it
did not get organised again, but the remnants of the storm tracked a
good way across the Atlantic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the discussion of Fred, it is likely to be pulled apart in
the short term.  Then the track forecasts give a range of
possibilities, including heading westward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Latest (5AM AST, 1st September) forecast discussion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.nhc.noaa.gov/text/refresh/MIATCDAT1+shtml/010849.shtml"&gt;http://www.nhc.noaa.gov/text/refresh/MIATCDAT1+shtml/010849.shtml&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These discussions tend to be very helpful in gauging how much
confidence the forecasters about the forecasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, both track and intensity forecasts can be pretty accurate
out to 24 hours or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paragraph from the discussion has a lot of information in it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Fred is expected to move between west-northwest and northwest for
the next 72 hours as a mid-level ridge to the north of the cyclone
gradually builds westward. After that time, a turn toward the
north-northwest and north is forecast due to a deep-layer trough
currently over eastern Canada that is expected to dig
southeastward over the central Atlantic and erode the ridge. The
NHC model guidance is in decent agreement on this developing
pattern change.  However, there are significant differences in the
model solutions with the HWRF, GFS, and GFDL models keeping Fred
stronger and making the northward turn sooner, whereas the weaker
solution models like the UKMET and ECMWF take a weaker and more
vertically shallow cyclone farther west before turning it
northward.  The official forecast track is a little south of the
previous advisory track, mainly due to the more southerly initial
position, and follows a blend of the weaker UKMET and ECMWF
solutions.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end, we learn the current forecast track is further south than
the previous advisory.  The discussion notes this is mostly because
Fred did not move as far north as expected over the previous period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disagreements in models are usually informative, often indicating
there is more uncertainty in the forecast.  Sometimes the forecasters
have good understanding of why the models are disagreeing, different
models have different strengths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="bermuda-weather"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bermuda Weather&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://weather.bm/images/surfaceAnalysis/Latest/Atlantic.gif"&gt;http://weather.bm/images/surfaceAnalysis/Latest/Atlantic.gif&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="wikipedia"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hurricane_Fred_%282015%29"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hurricane_Fred_%282015%29&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hurricane_Fred_%282009%29"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hurricane_Fred_%282009%29&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="national-hurricane-centre"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;National Hurricane Centre&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://weather.bm/images/surfaceAnalysis/Latest/Atlantic.gif"&gt;http://weather.bm/images/surfaceAnalysis/Latest/Atlantic.gif&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014</category><category>2015</category><category>fred</category><category>hurricane</category><category>weather</category><guid>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/fred-update.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:41:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Erika, Andrew, Danny and Fred</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/erika-andrew-danny-and-fred.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last few weeks the Atlantic hurricane season has got more active.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Danny never really got started, was blown apart by sheer, but no doubt
spawned a lot of thunderstorms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flooding from Erika has resulted in numerous deaths in Domincan
Republic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erika has fallen apart, but again there will be a lot of thunderstorms
along its path.  There is a lot of moisture in the atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="erika"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Erika&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early forecasts had the most likely track heading over Hispanola, Then
curving, but likely being blown apart by sheer from strong upper
atmosphere winds related to El Nino.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is in fact very close to what actually has happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="track-forecast"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Track forecast&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weather models started to suggest the storm would curve more
northerly.  This all involves really complex systems that stretch over
thousands of miles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the models most likely path was more northerly, and that might take
it on a path to hit Florida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At one point the most likely track was heading all up the east coast
of Florida, without making landfall.  If it had held together it might
of intensified over hot water with low windsheer and been a major
storm at landfall in the Carolinas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this period there was always the possibility of heading
over Hispanola, but it wasn't the most likely path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="andrew"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Andrew&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew formed in a similar season to 2015 with a high El Nino.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took a more northerly track, steered north of the Caribbean, then
turned straight into Florida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think a comparison of Andrew and Erika, Danny too, would be
interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="fred"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fred&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hurricane names run on a six year cycle.  So, there are six lists,
that repeat every six years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a storm becomes significant in some way, usually the more intense
and damaging storms that hit land, the name gets &lt;em&gt;retired&lt;/em&gt; from the
list and is forever associated with that storm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, we have Fred.  Now for me, Fred means Fiery Fred Trueman,
Yorkshire and England fast bolwer.  I never saw him play, but often
heard him commentating on test matches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So some day we will see a Fiery Fred storm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A storm named Fred has just formed.  Like Erika, there is a fair
amount of uncertainty on what path it takes and how intense it will
get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="more-information"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;More information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael Johnston has also been blogging about the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://bermudaweather.wordpress.com/2015/08/30/active-tropics/"&gt;recent storms&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>hurricane</category><category>weather</category><guid>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/erika-andrew-danny-and-fred.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2015 21:39:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The raspberry pi super computer</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/the-raspberry-pi-super-computer.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The raspberry pi 2 comes with around 6 times the processing power of
the original pi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is still fairly low powered, but it is interesting to compare the
pi with some older computers that were considered powerful in their
day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pi comes with an ARM 7, quad-core processor.  It also has a
Broadcom graphics processor that can potentially be used for compute
intensive work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also comes with 1GB of memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For disk storage the nornal approach is to use a micro SD card.  There
are 16GB cards that give 45MB/s read/write capability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For less than $1000 you can get 20 pi's, with fast SD cards.  The
result is a machine with 80 cores, 16GB of memory and 320GB of disk,
with a combined bandwidth of 900MB/s read and write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These things are low power, so a 20 pi machine would require just 100
watts of power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is reasonable to assume that more powerful devices will be
available in he future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, computing power is becoming very, very cheap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="cray-xmp"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cray-XMP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give some indication of how cheap compute power has become, this
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://vk5tu.livejournal.com/50955.html"&gt;comparison to a Cray-XMP&lt;/a&gt; shows that the older Pi B+ has very
similar compute power to the Cray-XMP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you compate the inflation adjusted price tags you see how cheap
compute power has become.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pi 2 is roughly six times the power of the B+.  Hence 20 of those
gives you 120 Cray-XMP's.   For $1000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="renewable-energy"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Renewable energy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One criticism often directed at renewable energy is that sun, wind and
wave are not reliable.  In order to reliably meet peak demand much
it is necessary to have much more capacity than is needed on average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way to mitigate this cost is to have uses for the spare capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One possible use is to have a compute farm to mop up spare capacity.
This works particularly well if you have long running computations
that can be used to mop up spare compute cycles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin mining is one potential application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Cray</category><category>Cray-XMP</category><category>raspberry pi</category><guid>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/the-raspberry-pi-super-computer.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 22:08:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Red and White v Blue and White</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/red-and-white-v-blue-and-white.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last Saturday there was a big cricket match at Lord's.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not the Lord's where England were falling apart as the Aussies were
dominating the second test, but Lord's in St David's, Bermuda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bailey's Bay were playing Cleveland County in what is known as the
Eastern Counties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each team in Bermuda has its colours, Bay are red and white, Cleveland
are blue and white.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I come from Sheffield, UK, a city divided between the blue and white
of the Owls and the red and white of the Mighty Blades.  I follow the
Blades, so it was natural for me to be cheering for Bailey's Bay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a slow start to the day and it was a long (for Bermuda) ride on
the moped to St David's, so we didn't get to the ground until just
before lunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we entered we were greeted by a larger than life character in red
and white.  Once I took out my red and white, &lt;em&gt;cat in the hat&lt;/em&gt;
headgear he directed us towards the Digicel tent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/EasternCounties/20150718_123538.jpg" src="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/galleries/EasternCounties/20150718_123538.jpg" style="width: 400px; height: 300px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game was nicely poised, with Cleveland batting first and on about
80 runs for 4 wickets at lunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After lunch the Bay bowlers dominated and Cleveland were bowled out
for 127 in 49.3 overs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/EasternCounties/20150718_151601.jpg" src="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/galleries/EasternCounties/20150718_151601.jpg" style="width: 400px; height: 300px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lord's is a wonderful ground, right by the ocean, with natural banks
on which people build stands.  Between innings we went for a walk
round the ground and took some pictures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/EasternCounties/20150718_125203.jpg" src="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/galleries/EasternCounties/20150718_125203.jpg" style="width: 400px; height: 300px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then there is the precariously perched commentary position that
you have to walk the plank to get to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/EasternCounties/20150718_152446.jpg" src="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/galleries/EasternCounties/20150718_152446.jpg" style="width: 400px; height: 300px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now being a Blades supporter I have got used to my team snatching
defeat from the jaws of victory.  The target of 128 that Bay were set
should have been easily within their grasp, but we were about to
witness one of the most bizarre afternoon's cricket there ever was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bay lost two early wickets, but then regrouped and the batsmen were
starting to open up at 50-2.   Cleveland had a couple of strong
appeals turned down.  There was a strong appeal for a catch, but it
was one of those where it was hard to tell if the ball had been
blocked into the ground or hit the ground and come off the bat.  The
umpire gave the benefit of the doubt to the batsman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cleveland protested and for 40 minutes chaos ensued.  Both coaches,
the president of the Eastern Counties and even a policeman took to the
pitch to try and get the game restarted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/EasternCounties/20150718_171958.jpg" src="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/galleries/EasternCounties/20150718_171958.jpg" style="width: 400px; height: 300px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon after the restart, there was another delay for a drinks break.
The batsmen were finding it difficult to get into any sort of rhythm
and first ball after the break a wicket fell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this wickets fell steadily, but Bay always looked like they
would make it.  Until, after 30 overs, with the scores tied and Bay
with just 2 wickets remaining the umpires declared the game over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the scores tied, Cleveland, as holders, were declared winners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It reminded me of the infamous F.A. Cup tie when the Blades were
holding their own against an Arsenal side.  The ball was kicked into
play for an injury.  The resulting throw was sportingly thrown back to
the blades players, but Kanu did not seem to understand what was
happening, raced onto the ball and slotted it into the net.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arsenal went on to win, but Wenger graciously agreed to replay the
game.  Of course, the Blades went on to lose the replay, but at least
the game was not decided by this bizarre incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read today that the Cleveland coach was very unhappy with his sides
behaviour, perhaps he will follow Wenger's example and ask for the
game to be replayed.  However, that might not be possible given the
busy summer cricket schedule here in Bermuda, with Cup Match &lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/red-and-white-v-blue-and-white.html#id2" id="id1"&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; less than
two weeks away this might not be an option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today's Royal Gazette has a full page &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.royalgazette.com/article/20150720/COMMENT01/150729969"&gt;editorial&lt;/a&gt; on the game.  There
are also rumours that Cleveland have been &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.royalgazette.com/article/20150720/SPORT02/150729960"&gt;stripped of the cup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is never dull following the Red and White wizards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much for the cricket, the day itself was fun from beginning to
end.  Unfortunately, I had packed the bag of stuff to take to the
ground, so instead of drinks and food and sunscreen we had an
assortment of raspberry pi's, humidity sensors, air pressure sensors,
wires, breadboards and a netbook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was food in the clubhouse, yellow and blue, St David's colours.
So we were able to find some chips that weren't made of silicon.  And
the rum swizzle went down very smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The banter in the crowd rarely stopped, with fans from both sides
sitting enjoying together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cricket in Bermuda is very much something you go to watch with family
and friends.  Worst case, you have a day in the sunshine in a
beautiful setting, with people you love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next stop the blue and red of Somerset playing the light and dark blue
of St George's.  Cup Match!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="docutils footnote" frame="void" id="id2" rules="none"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col class="label"&gt;&lt;col&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="label"&gt;&lt;a class="fn-backref" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/red-and-white-v-blue-and-white.html#id1"&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Cup match is a two day game between the Red and Blue of
Somerset and the dark and light blue of St Georges.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/red-and-white-v-blue-and-white.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 00:35:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Sixty-seven Minutes</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/sixty-seven-minutes.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div tabindex="-1" id="notebook" class="border-box-sizing"&gt;
    &lt;div class="container" id="notebook-container"&gt;

&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Nelson-Mandela-Day"&gt;Nelson Mandela Day&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/sixty-seven-minutes.html#Nelson-Mandela-Day"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;July 18th is Nelson Mandela's birthday, he would have been 97.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The United Nations calls it Mandela Day, or international day for
freedom, justice and democracy.  They say:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every year on 18 July — the day Nelson Mandela was born — the UN
   joins a call by the Nelson Mandela Foundation to devote 67 minutes of
   time to helping others, as a way to mark Nelson Mandela International
   Day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For 67 years Nelson Mandela devoted his life to the service of
   humanity — as a human rights lawyer, a prisoner of conscience, an
   international peacemaker and the first democratically elected
   president of a free South Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is more here:  &lt;a href="http://www.un.org/en/events/mandeladay/"&gt;http://www.un.org/en/events/mandeladay/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a number of events being organised in Bermuda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks like things might kick off early with this event at Bermuda College:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the Eve of Nelson Mandela Day&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collaboration by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ADHT,  Bermuda College, Chewstick, HRC, Imagine Bermuda&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another Kind of ‘Happy Hour’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based @ the Bermuda College Library&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FRIDAY, JULY 17TH 5.30 – 7.30 pm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MUSIC……….POETRY………STORY-SHARING&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NETWORKING…….NETPLAYING&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meet and Greet,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even stump your feet,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Challenging,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember, Life is Sweet!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are others planning events, I will try to post details here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am thinking of going to different events and doing &lt;em&gt;sixty-seven minutes of pi&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mandela often spoke of Ubuntu:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ubuntu does not mean that people should not enrich themselves. The
question therefore is: Are you going to do so in order to enable the
community around you to be able to improve?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Trivia"&gt;Trivia&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/sixty-seven-minutes.html#Trivia"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing code_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="input"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;In [7]:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
    &lt;div class="input_area"&gt;
&lt;div class=" highlight hl-ipython3"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;math&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="kn"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;ipython_doctester&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;test&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="c"&gt;# FIXME &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c"&gt;# ipython_doctester broken, might be this prob: https://github.com/catherinedevlin/ipython_doctester/pull/5&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c"&gt;#@test&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;prime&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="sd"&gt;""" Simple primality tester&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="sd"&gt;    Examples:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="sd"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="sd"&gt;    &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; prime(15)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="sd"&gt;    False&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="sd"&gt;    &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; prime(67)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="sd"&gt;    True&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="sd"&gt;    """&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="c"&gt;# Deal with some small numbers&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;n&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;lt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;True&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="n"&gt;factor&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="k"&gt;while&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;factor&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;math&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;sqrt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;n&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;factor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;):&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;False&lt;/span&gt;
        
        &lt;span class="n"&gt;factor&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;+=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="k"&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;True&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing code_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="input"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;In [9]:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
    &lt;div class="input_area"&gt;
&lt;div class=" highlight hl-ipython3"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="c"&gt;# Is 67 prime?&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nb"&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;"Is 67 prime?"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nb"&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;prime&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;67&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="c"&gt;# Mandela would have been 97&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nb"&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;"Is 97 prime?"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nb"&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;prime&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;97&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="output_wrapper"&gt;
&lt;div class="output"&gt;


&lt;div class="output_area"&gt;&lt;div class="prompt"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="output_subarea output_stream output_stdout output_text"&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;Is 67 prime?
True
Is 97 prime?
True
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Sixty-seven-minutes-of-$\pi$"&gt;Sixty-seven minutes of $\pi$&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/sixty-seven-minutes.html#Sixty-seven-minutes-of-%24%5Cpi%24"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Angles are measured in different units.  Mostly, people seem to use degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A right angle is 90 degrees.  The angles in a triangle add up to 180 degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In mathematics it is often useful to use different units, &lt;em&gt;radians&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$\pi$ radians is equal to 180 degrees.  So the angles in a triangle
add up to 180 degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now just as there are 60 minutes in an hour, there are also 60 minutes in a degree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, 67 minutes of $\pi$ is just 67 minutes from 180 degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
$$ x = \pi * 67 / (180 * 60)$$
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing code_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="input"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;In [10]:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
    &lt;div class="input_area"&gt;
&lt;div class=" highlight hl-ipython3"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="c"&gt;# In python&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;math&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;pi&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;67&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;180&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;60&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="output_wrapper"&gt;
&lt;div class="output"&gt;


&lt;div class="output_area"&gt;&lt;div class="prompt output_prompt"&gt;Out[10]:&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class="output_text output_subarea output_execute_result"&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;0.019489509980603347&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing code_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="input"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;In [11]:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
    &lt;div class="input_area"&gt;
&lt;div class=" highlight hl-ipython3"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="c"&gt;# Now 67 minutes of pi number begins 0.01948.&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="mi"&gt;1948&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;67&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="output_wrapper"&gt;
&lt;div class="output"&gt;


&lt;div class="output_area"&gt;&lt;div class="prompt output_prompt"&gt;Out[11]:&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class="output_text output_subarea output_execute_result"&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;2015&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if Mandela had started his campaigning on his birthday in 1948 he would still be at it today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UN are just asking you to spend 67 minutes helping others on his birthday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
</description><category>67</category><category>giving</category><category>mandela</category><category>pi</category><category>take a minute</category><guid>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/sixty-seven-minutes.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 17:02:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Future proof your organisation with free software</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/future-proof-your-organisation-with-free-software.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few days ago I was hoping to be able to listen to a Bermuda
Parliament debate via the Hansard site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was actually unable to find a stream for the debates.  Further
enquiries revealed it does exist, but the streaming uses Microsoft's
Silverlight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This creates a problem, since Microsoft has abandoned Silverlight and
it is no longer supported and does not work in many modern browsers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a scenario that gets repeated over and over.  In what follows,
I will be using government as an example, but you could substitute
&lt;em&gt;organisation&lt;/em&gt; for government and the story is the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here is a typical scenario:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Government has a problem to solve, in this case streaming recordings
of parliamentary debates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Government hires a consultant &lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/future-proof-your-organisation-with-free-software.html#id2" id="id1"&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;  to implement a solution:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the consultant chooses the technology stack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;government workers lack time, resources and skills to understand the
choices the consultant is making.  This problem is exacerbated by
outsourcing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Consultant provides a solution with proprietary technologies.  In many
cases the consultant, not the government owns the software created for
the project.  The result is the government is locked into that
consultant for support and dependent on proprietary software
companies for support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proprietary vendor drops support for the tech that was used.  Result
is unmaintainable websites that eventually have to be replaced.
Everything is thrown out and the process is repeated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the free software world you get a different story:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Government has a problem to solve, in this case streaming recordings
of parliamentary debates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Government IT staff research free software solutions that will solve
the problem&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they look to see what others are using;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they work with those in other government departments with similar
problems;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they pick some free software projects that solve the problem and
that appear to be active and vibrant projects;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the solution is implemented;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;any software written is released as a free software project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this scenario, the end result is something that can be supported not
just by the government workers involved in the project, but actually
anyone with access to the code, which is in fact &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This includes enthusiasts in the local community, but also people
worldwide that are working with the technology that is being used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of being tied to a single supplier, there is choice and hence a
competitive market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The software will generally be both free as in freedom and free as in
cost.  The money saved can be invested in developing local talent to
support it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further money will be saved in the future due to not having to replace
the system due to proprietary vendors stopping support.  Sure the system
will need maintenance and future development, but the government workers
will have all the tools they need to do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system will likely require lower cost hardware resource too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="silverlight-and-moonlight"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Silverlight and Moonlight&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Silverlight story is an excellent example of this sort of problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft launched Silverlight with a great fanfare, whilst ignoring
web standards such as HTML5 that provided very similar capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It integrated nicely with their .NET platform and they provided some
good tools to help with development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Silverlight failed to gain traction and by 2013 Microsoft
announced they were discontinuing development, just six years after
introducing the technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="security-and-proprietary-frameworks"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Security and proprietary frameworks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This never ending stream of proprietary technologies, each supposedly
better than the previous technology, that is no longer supported,
creates serious computer security issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many government websites here in Bermuda use Adobe Flash or
Silverlight.  The latter is no longer supported, the former has very
patchy support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, government sites using Flash depend on ancient versions
that are likely riddled with security holes, yet impossible to
support.  Further, they simply do not work in modern browsers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free software greatly reduces this problem: since the software comes
with freedom, those using it have everything they need to support it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upgrades are done only as and when significant improvements are made,
not on some corporation's timetable, designed to generate revenue for
that corporation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="mono"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mono&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Silverlight is built on top of Microsoft's .NET framework.  .NET is
interesting technology, but in many ways not fundamentally different to
Java.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The free software community has always been wary of .NET.  There is a
project called "mono" that is a free implementation of .NET.  There were
concerns that mono infringes some Microsoft, might use those patents to
attack mono.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, this has not happened and recently Microsoft has released a
number of .NET related tools as open source, but there is still some
wariness about mono.  I believe it does have a significant role to play
in helping Microsoft shops migrate to free software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Silverlight was announced the Mono team started the Moonlight
project, a free implementation of silverlight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project was abandonned in 2012 after poor adoption of Silverlight
and very few sites that use Silverlight work under Moonlight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result is that people who used Silverlight are left with an
expensive mess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also interesting to read the criticisms of Silverlight in the
wikipedia article.  Note that many of these criticisms come from
companies like Adobe, who were probably more motivated by protecting
their ancient Flash technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="footnotes"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table class="docutils footnote" frame="void" id="id2" rules="none"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col class="label"&gt;&lt;col&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="label"&gt;&lt;a class="fn-backref" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/future-proof-your-organisation-with-free-software.html#id1"&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;I say &lt;em&gt;consultant&lt;/em&gt; but it could be any vendor offering a solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't mean to bash consultants, there are some excellent ones out
there, I am planning to be one myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consultant's work pattern should be to come to an organisation,
empower them to solve their own problem and leave them with all the
resources they need to continue to maintain and develop that
solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, "get in, solve the problem, empower the organisation, get
out".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;Too often the "empower the organisation" bit is skipped since by
not doing that the consultant creates future opportunities for
themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>.NET</category><category>free software</category><category>moonlight</category><category>silverlight</category><guid>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/future-proof-your-organisation-with-free-software.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 20:52:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>D Bermuda Pi</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div tabindex="-1" id="notebook" class="border-box-sizing"&gt;
    &lt;div class="container" id="notebook-container"&gt;

&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Bermuda-Pi"&gt;Bermuda Pi&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Bermuda-Pi"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
$$\Delta \; B\epsilon\rho\mu\delta\alpha \; \Pi$$$$Number \; -e^{i\pi}$$
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The week 10th to 18th October 2015 there is a lot happening in Bermuda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;TEDx Bermuda on 10th October&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;America's Cup racing 16th-18th October&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first anniversary of hurricanes Fay and Gonzalo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This creates a good opportunity to run a number of small events around
&lt;a href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html"&gt;Free Software&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html"&gt;Free Culture&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Science, Technology, Engineering and Mathematics &lt;a href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html"&gt;STEM&lt;/a&gt; is already
getting a lot of attention.  This is natural in a world where there is
so much innovation and change in current times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout my life technological change has created a lot of wonderful
things.  At the same time, humanity and social systems are struggling
to keep pace with this change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html"&gt;STEAM&lt;/a&gt; adds the Arts into STEM.  Making the Bermuda $\pi$ a STEAM
powered event seems a natural choice, as the event can then embrace
Bermudian culture in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, a hurricane can be viewed as a giant steam engine.
Bermuda once ran a steam powered island.  How about bringing this to
the 21st century:  &lt;em&gt;D Bermuda $\pi$, STEAM powered&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id="Free-Culture"&gt;Free Culture&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Free-Culture"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;People in the free software movement have been dealing with this
change for some time.  They have developed ways of working with
technology that not only scale, but also enable people to build
systems that evolve naturally over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a more general Free Culture movement, publishing artistic
material under &lt;a href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html"&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/a&gt; licenses that mirror the free
software licenses.  Generally, these licenses allow others to build on
the ideas and use them in their own work, usually with attribution.
Some licenses do not permit commercial use, but many do.  Authors
choose a license based on their own values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id="Weather-and-hurricanes"&gt;Weather and hurricanes&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Weather-and-hurricanes"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given the connection with Fay and Gonzalo some events would focus on
hurricane research in the Bermuda context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Event-Ideas"&gt;Event Ideas&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Event-Ideas"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id="A-Pi-conference"&gt;A Pi conference&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#A-Pi-conference"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raspberry Pi's&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weather data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hurricane simulation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Damage surveys and damage estimation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Impact of climate change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lightning talks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;python and pi's in Bermuda education&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aim for most presentations to be about activities that are going on
already in Bermuda, with some visions for future projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invite others from overseas that are doing similar work.  Better
still, people we are already collaborating with on Bermuda projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focus on the Bermuda context: why is what you are doing a good fit for
Bermuda, how can it fit better?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h4 id="Music,-Art"&gt;Music, Art&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Music,-Art"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Allow local musicians and artists to work and play together.  Work on
making local artists work freely available on line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work on ways technology can complement the arts and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="Story-Telling"&gt;Story Telling&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Story-Telling"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have people tell their hurricane stories about last year's storms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Structure in a way that the stories might inspire new ideas to gather
data and do research based on data from previous storms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A 5km run over a 3.14 ($\pi$) mile course.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pies to eat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Education, teaching students using raspberry pi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ideas here are very much inspired by the way &lt;a href="https://us.pycon.org"&gt;python conferences are run&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim is to have a number of small events, that together make up the &lt;code&gt;Bermuda Pi&lt;/code&gt; experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Food and sustainable agriculture&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="Local-Bermuda-food"&gt;Local Bermuda food&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Local-Bermuda-food"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;h4 id="How-to-do-sustainable-agriculture"&gt;How to do sustainable agriculture&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#How-to-do-sustainable-agriculture"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Leisure-activities"&gt;Leisure activities&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Leisure-activities"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fay and Gonzalo parties would seem a good starter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music, story-telling, Bermudian food,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gombeys!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 5km run over a 3.14 ($\pi$) mile course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pies to eat!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Weather"&gt;Weather&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Weather"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Any event during hurricane season has to pay attention to the weather.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that one theme of &lt;code&gt;D Bermuda Pi&lt;/code&gt; will be hurricane research it
would be unfortunate if the event were hit by a hurricane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having said that, it would give the researchers valuable first hand experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One project to work on during the week would be getting better
estimates of the probability of the event being hit by bad weather.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use long term climate features such as El Nino, the North Atlantic
Oscillation, and the Bermuda High to help with contingency planning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Develop tools that can help with future event planning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Study detailed windfields around the island to better understand the
challenges faced by the sailors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Study tides and currents around the island&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html"&gt;Murphy's Law&lt;/a&gt; is likely to intervene here, so in the meanwhile it
would be good if we kept an eye on the long range hurricane forecasts
and nearer the time be in a position to work with Bermuda Weather and
have plans in place in the event of bad weather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Sustainablility-and-environmental-impact"&gt;Sustainablility and environmental impact&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Sustainablility-and-environmental-impact"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Renewable-Energy"&gt;Renewable Energy&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Renewable-Energy"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Information-security-and-privacy"&gt;Information security and privacy&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Information-security-and-privacy"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Cryptocurrencies,-Bitcoin"&gt;Cryptocurrencies, Bitcoin&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Cryptocurrencies,-Bitcoin"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Bermuda-Based-Organisations"&gt;Bermuda Based Organisations&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Bermuda-Based-Organisations"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BIOS station&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bermuda Weather&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BEST -- sustainablility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;code441&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;codtuna&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pecha Kucha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chewstick&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Others?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Coding-Sprint"&gt;Coding Sprint&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Coding-Sprint"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Work on free software projects for a better Bermuda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Reinsurance"&gt;Reinsurance&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Reinsurance"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many of the reinsurers are using free software and the python language in particular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be possible to have a &lt;em&gt;free software in finance&lt;/em&gt; track,
perhaps along the lines of the PyData conferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Visitors"&gt;Visitors&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Visitors"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free software practitioners and enthusiasts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python Foundation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RedHat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Canonical/Ubuntu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Environmentalists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meteorologists and climate researchers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Venues"&gt;Venues&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Venues"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This will very much depend on the level of interest&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Southampton Princess conference hall, used for TEDx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BIOS station&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BIOS station is close to the airport and close to Paget Island (see below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h4 id="Paget-Island"&gt;Paget Island&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Paget-Island"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paget Island is one of a number of Government run islands.  It has
basic facilities.  It would make an excellent venue for a coding
sprint focussing on the environment and sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bermuda is an expensive place to visit, some free sofware enthusiasts
would be more than happy to come and camp on the island.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One goal would be to make this as inclusive an event as possible,
hence creating many different activities that will appeal to different
demographics, but also to find ways to mix those people and give them
new experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The buildings and infrastructure on Paget Island are in need of some
TLC.  It would be good to work towards building a place run on
renewable energy, environmentally positive where people can come to
study how we are doing things in Bermuda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The philosophy of a camp on the island would be to leave the place
better than it is found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h4 id="Chewstick"&gt;Chewstick&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Chewstick"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h4 id="Everywhere!"&gt;Everywhere!&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Everywhere!"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Trivia"&gt;Trivia&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Trivia"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h4 id="Around-the-world-in-80-days"&gt;Around the world in 80 days&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Around-the-world-in-80-days"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;This blog started as a blog for an idea to create an *Around the world
in 80 days* idea, to run little competitions where people get miles
(or kilometers) for activities.  The idea is to see how far round the
world you can get in 80 days, with fun twists along the way.
One idea was to do an &lt;em&gt;Around Bermuda on Bermuda Bus and Ferry&lt;/em&gt;
competition.  I learnt a lot on the project, but never quite got it
out of the door.  But that is another story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a version still limping along on heroku: &lt;a href="https://tonzone80days.herokuapp.com/"&gt;https://tonzone80days.herokuapp.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kudos to heroku.  I have a half build project running there, haven't
checked it in ages and boom it springs into life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some other pieces coming together that might make the bus
thing viable in the near future, just needs a bit of time applied to
it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that I found useful in the project was thinking in an 80 day
time horizon.  So I was curious about what date is 80 days before 10th
October 2015, the date for the start of the Bermuda $\pi$.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hitting &lt;em&gt;Home&lt;/em&gt; on the &lt;a href="https://tonzone80days.herokuapp.com/"&gt;https://tonzone80days.herokuapp.com/&lt;/a&gt; shows me this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jun 29, 2015 is today's date&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sep 17, 2015 is 80 days from today&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apr 10, 2015 was 80 days ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So time for a little python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing code_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="input"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;In [6]:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
    &lt;div class="input_area"&gt;
&lt;div class=" highlight hl-ipython3"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="c"&gt;# lets see what python says&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;datetime&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;bermuda_pi_start&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;datetime&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;date&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;2015&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;eighty_days_before_start&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;bermuda_pi_start&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;datetime&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;timedelta&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;days&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;80&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="nb"&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;eighty_days_before_start&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="output_wrapper"&gt;
&lt;div class="output"&gt;


&lt;div class="output_area"&gt;&lt;div class="prompt"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="output_subarea output_stream output_stdout output_text"&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;2015-07-22
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing code_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="input"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;In [ ]:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
    &lt;div class="input_area"&gt;
&lt;div class=" highlight hl-ipython3"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;So&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;things&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;need&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;get&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;started&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;on&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;July&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;22&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;nd&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;2015&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
$$2015^{{10}^2}$$
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h4 id="What's-this-*Number-$-e^{i\pi}$-thing-about?"&gt;What's this *Number $-e^{i\pi}$ thing about?&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#What's-this-*Number-%24-e%5E%7Bi%5Cpi%7D%24-thing-about?"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a wonderful equation in mathematics that links some of the key
constants from the world of mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is $\pi$, the ratio between a circle's diameter and its
circumference. $\pi$ turns up all the time in mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there is &lt;em&gt;e&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both $\pi$ and $e$ are transcendental, a special type of number,
although there are an infinite number of transendental numbers, when
they turn up in mathematics they tend to be important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there is 1.  The special number that you can multiply any other
number by and leave it unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there is 0.  The special number you can add to anything and leave it unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The equation is known as &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Euler%27s_identity"&gt;Euler's identity&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
$$ e^{i\pi} + 1 = 0 $$&lt;p&gt;As this would be the first Bermuda $\pi$ it would:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Bermuda-$\pi$-Number-1-=-$-e^{i\pi}$"&gt;Bermuda $\pi$ Number 1 = $-e^{i\pi}$&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Bermuda-%24%5Cpi%24-Number-1-=-%24-e%5E%7Bi%5Cpi%7D%24"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let's make it number one, every year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
</description><category>bermuda</category><category>chewstick</category><category>education</category><category>python</category><category>raspberry pi</category><guid>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 21:12:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Where's de bus</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/wheres-de-bus.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year's TLF students are considering creating an application to
give Bermuda's public transport users up to date information on where
the buses and ferries actually are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transit authorities that have made this data available have found a
number of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.actsoft.com/public-transportation-profits-from-gps-tracking/"&gt;benefits&lt;/a&gt; of bus tracking, including increased usage of
public transport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a thriving open source project, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://onebusaway.org/"&gt;One Bus Away&lt;/a&gt; which looks
like it could be used in the Bermuda environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A first step in getting the transport data into the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://developers.google.com/transit/gtfs/reference"&gt;General Transit
Feed Specification&lt;/a&gt; (GTFS) format.  This provides a flexible format
for transit data.  It is how you specify bus stop locations, routes
and timetables.  Once you have your data in this format there are a
number of projects that you can use to create a powerful transit
application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://onebusaway.org/"&gt;One Bus Away&lt;/a&gt; project is an open source project that is being
used in a number of US and Canadian cities.  It should be usable here
in Bermuda too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google provides good support for transit information and the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.dutchnews.nl/news/archives/2015/06/the-netherlands-debuts-new-google-public-transport-service/"&gt;Netherlands&lt;/a&gt; recently became the first country in the world to
provide full information via their service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst this support from Google is good to have, since many tourists
will be using google maps whilst visiting the island, there are
benefits to being in control of your own data and websites.  There are
restrictions on the use of Google maps and you are not in control of
future development when you use that platform.  Further, users may not
wish to share their location with Google due to privacy concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.openstreetmap.org/search?query=bermuda#map=12/32.2949/-64.7830"&gt;OpenStreetMap&lt;/a&gt; is an free and open project to make top quality
digital maps available.  The Bermuda map is quite excellent.  Further,
there is a good open source javascript library, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://leafletjs.com/"&gt;leaflet&lt;/a&gt; to create
interactive maps using OpenStreetMap data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few months back Open Bermuda started work on a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/openbermuda/wheres-de-bus"&gt;Where's de bus&lt;/a&gt;
project during a hackathon.  The challenge at that time was finding
out where the actual bus stops were.  It is hoped that it will be
possible to get this information and full bus and ferry timetables in
machine readable form from the Bermuda Transportation Board (BTB).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the small size of Bermuda and its transit network it would also
be possible to crowd-source the data for a transit application.  If
live GPS data is not avaialable from BTB an alternative would be to
create a mobile application that public transport users could run and
use to report bus locations as well as how full the bus currently is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are already some open source GPS tracking systems available such
as &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.opengts.org/"&gt;OpenGTS&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.traccar.org/"&gt;Traccar&lt;/a&gt; that might be usable here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bermuda</category><category>bus</category><category>ferry</category><category>open source</category><category>transit</category><guid>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/wheres-de-bus.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 14:14:04 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>