<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Around the world in 80 days</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/</link><description>Blog for an 80 day coding and exercise experiment.</description><atom:link href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 15:35:43 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Blades and Sens results correlated?</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/blades-and-sens-results-correlated.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div tabindex="-1" id="notebook" class="border-box-sizing"&gt;
    &lt;div class="container" id="notebook-container"&gt;

&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have felt for a while that when the Blades win, the Sens also seem
to do better.  When the Blades lose, the Sens don't do so well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My guess is this is mostly just perspective, but I follow both teams.
Blades, or Sheffield United, are hoping to get a place in the League 1
play-offs.  The Sens, or Ottawa Senators, are trying to get into the
Stanley Playoffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you'd asked me at the start of the year, I would have thought being
about where we are was a distinct possibility.  I still felt we might
push into the top two.  That would get us up to the Championship
automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sens on the other hand appeared to be going nowhere.  Until the
inevitable sacking of the coach to be replaced by Dave Cameron, who
was the assistant up to that point.  And for a while nothing changed,
but then a new goalie was brought in, due to injuries.  Since then
they have been on a run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last few games have been just like watching the Blades.  The
Blades never (well almost never) do it the easy way.  So it is always
a season of maybe, just waiting for the point where it all unravels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this Sens run has been different.  They are already way beyond
what anyone could have hoped for a few months back.  But now they are
tantalisingly close to a playoffs, with a team that is playing well
and having fun.  But like the Blades, they've been doing it the hard
way.  3-0 leads disappearing, coming from behind to go on and win in
over-time.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="getting-some-data"&gt;Getting some data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, there has been a lot going on and my guess is that anything
that might be in the data will be better explained by major changes such
as of coaching staff or players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So first problem, getting the data.  I am planning to just get this season's results for both teams and extract the days when they both played, then take a look at how the results lined up.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="yesterday-s-games"&gt;Yesterday's games&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mighty Blades had a key game against local rivals Doncaster.  As
per usual, they did things the hard way, coming from behind twice to
end up winners 3-2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is two big wins over local rivals in a matter of days.  The
Blades are now firmly in the playoff positions, one more win from the
last three games might be all that is needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another local side, Chesterfield, are looming large.  It feels like
they will play a part in the rest of our season.  I grew up on the
Chesterfield side of Sheffield, almost equidistant from the two
grounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the Senators were at home to the Pittsburgh Penguins last
night, in what really was a must win game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was also fan appreciation night.  Within 10 seconds of the start
they were 1-0 down.  By 5 minutes in they were 2-0 down and by the end
of the first period it was 3-0.  Oh dear.  Sid Crosby on form and the
young Sens not firing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second period was a different story.  Sens put the Penguins under
pressure, but nothing finding the net, until 5 minutes from the end of
the period.  Pageau managed to sneak one in off one of the Penguin's
skates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;30 seconds into the third period they got a second.  Two minutes from
time they equalised and then Mark Stone fired in the winner in
overtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that is what I call a fan appreciation night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and Blades and Sens both win on the same night, so that hypothesis
is proven ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
</description><category>sufc sens</category><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/blades-and-sens-results-correlated.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 21:48:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bermuda 3 Bahamas 0</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/bermuda-3-bahamas-0.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This afternoon Bermuda were playing Bahamas in a World Cup qualifier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the second leg, but Bermuda, led by Nahki Wells, were already
5-0 win in the Bahamas last Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This game hadn't been generally broadcast in Bermuda.  But we had seen
highlights, and the first many of us knew about the game was via a
banner that was put out on the TV station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a long suffering supporter of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sheffield_United_F.C."&gt;Mighty Blades&lt;/a&gt; I have rarely
been in the position of being able to go to a game, already 5-0 up.  I
have also never been to a World Cup game before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So today we set off early to the game on the moped.  The game was a
sell out, parking was likely to be tricky.  In any case, the build up
to the game would likely be fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was cold.  Not Canada cold, but Bermuda cold.  Cloudy and damp,
windy and looked like it could rain any minute.  The rain held off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The build up to the game was fun too.  Many in the crowd knew one or
more of the players well.  There was excitement that we would see a
few goals, and a slight fear that maybe things could unravel.  And
there were Gombeys :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bermuda did dominate the game from start to finish.  The goalkeeper,
Fredrick Hall, was substited at half-time.  I am guessing that he was
frozen, as the ball boys had all had a lot more work to do.  It was
a good time to give his back-up a chance to play, and he at least had
some saves to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nahki Wells won a penalty, then crashed the resulting kick against the
cross-bar.  This was close to half-time, Bermuda had already had 5-6
really good chances, but the ball didn't want to go in the net.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier Wells had been fouled, about 30 yards out and needed treatment
from the physio.  He was then made to leave the field, and was not
able to be there for the free-kick that required the treatment.
Broken rules?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Justi Donawa had what looked like a painful injury to his foot, and
had to be replaced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second half was more of the same, but Bermuda were increasingly
getting the feeling that it was going to end 0-0.  The players felt it
and the crowd too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then Nahki Wells broke through and this time made no mistake, 1-0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this point every time Bermuda went forward, and that was
frequently, they looked like scoring.  The game ended 3-0.  The Gombey
Warriors will play Guatemala, away on the 8th of June, at home on the
16th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two last things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is a very young Bermuda team.  I heard the average age is
just 21.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Bahamas also have a young team.  They played a good game today,
the game flowed, there were lots of entertaining moments.  It can't
have been easy travelling away already 5-0 down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a great afternoon, two teams, refs and the crowd all played
their part.  Looking forward to the next games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>sufc football bermuda</category><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/bermuda-3-bahamas-0.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2015 22:34:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Pi Day at Chewstick</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/pi-day-at-chewstick.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This Saturday the date is 3.14.15, March 14th, '15.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;March 14th has become known as &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.piday.org/"&gt;Pi Day&lt;/a&gt;, on account of the fact that
the first three digits of the mathematical constant pi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year it is extra special, since the next two digits are 15, which
corresponds to the year.  After that, the next five digits of pi are
9:26:53.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To mark the occasion &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.chewstick.org/"&gt;Chewstick&lt;/a&gt; at the new premises on 81 Front St
is hosting a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.raspberrypi.org/pi-day-is-around-the-corner/"&gt;Raspberry Pi Day&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A raspberry pi is a $30 computer (Raspberry Pi) that runs off a phone
charger. We will be making videos of people performing, playing games
etc, so bring your camera, SD card, instruments to contribute your
content as we build a Raspberry Pi media centre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/RaspberryPi/raspberry.jpg" src="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/galleries/RaspberryPi/raspberry.jpg" style="width: 400px; height: 300px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will also have a retro games console running on a pi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan is to start the event at 9:26:53am and run with it until
9:26:53pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have three working raspberry pi's and some SD cards that can be used
to host the operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have one pi running the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://kodi.tv/"&gt;Kodi&lt;/a&gt; media centre that I hope to add some
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.chewstick.org/"&gt;Chewstick&lt;/a&gt; and Bermuda content to.  The image below shows Kodi
displaying the Bermuda weather.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/RaspberryPi/weather_pi.jpg" src="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/galleries/RaspberryPi/weather_pi.jpg" style="width: 400px; height: 300px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have another pi running a retro games console and a third running
the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.raspbian.org/"&gt;Raspian&lt;/a&gt; operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no need to bring anything but yourself to the event, but if
you do have raspberry pi's or related hardware it would be good to
bring them along too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All going well, we will also have actual pies to eat too :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information see this &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1563187683958954/"&gt;facebook&lt;/a&gt; posting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>linux raspberry-pi chewstick</category><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/pi-day-at-chewstick.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 15:14:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bermudaful Day</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/bermudaful-day.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks back I had my sons and their partners visiting from
Canada.  They were having difficulty understanding why I am thinking
it was so cold here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've lived in many places, but including hard Ottawa winters, but
never felt as cold as Bermuda the last few weeks.  It is all
perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had good times while they were here, below is just one of those
days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pink-and-blue-limo"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pink and blue limo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'd decided to go to Spittal Pond.  As we are down the west end of
the island, that means 2 buses, or &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/the-pink-and-blue-limo.rst"&gt;the pink and blue limo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were in luck, the number 7 bus pulled up just as we reached the
stop.  A sunny day, so the views along South Shore were spectacular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were soon in town and just had a bit of time between buses to look
at Victoria Park and the web of ropes holding up trees that have been
lifted back up since the hurricanes knocked them over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onto the number 1 bus and another beautiful journey.  You are higher
up on the bus, and see so a lot more.  Plus it stops every now and
again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="spittal-pond"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Spittal Pond&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/SpittalPond/20150221_132114.jpg" src="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/galleries/SpittalPond/20150221_132114.jpg" style="width: 400px; height: 300px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have liked Spittal Pond for a lot of years.  It is a place in
Bermuda where you can really feel in a natural environment.
Spectactular views and lots to explore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also a place that changes through the seasons, so there is
always something new to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the first time I had been since the hurricanes.  There wasn't
much sign of them on this walk.  Just a fiew views that didn't used to
exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we were treated to a sunny day without much wind.  The ocean
always looks better in the sun.  It lights up the clarity of the water
and the pink sand beneath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The path leads down to some rocks where in a few places there are
actually steps cut out to make it a little easier to clamber over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the waters edge there were a couple of large parrot fish, bobbing
around as the waves were breaking against the rocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/SpittalPond/20150221_140921.jpg" src="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/galleries/SpittalPond/20150221_140921.jpg" style="width: 400px; height: 300px;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="portuguese-rock"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Portuguese Rock&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We took the little detour up to a rocky cliff overlooking the ocean.
Here there is a brass plate that is a cast of an inscription that was
found on the rock here.  It has the date 1543 and some other marks
that have been interpretted as "R. P." standing for Rex Portugaline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1543 is nearly 70 years before the island was settled, indicating that
there is more to the early history of this island than we are every
likely to discover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/SpittalPond/20150221_133042.jpg" src="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/galleries/SpittalPond/20150221_133042.jpg" style="width: 400px; height: 300px;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-farm-on-mcgalls-hill"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The farm on McGalls Hill&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once back at the road we decided to walk over the hill, past St Mark's
church and down McGall's Hill to the Northrock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part way down the hill we stopped to look at a small banana
plantation.  The farmer, Henry, and his wife, Theresa, were there
looking after the land and invited us down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Henry delighted in telling us just what is invoved in growing
bananas.  He also showed us onions, giant cloves of garlic and new
potatoes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They had such patience in showing how all the different plants
thrived.  Henry also told us about the fruit salad tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citrus fruit used to be a big thing in Bermuda.  If you visit the
island ask an older Bermudian about the citrus and they will tell you
Bermuda used to have some of the best citrus fruit you can find.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Henry explained that you can even grow fruit salad trees here: a
single tree that grows lemons, limes, oranges and grapefruit, all as a
result of grafting buts from different fruits onto a wild lemon base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, it was a great day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/bermudaful-day.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 03:35:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Mercurial Adjustment</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/mercurial-adjustment.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;So careful observers will note the project is running a little late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim was to launch the site on February 1st.  I am not quite ready
to go live yet.   I want a few more features implemented first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am also aware that there is a lot still to do.  But it was always
the plan to build features through the 80 day running of the
competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project has been a very interesting experience for me.  At the
start, I had a task that I knew I could get done in a few days.  With
stuff I had used in the past.  But, I wanted to learn some knew
stuff.  &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://angularjs.org/"&gt;angular.js&lt;/a&gt; was one thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like python and have enjoyed working with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.djangoproject.com/"&gt;django&lt;/a&gt; over the
years.  It has been a struggle at times.  I've always loved what the
project is doing, it has been a constantly evolving project.  Often,
knew releases would break old sites.  This was actually a good thing,
a bit of reading and you could find the solution.  And if you
implemented it, your code was generally better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have loved &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/1.7/topics/migrations/"&gt;django migrations&lt;/a&gt;.  I like to develop sites as they
are being run.  Now one tricky bit is knowing when you can (or should)
let others loose on the site.  They might put work into it that would
be lost by changes you want to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where these migrations come in very handy.  Over the course of
what I have been doing I have been running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
python 80days/manage.py makemigrations
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and/or:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
python 80days/manage.py migrate
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;more or less at random (as I got to know what the errors really mean,
so less random as time went on.  And what has been cool is that pretty
much every time they have lead me through the process and done exactly
what I wanted with pretty minimal fuss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Murphy's law dictates that I will now encounter a nightmare with
migrations, at some, inconvenient point.  The good news is I have good
confidence in these migrations.  In particular, I love the way you get
the code for the migration.  So, if I am doing something scary, or if
it all breaks, then I can take a look at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="angular"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Angular&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has been a rocky ride at times.  On the face of it, it is doing
something elegant and simple.   But it is doing what it does inside
the DOM model as implemented by various browsers.  These browsers are
trying to be helpful.  So I spent an afternoon wrestling with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/angular/angular.js/issues/1459"&gt;angular
directives for table rows&lt;/a&gt;.  I just wanted to write a partial piece
of html for each row.  Now it seems this is really tricky to do in
angular because of the way browsers try to be helpful with broken
table code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I am happy with where things are.  There are a lot of areas
I would like to learn more about.  I need to spend an afternoon with
the node/angular testing setup.  I really do need to start writing
those tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, there are a lot of things I know can be done better, but
most are good enough for now and I can work on the pain points as they
become more aparent,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="summary"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news is that after all the research and experimenting I have
found a lot of the gotchas.  In short, I have the tools and have
figured enough about how they work that I should be quite productive
from here on in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was cookiecutter a good idea?  Very much so.  It introduced me to lots
of things that I would not of explored at this point otherwise.  Some
bits I have pretty much forgotten about, but I think most of the stuff
I have explored is mentioned in this blog somewhere, or in &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/swfiua/"&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;.
So, if nothing else, it is there if I need to refer to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="and-finally"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;And finally..&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the mercurial adjustment works like this.  Every software project
runs late.  They run late for lots of reasons.  Most of them good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mercury_%28planet%29"&gt;planet mercury&lt;/a&gt; orbits the sun in just under 88 days.  But
here on planet earth, in that time the earth moves, so that it is
actually nearly 116 days before the earth, mercury and sun are in a
similar alignment.  This probably needs to be done in a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/jupyter"&gt;jupyter
notebook&lt;/a&gt;, so for now, the deal is that depending on your frame of
reference and definition of a day, 80 days could arguably be deemed to
be a shade over 105 days as most of us here on earth know them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So next time your n day software project is running late, come into
work dressed as Mercury ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/mercurial-adjustment.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 19:47:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Are we nearly there yet?</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/are-we-nearly-there-yet.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As of last night I have competition entry all working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see all the competions being run.  If a competition has not
started yet or is still in progress you can enter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To enter, just give the nickname you want to use for the competion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next job is to add code to allow competitors to create and join teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This shouldn't take too long given what I now have.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>angular django python 80days</category><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/are-we-nearly-there-yet.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 15:43:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Angular velocity</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/angular-velocity.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;So it has been a while since I blogged about the 80 day project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is largely due to most of my free time has been spent working on
the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just to recap, 77 days into the project I still had quite a bit to
do.  Most of the work up to that point had been on getting pieces
together, decide what tools to use, learning those tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next job was to move the angular code around a bit and try and get
django serving it all.  In particular, I had decided it was probably
worthwhile to have the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://angularjs.org/"&gt;angular.js&lt;/a&gt; partial html pieces go through
the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.djangoproject.com/"&gt;django&lt;/a&gt; template engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting npm up and running, with a recent enough version can be
tricky, but there was an excellent guide on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/joyent/node/wiki/Installing-Node.js-via-package-manager#debian-and-ubuntu-based-linux-distributions"&gt;Installing npm on Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With moving all the files around, &lt;strong&gt;.bowerrc&lt;/strong&gt; needed editing a few
times to point it at where the bower_components were now made to be
installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/global-hackathon-team-bermuda.html"&gt;Global Hackathon, Team Bermuda&lt;/a&gt; I have had mild
paranoia that cross-site-request-forgery is going to bite me at some
point.  I am hoping that by serving everything under django I will
avoid that nightmare.  In the meanwhile, I did at this &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/swfiua/80days/commit/678ae25e432b8633230bf67f8168a8f8188717b1"&gt;csrf fix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A previous post, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/nginx-on-kodingcom.html"&gt;Nginx on koding.com&lt;/a&gt; came in useful for setting
up postgres on koding.com as I decided it was more than time to get
this thing running on a cloud based machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have not found myself using &lt;em&gt;django-angular&lt;/em&gt;, but the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django-angular.readthedocs.org/en/latest/integration.html"&gt;django
angular integration&lt;/a&gt; docs have been an enormous help in highlighting
issues in integrating django and angular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In amongst all this I decided it was time to add &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/tomwalker/django_quiz/"&gt;django quiz&lt;/a&gt; to
the mix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was mostly painless, following the django-quiz docs, but when I
fired up the server it failed.  The problem was down to me using
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django-allauth.readthedocs.org/"&gt;django-allauth&lt;/a&gt; which effectively removes &lt;em&gt;auth.User&lt;/em&gt;. The fix is to
use &lt;em&gt;settings.AUTH_USER_MODEL&lt;/em&gt; if you want to reference the &lt;em&gt;User&lt;/em&gt;
model in your own models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/tomwalker/django_quiz/commit/9416c05cd447e3aa40a2351684f2105dafa95e13"&gt;user model fix&lt;/a&gt; and made a pull request.  Happily, the
project maintainer actioned the request within the hour (many thanks
Tom!) and I was able to update to the new version with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
pip install git+https://github.com/tomwalker/django_quiz.git
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By February 1st I was starting to get comfortable with angular and the
pieces were coming together.  I have some simple partials, I have
angular calling the django rest API and I have the beginnings of some
views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next task is to display competitions a user can enter and provide
an enter button.   At this point I did a bit more thinking and
reading.  Deciding what logic to put in angular and what to put in
django views and api calls needs a little thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here the plan is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;get the competion list and competion entry features working&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;get team creation and team membership features implemented&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;get the site up and running in the cloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a simple test server on koding.com, but want to run the actual
site on a different instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>angular javascript django 80days</category><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/angular-velocity.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 14:36:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Got the ingredients, lets cook this thing</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/got-the-ingredients-lets-cook-this-thing.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This post is likely going to be a bit of a mixture.  It started out as
an account of what I am doing today, but I think it might turn into an
account of why a 3 day project can take 80 days and why that isn't
always a bad thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I have had this goal for 80 days to create a website.  Now this
hasn't been my only goal in this period.  Actually, I have had a lot
of other stuff going on.  Oh, and there was Christmas and New Year and
of course the annual flu/cold/sore throat fun to deal with.  Also,
this is supposed to be a fun project and I have other fun things I
have been doing at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also been using it to learn some new stuff.  Now this is always
a dilemma with IT: learn to do things the &lt;em&gt;proper&lt;/em&gt; way, learn about
the latest tools or just use what you already know?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could have built this thing with pure django and simple html
templates in 2-3 days I am sure.  Well not quite that because I need
all these things too:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;authentication, user registration, preferably supporting third party
openID management.  That is where &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django-allauth.readthedocs.org/"&gt;django-allauth&lt;/a&gt; comes in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;database migrations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deployment to cloud.  I think I will use &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/https//koding.com"&gt;koding.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;code generation.  I wrote some simple code generators. I should be
able to include these in a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://cookiecutter.readthedocs.org/en/latest/"&gt;cookiecutter&lt;/a&gt; so my next project will
be much quicker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am learning &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://angularjs.org/"&gt;angular.js&lt;/a&gt;.  I already see the promise in this and
it should strengthen my javascript skills which will help with the
next phases of the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I have the ingredients together.  I think I know most of the
problems I will have, just have to put this thing together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First thing: &lt;cite&gt;angular dates are in milliseconds&lt;/cite&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now with this knowledge I have the angular showing today's date,
80 days from now and 80 days ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next stop is to get a form to register a team.  There is quite a bit
to learn here.  I will need to figure out how angular calls REST api's
and of course deal with the form stuff too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK, so thanks to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://campus.codeschool.com"&gt;codeschool&lt;/a&gt; I now have a good idea of how most of
this angular stuff hangs together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next task is to see if I can get data from the django rest
services.  Before I do that I think it is time to re-organise the code
so that it can all be served by the django server.  I suspect this
might get tricky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I should be in town in the morning, so I decided this would
be a good time to see if I can get this thing running on Gonzalo,
otherwise known as the &lt;cite&gt;laptop without an escape key&lt;/cite&gt;.  This thing
also has a battery with a life of about 5 minutes.  But I like it in a
weird sort of way.  It needs more memory too, but that should be an
easy fix.  I think it might turn into that broom with 20 new heads and
five new handles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will be a good test of whether I can run everything on another machine
without too much pain.  With the screensaver doing the, "all work and
no play", I think it is time to take a break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/got-the-ingredients-lets-cook-this-thing.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 15:50:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Pink and Blue Limo</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/the-pink-and-blue-limo.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I first met &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Acegirl"&gt;ace-girl&lt;/a&gt; I was living in Ottawa.  One day she was
heading out into town on one of her missions.  I asked if she wanted
me to run her wherever she was going in the car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to confess, I don't really enjoy driving around Ottawa.  In
winter, when it is -25C outside then the car is a nice option to
have.  But I know I will spend a chunk of time stuck in traffic.
Plus, Ottawa is a grid system, there are traffic lights every block.
But, if ace-girl is running late then again the car can be handy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This day, she just responded, "Don't worry, I will just take the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.showbus.com/galcanada/octranspo.htm"&gt;Red and White Limo&lt;/a&gt;."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regular readers of this blog (if there are any! -- note to self, look
into google analytics) will know that I have a bit of a thing about
red and white, entirely due to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sheffield_United_F.C."&gt;Red and White Wizards&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my ears pricked up at the mention of red and white.  I was a little
concerned &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Acegirl"&gt;ace-girl&lt;/a&gt; seemed to be planning to take the limo to get where
she wanted.  Really, I would much rather run her there in the car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She quickly put my out of my misery.  The buses in Ottawa are red and
white, so &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Acegirl"&gt;ace-girl&lt;/a&gt; just referred to them as the red and white limo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have always liked the bus.  I grew up in Sheffield, UK at a time
when the bus service was quite excellent.  Being under 16 I could go
anywhere in town for just 2 new pence.  Adults had to pay the princely
sum of 10 new pence.  I would walk down to the bottom of our road and
a bus would always turn up within 10 minutes or so.  No need to check
the timetable: the buses were often 5 minutes or so off schedule, but
they were so regular that it didn't matter.  Sheffield buses were
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bus-and-coach-photos.com/picture/number3844.asp"&gt;Brown and Cream Limos&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not really my favourite colour scheme, red and white would have been
better, but then the blue and white half of the city might never have
taken a bus.  In any case, these things looked like giant ice-cream
sandwiches: a block of vanilla ice cream sandwiched between two
wafers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ride into town was always fun.  I would sit upstairs, preferably
at the front where you could see everything.  My journey was down
Abbeydale Road.  It felt like you could literally find anything you
wanted on Abbeydale Road.  Looking out of the bus I would always
notice new things.  There was the cycle shop that had a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Penny-farthing"&gt;penny
farthing&lt;/a&gt; mounted above the shop window.   A bit further down there
was Bardwell's electronics store.  This was like a little hardware
store only it sold electronic components:  resistors, capacitors and
these new fangled things called transistors.  Oh, and you could still
get valves there too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well move on 30 or so years and I am now in Bermuda with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Acegirl"&gt;ace-girl&lt;/a&gt;.
Nowadays she takes the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bermuda-online.org/bermudabus.jpg"&gt;Pink and Blue Limo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For anyone who enjoys buses, the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bermuda-online.org/bermudabus.jpg"&gt;Pink and Blue Limo&lt;/a&gt; has to be one
of the best bus experiences in the world.  First of all, the buses are
pink and blue.  Pink to match the sand on the beaches, blue to match
the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bus stops are marked by pink or blue poles.  Pink means the bus is
heading in to town, blue means it is heading away from town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am lucky, I live at the top of a hill between South Shore and Middle
Road.  I can walk down to South Shore and take the 7, or I can go to
Middle Road and take the 8.  There is a bus every half hour, happily
at my point in the island the buses are off cut by 15 minutes, the
result is average waiting time should be less than 10 minutes most of
the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have a moped.  This is a great way to get around the island,
but on occasion I head into town and end up having a couple of beers.
One such occasion was last Wednesday.  The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sheffield_United_F.C."&gt;Red and White Wizards&lt;/a&gt;
were playing Tottenham Hotspur in the first leg of the League Cup
semi-final.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Blades are two divisions below Spurs.  Just getting to this semi
was quite an achievement.  I headed in to town with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Acegirl"&gt;ace-girl&lt;/a&gt; to
watch the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can expect, for such a major fixture the bar was packed out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/Blades/packed_out_at_the_hood.jpg" src="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/galleries/Blades/packed_out_at_the_hood.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 400px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was fearing the worst.  The Blades have actually been doing really
well in the cups since &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nigel_Clough"&gt;Nigel Clough&lt;/a&gt; took over as manager.  But
after years of following the Blades I know not to get my hopes up.  I
really just hoped that the game wouldn't be over in 20 minutes with us
3-0 down and the prospect of a pointless game at Bramall Lane the
following week.  In fact, first half the blades looked in control,
even had a couple of half chances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The longer the game went on, the more I dared to hope.  Spurs did get
a penalty, which they scored, but the game finished 1-0.  As this is
two legs, the blades are just 1-0 down at half-time with the second
leg due to be played in front of a sell-out crowd at the Lane.
Tomorrow could be fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, suffice to say, riding home on the bike was not an option.  We
left the bike with one of the people working in the bar.  His bike was
off the road due to a scary accident, happily he just had a bit of
road rash and some bruises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day I took the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bermuda-online.org/bermudabus.jpg"&gt;Pink and Blue Limo&lt;/a&gt; in to town to collect
the bike.  I walked down to the 7, but was sat on the wall admiring
the view and looking for my ticket when the bus sailed past.  Not the
driver's fault, I wasn't at the actual stop.  Fortunately, I had time
to walk over the hill, getting there just in time to admire the view
before the 8 turned up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bermuda bus etiquette is quite complex.  The buses are smaller than
normal buses and only single decker, mainly because the roads here are
pretty narrow.  If you are on the bus you wait until it has come to a
stop before getting up from your seat to get off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The school children always give up their seat to older people.
Everyone greets the driver as they get on the bus.  Usually, there are
a bunch of regulars on the bus.  It is Bermuda, everyone knows
everyone and you see people catching up on news as they encounter
friends and relatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always like to get a seat by the window.  On the number 7 the views
of the South Shore beaches are breathtaking.  On the number 8 you are
inland for much of the journey, but it is never dull.  You
will get glimpses of the ocean, but also see lots of the wonderful
coloured houses and of course all the plants and trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the hurricanes Gonzalo and Fay, back in October there has been
lots more to look at.  First, there was all the damage to the trees as
well as some property damage.  Within a couple of days everything was
pretty much running as normal, but everywhere you looked there were
people helping clean up.  Either soldiers in the regiment, those
working for the government as well as many proud Bermudians working
together to get the island back on its feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the hurricanes took out a lot of trees, so now you can see things
you never knew were there.  The older Bermudians just smile, they have
seen it before, after Fabian or Emily or Felix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journey is a good time to think, to slow down, experience
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vbVyE6hZjCU"&gt;another world that is Bermuda&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am writing this post today in part because the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bermuda-online.org/bermudabus.jpg"&gt;Pink and Blue Limo&lt;/a&gt;
is off the road.  Unfortunately, the government here is short of
money.  As a result, they have been trying to reduce the wage bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is coming at a time when the island is full of excitement having
won the right to host the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.americascup.com/"&gt;America's Cup&lt;/a&gt; in 2017.  There is a lot of
work to do to get the island ready for this.  But the government is
broke.  And to deal with that they made an agreement with the unions
to cut wages in return for days of &lt;em&gt;furlough&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know the ins-and-outs of it all, but the hope was this would
be a temporary measure and that after a year or so the budget would
begin to balance and hours would be restored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This now doesn't look like happening and so the last two days there
have been peaceful demonstrations in town in protest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is hoping that all parties will get around the table and work out
a solution that works for all of Bermuda and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Acegirl"&gt;ace-girl&lt;/a&gt; can get back
to her &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bermuda-online.org/bermudabus.jpg"&gt;Pink and Blue Limo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and if the blades could somehow pull off a miracle tomorrow, that
would also be good ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bermuda bus ottawa sufc</category><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/the-pink-and-blue-limo.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 18:57:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Angular Momentum</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/angular-momentum.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Friday I got to the point that the angular seed app is now checked
into my 80days repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today's mission is to start turning that into the app I really want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the first things I want to do is fix up angular so that it uses
different markers for its template substitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.djangoproject.com/"&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt; uses '{{' and '}}' to mark blocks that the template engine
needs to pay attention to and do substitutions.  Actually, the &lt;cite&gt;django
template languate&lt;/cite&gt; has two escape patterns:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;{{ and }} are used to mark variables to be expanded&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;{% and %} are used to mark django template tags.  These get used for
things like marking &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt; loops and the like&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now by an unhappy coincidence, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://angularjs.org/"&gt;angular.js&lt;/a&gt; also uses {{ and }} to
mark stuff for expansion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happily, angular allows you to over-ride these markers, as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code javascript literal-block"&gt;
&lt;span class="kd"&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nx"&gt;my_app&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nx"&gt;angular&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;module&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'MyApp'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;config&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kd"&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;$interpolateProvider&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nx"&gt;$interpolateProvider&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;startSymbol&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'{$'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nx"&gt;$interpolateProvider&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;endSymbol&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'$}'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, since I already had some code in my &lt;em&gt;app.js&lt;/em&gt; I just added the
extra config code, so my &lt;em&gt;app.js&lt;/em&gt; now looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code javascript literal-block"&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'use strict'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="c1"&gt;// Declare app level module which depends on views, and components
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;angular&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;module&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'myApp'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'ngRoute'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'myApp.view1'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'myApp.view2'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'myApp.version'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;]).&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nx"&gt;config&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;([&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'$routeProvider'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kd"&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;$routeProvider&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="nx"&gt;$routeProvider&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;otherwise&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;({&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;redirectTo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'/view1'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}]).&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="nx"&gt;config&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kd"&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;$interpolateProvider&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nx"&gt;$interpolateProvider&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;startSymbol&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'{$'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nx"&gt;$interpolateProvider&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;endSymbol&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'$}'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, making some progress, but I still can't figure out this controller
thing and how to tie it all together.  Time to go back to
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://campus.codeschool.com"&gt;codeschool&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, their &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://campus.codeschool.com/courses/shaping-up-with-angular-js"&gt;shaping up with angular&lt;/a&gt; introduction.  I had
to register with codeschool.  Thankfully, that was painless bar having
to create yet-another-password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it has been worth it.  You can watch the videos at 1.5x or 2.0x or
slow them down.  It would be great if they took the mythtv trick and
shifted the frequency of voices down so that the presenters don't
sound like chipmunks on speed when you speed things up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good bit is you can click on "Start Challenges" as soon as you are
bored with the video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once in the challenges, the "check my work" button is genius and
extraordinarily helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="angular-date-filter"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Angular date filter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just fell in love with the angular date filter.  Feed it a unix
datetime and it does the right thing.  Eg Unix time began 1969/12/31 @
8:00PM in Bermuda, note the four our offset from UTC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See this &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/swfiua/80days/commit/04a9b8a64f9cb402c434ad1f6b6224757ca09182"&gt;github commit&lt;/a&gt; for some code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="thanks"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thanks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to @ergoemacs on twitter who posted a link to their excellent
mini tutorial on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ergoemacs.org/emacs/emacs_magit-mode_tutorial.html"&gt;magit-mode&lt;/a&gt;: git mode for emacs.  I had this
installed already, but never quite plucked up the courage to try it.
Wow: git in emacs: lovely jubbly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And thanks to stack exchange for this tip on how to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/17798109/how-can-i-diff-a-single-file-with-magit"&gt;diff a single
file with magit&lt;/a&gt;,  Answer: just hit tab in the magit status buffer on
the line for the file you want to diff.  More &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=lovely+jubbly"&gt;lovely-jubbly&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, thanks to Snowy, who helped with the coding:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/Snowy/coding.jpg" src="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/galleries/Snowy/coding.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 400px;"&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>javascript angular django</category><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/angular-momentum.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 16:44:11 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>