<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Around the world in 80 days</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/</link><description>Blog for an 80 day coding and exercise experiment.</description><atom:link rel="self" href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/rss.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 18:15:46 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The Music from UNCLE</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/the-music-from-uncle.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am lucky enough to live in a wonderful part of the world.  &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vbVyE6hZjCU"&gt;Bermuda
is another world&lt;/a&gt;.  It really is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A tiny island of just 60,000 people, a place with a complex history.
There are a lot of wonderful people here.  There are also some cool
things starting to happen here such as &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://code441.com"&gt;code441&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://wearebermuda.com/"&gt;wearebermuda&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is Christmas time.  The last Saturday before Christmas and there
are parties everywhere.  Many of them are company parties.  You know
the thing, you sort of have to go along.  With luck you'll get to sit
with some of the people at work you actually like.  As the night goes
on, if you are lucky, you will find some like-minded people to spend
time with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, no office party for me.  So, we went to a local bar.  There
is a DJ every Saturday night at this place.  The dance floor is always
packed, for a simple reason: he knows his crowd.  And he always walks
around before he starts, plans his work and works his plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night there must have been 60 cars parked in the area.  The place
was packed.  Everyone was having a good time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now only in Bermuda could a DJ start the evening with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wDC7NeVfc30"&gt;My God is
Awesome&lt;/a&gt;, follow it up with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9T4WB2zfmps"&gt;Silent Night&lt;/a&gt; and already have his
audience tapping their feet and getting into the mood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd never heard &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wDC7NeVfc30"&gt;My God is Awesome&lt;/a&gt; before.  Actually, I am sure I
must of heard it, just hadn't really listend.  And I only really
listened this time because it reminded me of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://awesome.naquadah.org/"&gt;Awesome window
manager&lt;/a&gt;  I've been using awesome the last few weeks and it has had a
huge impact on the way I use my computer.   And I am only scratching
the surface of what it can do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this was followed up with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xlVxEAUqWU0"&gt;You can't hurry love&lt;/a&gt;, an old version
by the Supremes.  Another special song for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there was &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vdB-8eLEW8g"&gt;One Love&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JFMtBibwrgY"&gt;Electric Slide&lt;/a&gt;, complete with line
dancing.  Bermudian line dancing has to be seen to be appreciated.
Last night was typical.  A mixture of regulars to the place and those
just there for the party.  Everyone having a good time together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My music tastes are a bit weird.  I pretty much follow the crowd.  And
my guitar music.  I have been (very slowly) learning to play over the
past few years.  I have a few books with tabs, most of them have the
word &lt;em&gt;easy&lt;/em&gt; in their titles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would pick a song and try the patience of those around me by playing
it over and over again, badly.  I would look at the tabs of some and
think, no way I can play that.  But now I am starting to get a little
better and a little more adventurous.  I am noticing songs that have
been there for years ready for me to play.  Song of the moment is the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YZo88P1Ie94"&gt;The Joker&lt;/a&gt;.  Like all good songs, there is lots of scope for
changing the lyrics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
I'm a picker,
I'm a grinder,
I'm a lover,
I'm a sinner,
I play my music in the sun
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grinder not grinner, in tribute to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pTXjp2bf1vo"&gt;Sheffield Grinder&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And seeing as I have a bit of a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://git-scm.com/"&gt;git&lt;/a&gt; obsession:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
I'm a puller,
I'm a merger,
I'm a midnight coder,
I get my checkouts from github.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks Uncle, old stuff still works.  Sometimes it works way better
than the new stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bermuda music awesome</category><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/the-music-from-uncle.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 20:01:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Nginx on koding.com</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/nginx-on-kodingcom.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is more than time that I get the project up and running on a host
somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could just check the code out on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/https//koding.com"&gt;koding.com&lt;/a&gt; and run the project
with django's build in server, but I feel I should run it under
&lt;em&gt;nginx&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could have chosen &lt;em&gt;apache&lt;/em&gt;, but I keep hearing people mention
&lt;em&gt;nginx&lt;/em&gt; so I want to see what it is all about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gooling &lt;em&gt;nginx django koding&lt;/em&gt; threw up a guide to deploying django
with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://agiliq.com/blog/2013/08/minimal-nginx-and-gunicorn-configuration-for-djang/"&gt;nginx and gunicorn&lt;/a&gt;, so let's try that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So all went well until I got to the bit about running the application
with &lt;em&gt;gunicorn&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My project layout is a little different to the one in the guide.  In
particular, the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://cookiecutter.readthedocs.org/en/latest/"&gt;cookiecutter&lt;/a&gt; I used to create the project lays out
the &lt;em&gt;django config&lt;/em&gt; stuff a bit differently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I did the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
export DJANGO_SETTINGS_MODULE="80days.config.production"
gunicorn 80days.wsgi:application
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This got me as far as being told:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
ValueError: Couldn't setup configuration '80days.config.production.Production':
Secret value 'SECRET_KEY' is not set
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time to disappear down the SECRET_KEY rabbit hole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So a little googling tells me a little about the secret key, but no
advice on how to go about keeping it secret.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So looking at what the wonderful &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/pydanny/cookiecutter-django"&gt;cookiecutter django&lt;/a&gt; created I see
the following incantation in &lt;em&gt;config/production.py&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code python literal-block"&gt;
&lt;span class="kn"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;configurations&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;values&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="c"&gt;# SECRET KEY&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;SECRET_KEY&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;values&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;SecretValue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c"&gt;# END SECRET KEY&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what is this &lt;em&gt;configuration.values&lt;/em&gt; thing?   Turns out it is coming
from the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django-configurations.readthedocs.org/"&gt;django configurations&lt;/a&gt; application that the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://cookiecutter.readthedocs.org/en/latest/"&gt;cookiecutter&lt;/a&gt;
was kind enough to include.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK, so it helps you not have to do&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code python literal-block"&gt;
&lt;span class="kn"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;foo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, that has to be a good thing :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So reading the docs I come to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
django-configurations allows you to optionally reduce the amount
of validation and setup code in your settings.py by using Value
classes. They have the ability to handle values from the process
environment of your software (os.environ) and work well in
projects that follow the Twelve-Factor methodology.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will leave this &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://12factor.net/"&gt;twelve factor&lt;/a&gt; thing for another day, but a quick
glance suggests there are some good guidelines there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, digging into the docs for django configurations (which, by the way
are quite excellent).  I come to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://django-configurations.readthedocs.org/en/latest/values/"&gt;this little gem&lt;/a&gt;.  In short, this
magic &lt;em&gt;values.SecretValue()&lt;/em&gt; is there to discourage me from actually
putting my secret key in the config file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is good, because I am pretty sure I have committed this sin in
pretty much every django project I have done up to now.  Thank you
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://cookiecutter.readthedocs.org/en/latest/"&gt;cookiecutter&lt;/a&gt; :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having said that, I feel this another case where good intentions are
likely to result in bad security, for more see my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/rant-about-computer-insecurity.html"&gt;rant about computer
(in)security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a tight deadline, how many developers would just slap a value in
the config file &lt;em&gt;just to get things working&lt;/em&gt; and be done with it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="now-what-was-i-doing"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Now what was I doing?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK, back to getting my site up and running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So armed with this new information I am back to trying to run
gunicorn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lots of errors from the production config, so I comment out a couple
of sections.  At this point I am not planning on using Amazon's AWS,
so that can all be commented out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I am sure I will need this &lt;em&gt;sendgrid&lt;/em&gt; thing just yet, so that is
getting commented out too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearly there (I think), but gunicorn is still failing due &lt;em&gt;s3boto.py&lt;/em&gt;
being unable to import &lt;em&gt;StringIO&lt;/em&gt;.  Now this looks like a python3
problem, since in python 3, StringIO got moved to io.StringIO :(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK, so boto is an interface to AWS. I am not using that, so this one
is easy to fix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, &lt;em&gt;gunicorn&lt;/em&gt; is running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chrome is doing something weird, it is switching to https and then
hanging with a mysterious &lt;em&gt;establishing secure connection&lt;/em&gt; message.
However, firefox and even chrome from another machine are just fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that's all for today, will finish this off tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/nginx-on-kodingcom.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 19:58:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Rant about computer (in)security</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/rant-about-computer-insecurity.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It seems that the more important something is to computer security the
more byzantine and patchy the documentation will be at explaining how
to make sure your computers actually are secure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is security is difficult. You only have to mess up once
and all bets are off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invarialby, getting stuff up and running involves a lot of hacking
around.  Eventually, you get the thing working, but by then it is
probably too late, even if you go back and plug all the holes And that
assumes you can remember what you did along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the open source world products are generally configured in a
&lt;em&gt;secure&lt;/em&gt; way out of the box.  You have to explicitly switch off things
that are there for your protection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is all well and good, but without excellent documentation
non-expert users (which in fact is every user a project will have: we
are all novices when we start using a new product) are going to have
problems getting the thing working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result is insecurity everywhere.  And that is before we get into
all the backdoors that various organisations have been more than happy
to leave in products for their own purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't have a good solution to this problem, the subject is complex.
What is clear is that the current situation just is not working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="following-industry-standards"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Following industry standards&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To all those company's who are &lt;em&gt;following industry standards&lt;/em&gt; you are
a huge part of the problem.  Those industry standards are horribly
broken, possibly by design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no substitute for hiring someone that actually understands
the subject and listening to their recommendations.  Blindly following
standards that were introduced 30 years ago and which nobody can
remember why they were introduced is lame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might get you off the hook with your boss: we are just doing what
everyone else does, nobody got fired for choosing IBM, etc, etc.  But
the fact is that your security is really dependent on the fact that
there are more attractive targets, such as companies that actually
call themselves &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.target.com/"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt; ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="http://dailyangst.files.wordpress.com/2012/02/birthmark.jpg" src="http://dailyangst.files.wordpress.com/2012/02/birthmark.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an example, every place I have ever worked has a &lt;em&gt;you must change
your password every 90 days&lt;/em&gt; rule.  Really?  This rule was introduced
based on the time it would take a good sized computer to crack a
password given the hashed value that gets stored in password
files... in the 1980's.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea being that if you change every 90 days it will be unlikely
the crackers will crack your password before you change it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NEWSFLASH: to all CIO's out there, computers have got faster
since 1980.  If you really want to protect against crackers that have
your hashed passwords then you probably need all your employees to
change their passwords about every five minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the one good thing that will come out of all the high profile
breaches we are hearing about at the moment is that some of this
archaic nonesense will be replaced by measures that genuinely increase
security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, with the technologies that most companies are dependent on,
the difficulty (or indeed near impossibility) of introducing genuine
security without making it impossible for everyone to do their jobs, I
think we are in for many more breaches in the coming years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, I would wager that there have been lots more very significant
security breaches, we just have not heard about them (yet).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/rant-about-computer-insecurity.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 18:03:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>SWFIUA explained</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/swfiua-explained.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I grew up in Sheffield in the UK.  There are two football teams in
Sheffield:  Sheffield United and Sheffield United reserves.  They play
in red and white stripes and are known as the &lt;em&gt;Mighty Blades&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also another team that goes by the name of Sheffield
Wednesday, also known as &lt;em&gt;The Owls&lt;/em&gt;, or ironically as &lt;em&gt;The Massive&lt;/em&gt;,
the owls or the Pigs.  Curiously, the followers of &lt;em&gt;The Massive&lt;/em&gt; also
refer to followers of the Blades as &lt;em&gt;Pigs&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you grow up in Sheffield you end up following one of the sides.  My
parents grew up within walking distance to Bramall Lane.  They were
both Blades, as were my grand-parents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most families have members in the other camp, so for instance my
sister married an Owl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I now live in Bermuda and here the closest thing to the Blades/Owls
rivalry is the Somerset v St George Cup Match rivalry.  Most
Bermudians don't get to choose who they follow: it is pretty much
decided at birth.  There should probably be a box to tick on Bermudian
birth certificates to specify which side you are going to follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both these rivalries are intense.  There is always lots of banter and
when the two teams meet if your side doesn't win then going in to work
the next day is going to involve some ribbing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Living away from Sheffield means when the Blades lose I at least don't
have to listen to the fowls.  In fact, on the rare occasions when I
meet a Wednesday fan here it is good to meet a fellow Sheffield
exile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now neither the Owls or the Blades have been all that good in my
lifetime.  Both have had spells in the top flight, both have had the
odd cup run here and there, but both have had more dreary 0-0 draws on
a cold damp February afternoon against some other struggling club such
as Grimbsby or Crewe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many afternoons at Beautiful DownTown Bramall Lane (BDTBL) there has
been nothing to cheer apart from maybe a stray dog wandering on to the
pitch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in the day there was no fancy digital scoreboard, just the
letters A-Z with hooks alongside with room for someone to go and hang
up the scores at half time.  If you wanted to know which game was
which you had to buy the program.  But A was always for the Owls game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is more, the Owls score would get updated every time a goal went
in.  When the Blades play at home, the Owls are away.  Since most
seasons they are likely to be struggling the odds are they will lose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when the man wanders out and puts up the score and the crowd sees
that they have let a goal in, the chant would go up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
Sheffield Wednesday Fucked It Up Again
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a good day, you would hear the chant 2-3 times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that is where swfiua comes from.   In short, the loudest cheer at
many a Blades game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it is not all doom and gloom as a Blade.  Last night was yet
another memorable cup tie at BDTBL.  We were drawn at home to
Southampton in the quarter final of the League (Capital One) Cup,
also known as the "whatever it is called this year cup".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time of the draw Southampton were defying gravity and placed
2nd in the Premier League.  Meanwhile the blades were holding their
own in League One, but not exactly scoring goals for fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meanwhile, the football gods have intervened, Southampton's
last few league games have been tough ones and they have lost them
all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All was set for a classic cup upset at BDTBL on a December night in
Sheffield.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a good crowd.  Night games at BDTBL are always special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point it is worth saying a word about &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nigel_Clough"&gt;Sir Nigel Clough&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is difficult to talk about Nigel without mentioning his father,
although I hesitate to do this, it cannot be easy being Brian's son.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brian Clough was an absolute genius of a football manager.  He was
always entertaining in interviews, always had sides that played good
football and his teams always respected referees and won fairly.  Oh,
and Brian always took the cups seriously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nigel Clough has now been in charge for 18 cup ties, all whilst the
Blades have been down in the third tier of UK football.  They have
only lost 2 ties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night was a wonderful win.  They took the game to Southampton.
The longer it went on the more I started to believe they might
actually win.  As a Blade, this is an uncomfortable feeling.  So many
times, just when you think we are going to do something it all
unravels.  The journey is always fun though, but we all know how it
ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well last night was one of those rare occasions when everything went
well.  We got to half time 0-0.  We were the better side first half.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first 10 minutes after half time were going to be key.
Southampton no doubt got a talking to, we had to be ready for them to
come at us.  Southamptin did come out a little stronger, but the
Blades held their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then the unbelievable happended, one of those freaky goals, ball
trickling over the line, with keeper and Sparky McNulty both racing to
get to it.  Sparky won the race and sparked off a fantastic last 30
minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know it will end in tears, but it is nights like this that make it
all worth while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I said to a Chelsea fan (who also had a soft spot for Derby) before
the game, the great thing about following the Blades is if we win two
games on the trot it is like winning the Champion's League.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So on to the semis, looking forward to the draw later today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and those wondering how the Owls did this year in the League Cup:
they lost 7-0 to Man City in the third round.  &lt;strong&gt;swfiua&lt;/strong&gt; * 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>football sufc blades</category><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/swfiua-explained.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 15:13:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Progress report on 80days</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/progress-report-on-80days.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am now 33 days into the project and anyone reading this blog ought
to be wondering how it is actually going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I am enjoying about this project is there is no project
manager.  Well I guess, technically, that is my job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been writing code long enough to see more than my share of
magic bullets that will make everything go smoothly.  Sometimes these
were formal approaches to coding and project management.  Other times
the bullets are coming from the open source community: ways of working
that people have developed for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, the open source stuff speaks for itself.  Nobody is
mandating that the projects work the way they do (actually, in most
cases the BDFL is probably mandating the standards).  But the point is
that the standards are being driven by those that know the job best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around the time Extreme Programming became popular I encountered the
following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
Time, resources, scope and quality:  pick any three
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fix three of these and then you have to let those doing the work tell
you what the fourth will likely be.  I find this to be a very useful
tool.  Letting others set all four is a recipe for failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 80 days project I am fortunate.  Time is set to 80 days, but I
pretty much have control over the other three.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, that is not quite true.  As far as &lt;em&gt;scope&lt;/em&gt; is concerned I
will need to deliver something by February 1st and actually need
somewhere people can register for the competition by January 1st (give
or take a few days).  But overall, the scope will be whatever gets
done in the time available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resources are to some extent under my control.  Right now there is
only me working on the project.  Actually, that is not really true.
There is a whole army of open source heroes working on this project,
they just don't know they are working on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far I really have not written much code.  However, I do have a site
that has a pretty landing page, and about page and you can register
either by setting up &lt;em&gt;yet another user id and password&lt;/em&gt; or by using
your google ID and open auth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't have to write any code bar a tiny bit of html and a fair bit
of configuration of django.  Mostly it has just been a matter of
finding packages, reading how they work, follow the instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To some extent, this whole project is turning into an exercise in how
little code I actually have to write.  Code re-use is working well for
now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="hosting"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hosting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The site is not available in the big bad world as yet, mostly due to
the fact I have not decided where to host it as yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I had a good experience with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/https//koding.com"&gt;koding.com&lt;/a&gt; during the recent
hackathon, that is probably what I will end up using.  The good news
is that I know all the stuff I am using will only take about 30
minutes to get up and running on that platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-is-left-to-do"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is left to do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty much all the details of the site, but this is most of the fun
stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am planning to create a couple of new django apps.  &lt;em&gt;django teams&lt;/em&gt;
will be a simple app to manage teams.  A team is just a set of
competitors, but will have some other attributes such as team size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I might include &lt;em&gt;competitions&lt;/em&gt; in this app, since teams will be busy
entering competitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another app I am thinking about is &lt;em&gt;django routes&lt;/em&gt;.   This is a key
part of the 80 days project: we need a route that we are going to take
around the world.  A route is really just an ordered set of places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the same app ought to be useful for the &lt;em&gt;around Bermuda Bus
in 80 days&lt;/em&gt; idea I keep thinking about.  Buses follow routes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/tomwalker/django_quiz/"&gt;django quiz&lt;/a&gt; project that I am hoping to use to add
quizzes to the competition.  The idea is that each time a team arrives
in a city along the route there will be a little quiz.  Get the
questions right and you will get some free miles en route to the next
city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am betting there is already something out there to help with &lt;em&gt;django
routes&lt;/em&gt;, perhaps I can make use of something written to work with the
transport data format &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://developers.google.com/transit/gtfs/"&gt;GTFS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, I think the project is on target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>80days</category><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/progress-report-on-80days.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 14:08:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Adventures in distro land..</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/adventures-in-distro-land.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We had a friend over the other evening.  I have a home full of half
working tech.  Stuff that really could do something, given enough
time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of my techy stuff has been neglected for a few years, so it is
suffering both bit and hardware rot.  So a good part of last night was
spent exploring why stuff wasn't working, in between finding a few
gems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So today, I had a few things I wanted to look into:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;why wasn't the server with the music on responding,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;installing a fedora iso onto a usb and seeing what it is like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That server with the music; well that thing won't even boot off a USB
key; though you can change a bucket load of things in the BIOS.  And
at one point it did seem like it would boot over the network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next stop, fedora install guide kindly gives the incantation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
dd if=fedora*.iso of=/dev/sdx  (x in my case was b)
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I booted up a laptop (the one with the battery that lasts 30
seconds) off the USB and fedora booted.  I did not have time to have a
good look around, but it seemed snappier and easier to use than the
Ubuntu desktop on the machine, more like the &lt;cite&gt;awesome wm&lt;/cite&gt; experience.
I will definitely take a nother look at this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to the music.  I resurrected an old mythtv box and tried to put
fedora on it.  I couldn't get it to install on the old myth box.  It
may have had something to do with some network issues that were going
on at the time.  Also possible there was some issue with this boxes
USB, it was an old machine, so might have old firmware.  Or the USB
isn't an innocent little USB.  But I digress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I tried arch.  This was like being beamed back to 1997.  It was fun
for a while, but then I typed the wrong thing and lost the internet
connection, which was what I needed to get the software to fix the
internet connection.  I did Ctrl-D out of the &lt;em&gt;chroot&lt;/em&gt; and if I'd been
awake when I booted back into it I might have skipped the second
install.  I gave up at the bootloader bit.  I know, I was nearly there :(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I might have to go back to arch one day when I have lots of time on my
hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So more rabbit holes.  Eventually, led to Debian.  By now the dining
table is buried under cables.  The IP over powerline is up and running
again and 2-3 boxes are in the pile marked broken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Debian install was been a joy, apart from the sporadic (or rather
repeated) interruptions to anything needing internet bandwidth (a
problem anywhere with expensive or unreliable bandwidth).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suspect I am biassed because over the years I have spent more time
with Debian based systems.  First with debian and then indirectly via
Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked Ubuntu primarily for its python packaging.  Ubuntu still is a
fantastic distribution for python.  As an interface for the sort of
programming I like to do it is becoming less responsive, or at least
that is my feeling.  Also, I am feeling myself further removed from
the hardware and the software configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, python packaging has come a long way.  With PyPi and
pip install the linux distro no longer matters so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Debian doesn't seem to have changed much in philosophy.  Most of what
I learnt back in the day still applies.  It led me through the install
with just enough information to make an informed decision about the
questions.  It guided pretty well, hinting which way I should go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of now I am yet to actually get it serving up the music, so this
will most likely not be the last distro related posting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>linux</category><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/adventures-in-distro-land.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 00:19:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Global Hackathon, Team Bermuda</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/global-hackathon-team-bermuda.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last weekend I took part in the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/worlds-first-global-hackathon.html"&gt;global hackathon&lt;/a&gt; run by
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/https//koding.com"&gt;koding.com&lt;/a&gt; as part of Team Bermuda aka &lt;em&gt;Three&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=aceboy"&gt;ace-boys&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;and an&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Acegirl"&gt;ace-girl&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other members of the team were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nick Hoskins, the one who told us all about it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beckett Simmons, residing &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/https//koding.com"&gt;koding.com&lt;/a&gt; expert&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Veronica Windus, working remotely from the frozen wastes of Canada&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea was to create a web based application in 48 hours.  There
were five themes to choose from, we chose:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
No one reads the fine print (ie TOS, EULA, legal documents) anymore
yet every site has them. Devise a creative/interactive solution.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, before we could start we needed a name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the average EULA is about as easy to read as the classic, James
Joyce' &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ulysses_%28novel%29"&gt;Ulysees&lt;/a&gt; we took the liberty of borrowing the name, and then
abusing it and came up with, &lt;em&gt;Eulasees&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a tenuous link with Bermuda in that many songs of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thomas_Moore"&gt;Thomas
Moore&lt;/a&gt; who lived in Bermuda for a while, are cited in the works of
James Joyce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, back to the hackathon.  This nominally started at 4am Bermuda time
on Saturday 6th December.  Team Bermuda hence decided to start work at
10am, gathering at the Watford Sports Club.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, things got off to a slow start due to several factors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;lack of coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, there was coffee, but we only had a tiny bodum to make it
in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;A fellow &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sheffield_United_F.C."&gt;Blade&lt;/a&gt; turned up at the sports club.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, blades are rare as hen's teeth, so progress came to a
complete standstill whilst yours truly reminisced about the good old
days when the Mighty Blades were in the heady heights of the first
division (technically, they are still in the first division, it is
just that now first really means third, English footy uses a weird
number system).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;At least one of us working on a laptop that was missing lots of the
standard development packages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Flaky wifi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;No real idea what we were going to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was very much a &lt;em&gt;make it up as you go along&lt;/em&gt; event.   We talked
about a few ideas, delegated lots of stuff to our ace-girl, who was
presumably still digging out from under a snow storm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rough plan was a to create a restful API with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.djangoproject.com/"&gt;django&lt;/a&gt; and build
an &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://angularjs.org/"&gt;angular.js&lt;/a&gt; front end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea was to load EULA's into the system, allow users to highlight
areas of text and apply &lt;em&gt;tags&lt;/em&gt; to these areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These &lt;em&gt;tags&lt;/em&gt; would have a short name indicating what the contract
clause really meant and a longer text body explaining what it was all
about really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we had this and some data in the system the plan was to create
some views allowing users to see which EULA's had which clauses and
other such fun stuff.  One idea was to add a quiz, getting people to
guess whose EULA had which clause, possibly using &lt;cite&gt;django quiz&lt;/cite&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most of Saturday we pretty much ignored the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/https//koding.com"&gt;koding.com&lt;/a&gt; virtual
machine, we were having enough other problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, the &lt;em&gt;angular&lt;/em&gt; stuff was going quite well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The django side was going a bit slower.  We were using &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://cookiecutter.readthedocs.org/en/latest/"&gt;cookiecutter&lt;/a&gt;
to create all the base files for our django apps and project.  This
works really well, but does come with a lot of extra goodness that we
probably did not need at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;pip install&lt;/em&gt; kept failing on obscure compile errors due to missing
&lt;em&gt;-dev&lt;/em&gt; packages.  I love pip, but with a big requirements list and a
dodgy wifi connection the downloads were taking way too long and I
couldn't get it to cache things reliably.  More on this later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having said that, being able to do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
python setup.py register
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Followed by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
python setup.py publish
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make the django app available on PyPi (and hence &lt;em&gt;pip install&lt;/em&gt;
magic just works), was very cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things went well on the Saturday.   Mid-evening we stopped for food
and more coffee (by now Nick had brought a decent sized bodum down
from his house, so the coffee shortage was averted).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to work until we were too tired, then get some sleep ready
to code until 4am on Monday morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is all a bit of a blur now, but at some point we decided we should
see if any of our stuff actually works on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/https//koding.com"&gt;koding.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sure the koding.com IDE is a joy to use, but now was not the time
to learn it.  Fortunately, Beckett had given us the number one pro-tip
for using koding.com:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Getting ssh to koding working is well worth the effort&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further, it didn't involve anything more than adding an ssh key to the
&lt;em&gt;~/.ssh/.authorized_keys&lt;/em&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suddenly &lt;em&gt;pip install&lt;/em&gt; was flying along.  Clearly, we should have been
doing everything on the koding machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having noted how well the koding VM was working, of course, we
continued to work locally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were, in fact, so effective at this that it was midnight on Sunday
before we decided it would be a good idea if the angular front end
could talk to the django rest API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No prizes for guessing the answer to this: hell no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Angular was either failing completely to connect to the django API
giving obscure messages about &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cross-site_request_forgery"&gt;cross-site request forgery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point we probably should have left the angular front end as an
example of where we were heading and just fed it some toy data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead we learnt way more about csrf's than we ever wanted to know,
in between cursing django for its attentiveness to security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After much thrashing around &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/ottoyiu/django-cors-headers"&gt;django cors&lt;/a&gt; came to the rescue.  By
now, however, it was past 3am and Nick was having to use a new
function to make the restful API calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got the two pieces talking, but ran out of time to fix up enough of
the angular code to get a viable front end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project code is on github, as &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/swfiua/eulasees"&gt;eulasees&lt;/a&gt;, with the the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/swfiua/django_eulasees"&gt;django
eulasees&lt;/a&gt; app in a separate repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also view the docs for the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://swfiua.koding.io:8000/docs/"&gt;eulasees API&lt;/a&gt; that was created.
These are created with the amazing &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/marcgibbons/django-rest-swagger"&gt;django rest swagger&lt;/a&gt; and allow
you to try out the API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did manage to load some data into the system, with the django admin
system coming to the rescue as the user interface of last resort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should probably apologise to google, since their &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/terms/"&gt;terms of
service&lt;/a&gt; was the toy example we decided to use.  You can actually get
all the data that we entered with this &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://swfiua.koding.io:8000/eulasees/everythingforeula/4/"&gt;one API call&lt;/a&gt;.  So, if there
are any google lawyers reading: we love you really, we know you are
not &lt;em&gt;evil&lt;/em&gt;.  Just one question: what is with the paragraphs IN ALL
CAPS?  ARE WE BACK IN THE 90's ON A SHOUTY FORUM?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remarkably, we got an email yesterday informing us we made it through
to the next round of the competition.  We can only assume that pretty
much everyone that got any sort of site up got through the first
round.  You can even &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hackathon.koding.com/entries/team-bermuda"&gt;VOTE FOR US&lt;/a&gt; :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>hackathon</category><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/global-hackathon-team-bermuda.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2014 22:37:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Using gnus for Gmail</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/using-gnus-for-gmail.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;My primary email account is with Gmail.  Overall it works pretty
well.  In particular, it works well on the phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I have been finding email less and less effective as a
communication medium of late, for a number of reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;There is too much clutter there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not really spam, but over the years too many organisations have got
my email address.  Sometimes this is good: booking flights or hotels
or whatever, the emails they send are useful, but then they send a
bundle of spam and special offers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Some key contacts don't really use email.  Not naming names, but
the younger you are the less likely it is that email will be your
default way to communicate electronically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;The Gmail interface in chrome is a resource hog.  Further it does
not make good use of the real estate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;The editor for writing emails is ok, but rather limited&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Some simple things are hard/impossible to do.  For example,
sometimes I am working on a draft and want to share the draft with
someone else, leaving the draft in the drafts folder.  No can do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;I started using the amazing &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://vimium.github.io/"&gt;vimium&lt;/a&gt; plugin in Chrome.  For Gmail
to work you have to switch off Vimium, but then you are left with
tabs where the Vimium shortcuts don't work.  So, I think it is best
to read email elsewhere.  I tried a browser window just for email,
but I end up opening new tabs, so that quickly fails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many years back I used to use RMAIL in emacs.  It was a powerful
client and I am left with my favourite editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, asking google for &lt;em&gt;emacs email client&lt;/em&gt; the answer that comes back
is gnus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.emacswiki.org/emacs/GnusGmail"&gt;quickstart&lt;/a&gt; on EmacsWiki was enough to get me as far as seeing
my gmail in emacs.  I even managed to read a few emails and may have
replied to one or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have dabbled in gnus before, but it seems to have taken on a whole
new life since then.  I suspect a large part of the rest of this week,
or maybe this month is going to go on figuring out how it all works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far though, I am liking it, so it is a good start.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/using-gnus-for-gmail.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 22:17:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>More on django-allauth</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/more-on-django-allauth.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Armed with the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.sarahhagstrom.com/2013/09/the-missing-django-allauth-tutorial/"&gt;missing django-allauth tutorial&lt;/a&gt; I have made some
progress getting auth working with &lt;em&gt;google&lt;/em&gt; doing as the
authentication provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sarah's guide pretty much covered everything I needed to know.  It
also encouraged me to work towards pushing out a bare-bones &lt;strong&gt;80
days&lt;/strong&gt; site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This actually makes sense as I don't need the whole site up and
running just for users to register for the competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The missing tutorial uses &lt;em&gt;facebook&lt;/em&gt; as the example.  Unfortunately, I
could not figure out how to register my application and get the
necessary keys on facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, I decided to have a go at using &lt;em&gt;google&lt;/em&gt;.   I quickly found
this &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://developers.google.com/+/quickstart/python"&gt;google guide&lt;/a&gt; which was enough to get my application registered
and get the necessary keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then it was back to the missing manual.   I actually used the &lt;em&gt;django
admin&lt;/em&gt; interface to update the django database, rather than run the
SQL as per the tutorial.  This was just a matter of going to this url:
&lt;em&gt;http://127.0.0.1:8000/admin/socialaccount/socialapp/&lt;/em&gt; and entering a
new record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still had a couple of errors to get by.  First, I copy/pasted the
configuration information from the missint tutorial and had to remove
the &lt;em&gt;publish_stream&lt;/em&gt; scope as google does not support that (at least I
assume that is what the problem is).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next I had to go back to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://console.developers.google.com"&gt;Google Developer Console&lt;/a&gt; and register
the callback url that my application was trying to use.  Bingo,
everything works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, with this setup, new users can just sign in with their google
account and the application will set up a user registration for them
if one does not already exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The down side with all this is that there are a plethora of
authentication providers I should probably support:  facebook,
twitter, yahoom, linkedIn, github, etc, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really, this whole system is horribly broken.  Every social media site
has its own identity management implementation and it, naturally,
wants everyone to use their identity management.   In short, they all
want to own your identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we really need is for users to be able to manage their own
identity, without need to for a central authority.  The central
authority is a critical security weakness as if that authority is
compromised all users using that authority are compromised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A secondary problem is that the current OAuth/OpenID solutions result
in everybody wanting to be the central authority and hence users are
faced with either balkanisation of identiy management or having to
manage multiple identities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, I do not see an end to this in the short term, not least
because the current mess suits all the current incumbents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/more-on-django-allauth.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 20:34:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bootstrap css, allauth and initial site</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/bootstrap-css-allauth-and-initial-site.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Write your post here.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/bootstrap-css-allauth-and-initial-site.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 18:05:42 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>