<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Around the world in 80 days (2015)</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/categories/2015.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 14:40:07 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Fred Update</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/fred-update.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fred formed way in the east of the Atlantic.  I believe it was already
a hurricane going over the Cape Verde islands.  I was shown pictures
today of seas damaging a pier.  I have not heard too much more about
damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Six years ago, Fred formed around the same area a little further
south, but did not intensify as fast.  It did become a hurricane, then
dissipated as it curled, for a short while was heading easterly, then
got pushed back westward.  By this time it had fallen apart and it
did not get organised again, but the remnants of the storm tracked a
good way across the Atlantic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the discussion of Fred, it is likely to be pulled apart in
the short term.  Then the track forecasts give a range of
possibilities, including heading westward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Latest (5AM AST, 1st September) forecast discussion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.nhc.noaa.gov/text/refresh/MIATCDAT1+shtml/010849.shtml"&gt;http://www.nhc.noaa.gov/text/refresh/MIATCDAT1+shtml/010849.shtml&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These discussions tend to be very helpful in gauging how much
confidence the forecasters about the forecasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, both track and intensity forecasts can be pretty accurate
out to 24 hours or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paragraph from the discussion has a lot of information in it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Fred is expected to move between west-northwest and northwest for
the next 72 hours as a mid-level ridge to the north of the cyclone
gradually builds westward. After that time, a turn toward the
north-northwest and north is forecast due to a deep-layer trough
currently over eastern Canada that is expected to dig
southeastward over the central Atlantic and erode the ridge. The
NHC model guidance is in decent agreement on this developing
pattern change.  However, there are significant differences in the
model solutions with the HWRF, GFS, and GFDL models keeping Fred
stronger and making the northward turn sooner, whereas the weaker
solution models like the UKMET and ECMWF take a weaker and more
vertically shallow cyclone farther west before turning it
northward.  The official forecast track is a little south of the
previous advisory track, mainly due to the more southerly initial
position, and follows a blend of the weaker UKMET and ECMWF
solutions.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end, we learn the current forecast track is further south than
the previous advisory.  The discussion notes this is mostly because
Fred did not move as far north as expected over the previous period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disagreements in models are usually informative, often indicating
there is more uncertainty in the forecast.  Sometimes the forecasters
have good understanding of why the models are disagreeing, different
models have different strengths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="bermuda-weather"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bermuda Weather&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://weather.bm/images/surfaceAnalysis/Latest/Atlantic.gif"&gt;http://weather.bm/images/surfaceAnalysis/Latest/Atlantic.gif&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="wikipedia"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hurricane_Fred_%282015%29"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hurricane_Fred_%282015%29&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hurricane_Fred_%282009%29"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hurricane_Fred_%282009%29&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="national-hurricane-centre"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;National Hurricane Centre&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://weather.bm/images/surfaceAnalysis/Latest/Atlantic.gif"&gt;http://weather.bm/images/surfaceAnalysis/Latest/Atlantic.gif&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014</category><category>2015</category><category>fred</category><category>hurricane</category><category>weather</category><guid>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/fred-update.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:41:56 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>