<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Around the world in 80 days (bermuda)</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/categories/bermuda.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 16:07:38 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Where's de bus</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/wheres-de-bus.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year's TLF students are considering creating an application to
give Bermuda's public transport users up to date information on where
the buses and ferries actually are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transit authorities that have made this data available have found a
number of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.actsoft.com/public-transportation-profits-from-gps-tracking/"&gt;benefits&lt;/a&gt; of bus tracking, including increased usage of
public transport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a thriving open source project, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://onebusaway.org/"&gt;One Bus Away&lt;/a&gt; which looks
like it could be used in the Bermuda environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A first step in getting the transport data into the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://developers.google.com/transit/gtfs/reference"&gt;General Transit
Feed Specification&lt;/a&gt; (GTFS) format.  This provides a flexible format
for transit data.  It is how you specify bus stop locations, routes
and timetables.  Once you have your data in this format there are a
number of projects that you can use to create a powerful transit
application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://onebusaway.org/"&gt;One Bus Away&lt;/a&gt; project is an open source project that is being
used in a number of US and Canadian cities.  It should be usable here
in Bermuda too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google provides good support for transit information and the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.dutchnews.nl/news/archives/2015/06/the-netherlands-debuts-new-google-public-transport-service/"&gt;Netherlands&lt;/a&gt; recently became the first country in the world to
provide full information via their service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst this support from Google is good to have, since many tourists
will be using google maps whilst visiting the island, there are
benefits to being in control of your own data and websites.  There are
restrictions on the use of Google maps and you are not in control of
future development when you use that platform.  Further, users may not
wish to share their location with Google due to privacy concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.openstreetmap.org/search?query=bermuda#map=12/32.2949/-64.7830"&gt;OpenStreetMap&lt;/a&gt; is an free and open project to make top quality
digital maps available.  The Bermuda map is quite excellent.  Further,
there is a good open source javascript library, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://leafletjs.com/"&gt;leaflet&lt;/a&gt; to create
interactive maps using OpenStreetMap data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few months back Open Bermuda started work on a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/openbermuda/wheres-de-bus"&gt;Where's de bus&lt;/a&gt;
project during a hackathon.  The challenge at that time was finding
out where the actual bus stops were.  It is hoped that it will be
possible to get this information and full bus and ferry timetables in
machine readable form from the Bermuda Transportation Board (BTB).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the small size of Bermuda and its transit network it would also
be possible to crowd-source the data for a transit application.  If
live GPS data is not avaialable from BTB an alternative would be to
create a mobile application that public transport users could run and
use to report bus locations as well as how full the bus currently is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are already some open source GPS tracking systems available such
as &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.opengts.org/"&gt;OpenGTS&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.traccar.org/"&gt;Traccar&lt;/a&gt; that might be usable here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bermuda</category><category>bus</category><category>ferry</category><category>open source</category><category>transit</category><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/wheres-de-bus.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 14:14:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Sharon Wilson</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/sharon-wilson.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you visit Bermuda you will likely end up at Horseshoe Bay at some
point during your trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of the biggest and busiest of the South Shore beaches.
Whenever there is a long weekend things will be happening on Horseshoe
Bay, such as the annual Good Friday flying of kites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Horseshoe Bay you can walk along the coast, past a number of
smaller and quieter beaches and coves.  Often you will be able to find
a beach to yourself, with pink sands, turquoise water and tropical
fish swimming around the reefs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the top of the driveway that leads down to Horseshoe Bay you will
find Southampton Rangers football and cricket club.  On the weekend
you might be able to watch some cricket and get some refreshment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also a restaurant, Gulf Stream where you can get a bite to
eat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Less than a couple of hundred yards to the west you will find a small
side-road, Turtle Place.  This is where local artist Sharon Wilson
lives.  Her home is also her studio and her gallery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If she is open for visitors she usually puts out a &lt;em&gt;sandwich board&lt;/em&gt; at
the end of the road, sometimes with a couple of balloons attached.  In
that case, you are in luck.  She will welcome you to her home and let
you discover her art.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>art</category><category>bermuda</category><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/sharon-wilson.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2015 15:40:38 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>