<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Around the world in 80 days (bermuda music awesome)</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/</link><description></description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" rel="self" href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/categories/bermuda-music-awesome.xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 14:39:47 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The Music from UNCLE</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/the-music-from-uncle.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am lucky enough to live in a wonderful part of the world.  &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vbVyE6hZjCU"&gt;Bermuda
is another world&lt;/a&gt;.  It really is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A tiny island of just 60,000 people, a place with a complex history.
There are a lot of wonderful people here.  There are also some cool
things starting to happen here such as &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://code441.com"&gt;code441&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://wearebermuda.com/"&gt;wearebermuda&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is Christmas time.  The last Saturday before Christmas and there
are parties everywhere.  Many of them are company parties.  You know
the thing, you sort of have to go along.  With luck you'll get to sit
with some of the people at work you actually like.  As the night goes
on, if you are lucky, you will find some like-minded people to spend
time with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, no office party for me.  So, we went to a local bar.  There
is a DJ every Saturday night at this place.  The dance floor is always
packed, for a simple reason: he knows his crowd.  And he always walks
around before he starts, plans his work and works his plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night there must have been 60 cars parked in the area.  The place
was packed.  Everyone was having a good time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now only in Bermuda could a DJ start the evening with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wDC7NeVfc30"&gt;My God is
Awesome&lt;/a&gt;, follow it up with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9T4WB2zfmps"&gt;Silent Night&lt;/a&gt; and already have his
audience tapping their feet and getting into the mood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd never heard &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wDC7NeVfc30"&gt;My God is Awesome&lt;/a&gt; before.  Actually, I am sure I
must of heard it, just hadn't really listend.  And I only really
listened this time because it reminded me of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://awesome.naquadah.org/"&gt;Awesome window
manager&lt;/a&gt;  I've been using awesome the last few weeks and it has had a
huge impact on the way I use my computer.   And I am only scratching
the surface of what it can do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this was followed up with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xlVxEAUqWU0"&gt;You can't hurry love&lt;/a&gt;, an old version
by the Supremes.  Another special song for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there was &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vdB-8eLEW8g"&gt;One Love&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JFMtBibwrgY"&gt;Electric Slide&lt;/a&gt;, complete with line
dancing.  Bermudian line dancing has to be seen to be appreciated.
Last night was typical.  A mixture of regulars to the place and those
just there for the party.  Everyone having a good time
together. There were a lot of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y6Sxv-sUYtM"&gt;Happy&lt;/a&gt; people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My music tastes are a bit weird.  I pretty much follow the crowd.  And
my guitar music.  I have been (very slowly) learning to play over the
past few years.  I have a few books with tabs, most of them have the
word &lt;em&gt;easy&lt;/em&gt; in their titles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would pick a song and try the patience of those around me by playing
it over and over again, badly.  I would look at the tabs of some and
think, no way I can play that.  But now I am starting to get a little
better and a little more adventurous.  I am noticing songs that have
been there for years ready for me to play.  Song of the moment is the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YZo88P1Ie94"&gt;The Joker&lt;/a&gt;.  Like all good songs, there is lots of scope for
changing the lyrics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
I'm a picker,
I'm a grinder,
I'm a lover,
I'm a sinner,
I play my music in the sun
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grinder not grinner, in tribute to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pTXjp2bf1vo"&gt;Sheffield Grinder&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And seeing as I have a bit of a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://git-scm.com/"&gt;git&lt;/a&gt; obsession:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
I'm a puller,
I'm a merger,
I'm a midnight coder,
I get my checkouts from github.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks Uncle, old stuff still works.  Sometimes it works way better
than the new stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bermuda music awesome</category><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/the-music-from-uncle.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 20:01:33 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>