<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Around the world in 80 days (bermuda)</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/</link><description></description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" rel="self" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/categories/bermuda.xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 18:46:46 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Magic Roundabouts and Geese</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/magic-roundabouts-and-geese.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Growing up as children we would watch The Magic Roundabout on the BBC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a five minute children's program with a carousel, Zebedee,
Dougal the dog and Dylan the rabbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each episode ended with Zebedee saying, "Time for bed", before
springing off, literally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we got older we might watch a bit of the news that followed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="roundabouts-around-the-world"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Roundabouts around the world&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around the world, traffic rules vary quite a bit.  Here are some
examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="france"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;France&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In France roundabouts used to be much less common than in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The early traffic rule was essentially, "priorite a la droite".  This
rule dated back to horses and carriages and mostly they could see each
other coming for a good way, it was simple to slow down and give way
to those from one side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another key rule, is which side of the road to drive on.  The French,
like most of continental Europe, drive on the right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looked at from above, the French go anti-clockwise around
roundabouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when they arrive at one, those already on the roundabout give way
to new arrivals, coming from the right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This works well with light traffic.  With heavy draffic, things can
fall apart: once the roundabout is full of cars nobody can go
anywhere, although if you are just taking the first right then you'll
probably be ok.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="arc-de-triomphe"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Arc de Triomphe&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now this is more like The Magic Roundabout.  I have no idea what the
rules are.   Rumour has it that insurance companies exclude any
accident that happens here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="british-isles"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;British Isles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here they drive on the left and go clockwise round roundabouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give way to those already on the roundabout.  Those already on can
keep going, those arriving have to wait for it to be safe to enter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, like the French you are giving way to those on the right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, it can work well it depends on the traffic volume and pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="swindon"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Swindon&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swindon actually has a Magic Roundabout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a crazy construction of five roundabouts with another roundabout
inside them all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UK rules apply, so once you get on the thing it is like a
roller-coaster, just go with the flow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the accidents happen, people are usually moving pretty slowly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="north-america"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;North America&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roundabouts used to be far less common in North America.  Four-way
stops are the order of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You arrive at the junction and stop.  If no-one else is there then you
can proceed, others arriving after you should give way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now this can lead to the &lt;em&gt;Canadian stand-off&lt;/em&gt;.   You arrive at a
roundabout just as someone else arrives.  There then follows an
elaborate dance where you both just sit there waiting for the other to
go first, often accompanied by hand-gestures.   Dead-lock is not
uncommon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="ottawa"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Ottawa&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a roundabout near the Experimental Farm that itself seems to
be a wonderful experiment in mixing British and French roundabout
rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in the day it was probably a four way stop, a simple cross-roads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's pretend there is a north-south (NS) road crossing east-west (EW)
and the NS is the bigger road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are travelling NS or SN, you can pretent your are French and
drive straight on to the roundabout.  Those coming from an EW
direction will give way to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are turning left, then you will have to give way to traffic
entering on the NS road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now if you arrive on the EW road you have to give way to traffic
already on the roundabout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is a complicated mixture of giving way to the left or right
depending on where you are on the roundabout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="going-backwards-round-the-magic-roundabout"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Going backwards round the magic roundabout&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* please don't try this *&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traffic arriving from east (or west) could do a Pierre Trudeau, behind
the Queen pirouette, turning 180 degrees to enter the roundabout
backwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this way, the &lt;em&gt;give way to traffic on your right&lt;/em&gt; rule ensures the
traffic that you need to giver way to is always coming from your right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once on the roundabout another pirouette should be done, having done
this, again give way to traffic entering from the North/South road,
which is again on your right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also ensures if you exit on this route you are facing the right
way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If continuing around the roundabout, another pirouette should be
performed after passing the north/south road.  Hence, you will again
be going backwards on the magic roundabout.   With your right side to
the centre of the roundabout there is no need to give way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was much younger my mother one night announced she felt a
little typsy.  As a curious child I asked what that was like.  She
said, "it is like I am going backwards on the magic roundabout".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like I said, don't try this on the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="johnny-barnes"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Johnny Barnes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Hamilton, Bermuda there are several roundabouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there is one special one.  It is known as The Johnny Barnes
roundabout and has its own magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is indeed magic.  Every weekday, between 5am and 10am you will see
Johnny Barnes.  He has been waving to traffic and dispensing love
at the roundabout since retiring from the Bus company.  He is now in
his 90's.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bermuda has its own road rules.  Mostly following the British.  But
the horn only really gets used to say &lt;em&gt;hi&lt;/em&gt; to friends and cousins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you see a friend trying to get out of a small side road you might
well follow the "priorite a la droite" rule and wave for them to go
ahead of you, even though you have right of way.  The roads are
narrow, the speed limit is 20 mph and a little give and take makes it
a better place for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if you are new to the island, watch out for vehicles stopping to let
people out of tiny driveways and side roads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-about-the-geese"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What about the geese?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week the Mighty Blades played Swindon.  Those brave fans that
made the journey down to Swindon went there knowing they would have to
negotiate the Magic Roundabout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being Blades fans, they were probably expecting the worst and a heavy
defeat.  I believe all the fans got through the roundabout unscathed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the game, well the new manager, Nigel Adkins, played a
motivational video before the game.  Google "geese sufc" and you
should find it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It explains how geese are able to travel 70% further by flying in a V
formation.  How one goose will lead and when tired drop back into the
formation and let another take the lead.d&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a goose is tiring and struggling, two other strong geese will drop
down to the ocean with the struggler and stay with it until it either
dies or makes a recovery.  They will then fly together to rejoin the
flock, or tag onto another flock following behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="magic-roundabouts-and-mother-geese"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Magic Roundabouts and Mother Geese&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was younger, my mum was my Magic Roundabout.  She would watch
the world circling around her and find ways to change the paths of
those that needed to be on a different path, or gently put together
those that would benefit from each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I now have another Magic Roundabout in my life.  Mum's are magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bermuda</category><category>blades</category><category>france</category><category>ottawa</category><category>roundabouts</category><category>sufc</category><category>swindon</category><guid>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/magic-roundabouts-and-geese.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 14:54:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>D Bermuda Pi</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div tabindex="-1" id="notebook" class="border-box-sizing"&gt;
    &lt;div class="container" id="notebook-container"&gt;

&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Bermuda-Pi"&gt;Bermuda Pi&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Bermuda-Pi"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
$$\Delta \; B\epsilon\rho\mu\delta\alpha \; \Pi$$$$Number \; -e^{i\pi}$$
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The week 10th to 18th October 2015 there is a lot happening in Bermuda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;TEDx Bermuda on 10th October&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;America's Cup racing 16th-18th October&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first anniversary of hurricanes Fay and Gonzalo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This creates a good opportunity to run a number of small events around
&lt;a href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html"&gt;Free Software&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html"&gt;Free Culture&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Science, Technology, Engineering and Mathematics &lt;a href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html"&gt;STEM&lt;/a&gt; is already
getting a lot of attention.  This is natural in a world where there is
so much innovation and change in current times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout my life technological change has created a lot of wonderful
things.  At the same time, humanity and social systems are struggling
to keep pace with this change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html"&gt;STEAM&lt;/a&gt; adds the Arts into STEM.  Making the Bermuda $\pi$ a STEAM
powered event seems a natural choice, as the event can then embrace
Bermudian culture in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, a hurricane can be viewed as a giant steam engine.
Bermuda once ran a steam powered island.  How about bringing this to
the 21st century:  &lt;em&gt;D Bermuda $\pi$, STEAM powered&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id="Free-Culture"&gt;Free Culture&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Free-Culture"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;People in the free software movement have been dealing with this
change for some time.  They have developed ways of working with
technology that not only scale, but also enable people to build
systems that evolve naturally over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a more general Free Culture movement, publishing artistic
material under &lt;a href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html"&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/a&gt; licenses that mirror the free
software licenses.  Generally, these licenses allow others to build on
the ideas and use them in their own work, usually with attribution.
Some licenses do not permit commercial use, but many do.  Authors
choose a license based on their own values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id="Weather-and-hurricanes"&gt;Weather and hurricanes&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Weather-and-hurricanes"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given the connection with Fay and Gonzalo some events would focus on
hurricane research in the Bermuda context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Event-Ideas"&gt;Event Ideas&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Event-Ideas"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id="A-Pi-conference"&gt;A Pi conference&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#A-Pi-conference"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raspberry Pi's&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weather data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hurricane simulation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Damage surveys and damage estimation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Impact of climate change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lightning talks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;python and pi's in Bermuda education&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aim for most presentations to be about activities that are going on
already in Bermuda, with some visions for future projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invite others from overseas that are doing similar work.  Better
still, people we are already collaborating with on Bermuda projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focus on the Bermuda context: why is what you are doing a good fit for
Bermuda, how can it fit better?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h4 id="Music,-Art"&gt;Music, Art&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Music,-Art"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Allow local musicians and artists to work and play together.  Work on
making local artists work freely available on line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work on ways technology can complement the arts and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="Story-Telling"&gt;Story Telling&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Story-Telling"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have people tell their hurricane stories about last year's storms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Structure in a way that the stories might inspire new ideas to gather
data and do research based on data from previous storms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A 5km run over a 3.14 ($\pi$) mile course.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pies to eat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Education, teaching students using raspberry pi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ideas here are very much inspired by the way &lt;a href="https://us.pycon.org"&gt;python conferences are run&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim is to have a number of small events, that together make up the &lt;code&gt;Bermuda Pi&lt;/code&gt; experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Food and sustainable agriculture&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="Local-Bermuda-food"&gt;Local Bermuda food&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Local-Bermuda-food"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;h4 id="How-to-do-sustainable-agriculture"&gt;How to do sustainable agriculture&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#How-to-do-sustainable-agriculture"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Leisure-activities"&gt;Leisure activities&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Leisure-activities"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fay and Gonzalo parties would seem a good starter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music, story-telling, Bermudian food,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gombeys!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 5km run over a 3.14 ($\pi$) mile course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pies to eat!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Weather"&gt;Weather&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Weather"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Any event during hurricane season has to pay attention to the weather.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that one theme of &lt;code&gt;D Bermuda Pi&lt;/code&gt; will be hurricane research it
would be unfortunate if the event were hit by a hurricane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having said that, it would give the researchers valuable first hand experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One project to work on during the week would be getting better
estimates of the probability of the event being hit by bad weather.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use long term climate features such as El Nino, the North Atlantic
Oscillation, and the Bermuda High to help with contingency planning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Develop tools that can help with future event planning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Study detailed windfields around the island to better understand the
challenges faced by the sailors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Study tides and currents around the island&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html"&gt;Murphy's Law&lt;/a&gt; is likely to intervene here, so in the meanwhile it
would be good if we kept an eye on the long range hurricane forecasts
and nearer the time be in a position to work with Bermuda Weather and
have plans in place in the event of bad weather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Sustainablility-and-environmental-impact"&gt;Sustainablility and environmental impact&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Sustainablility-and-environmental-impact"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Renewable-Energy"&gt;Renewable Energy&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Renewable-Energy"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Information-security-and-privacy"&gt;Information security and privacy&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Information-security-and-privacy"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Cryptocurrencies,-Bitcoin"&gt;Cryptocurrencies, Bitcoin&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Cryptocurrencies,-Bitcoin"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Bermuda-Based-Organisations"&gt;Bermuda Based Organisations&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Bermuda-Based-Organisations"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BIOS station&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bermuda Weather&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BEST -- sustainablility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;code441&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;codtuna&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pecha Kucha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chewstick&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Others?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Coding-Sprint"&gt;Coding Sprint&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Coding-Sprint"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Work on free software projects for a better Bermuda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Reinsurance"&gt;Reinsurance&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Reinsurance"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many of the reinsurers are using free software and the python language in particular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be possible to have a &lt;em&gt;free software in finance&lt;/em&gt; track,
perhaps along the lines of the PyData conferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Visitors"&gt;Visitors&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Visitors"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free software practitioners and enthusiasts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python Foundation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RedHat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Canonical/Ubuntu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Environmentalists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meteorologists and climate researchers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Venues"&gt;Venues&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Venues"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This will very much depend on the level of interest&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Southampton Princess conference hall, used for TEDx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BIOS station&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BIOS station is close to the airport and close to Paget Island (see below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h4 id="Paget-Island"&gt;Paget Island&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Paget-Island"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paget Island is one of a number of Government run islands.  It has
basic facilities.  It would make an excellent venue for a coding
sprint focussing on the environment and sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bermuda is an expensive place to visit, some free sofware enthusiasts
would be more than happy to come and camp on the island.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One goal would be to make this as inclusive an event as possible,
hence creating many different activities that will appeal to different
demographics, but also to find ways to mix those people and give them
new experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The buildings and infrastructure on Paget Island are in need of some
TLC.  It would be good to work towards building a place run on
renewable energy, environmentally positive where people can come to
study how we are doing things in Bermuda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The philosophy of a camp on the island would be to leave the place
better than it is found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h4 id="Chewstick"&gt;Chewstick&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Chewstick"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h4 id="Everywhere!"&gt;Everywhere!&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Everywhere!"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Trivia"&gt;Trivia&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Trivia"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h4 id="Around-the-world-in-80-days"&gt;Around the world in 80 days&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Around-the-world-in-80-days"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;This blog started as a blog for an idea to create an *Around the world
in 80 days* idea, to run little competitions where people get miles
(or kilometers) for activities.  The idea is to see how far round the
world you can get in 80 days, with fun twists along the way.
One idea was to do an &lt;em&gt;Around Bermuda on Bermuda Bus and Ferry&lt;/em&gt;
competition.  I learnt a lot on the project, but never quite got it
out of the door.  But that is another story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a version still limping along on heroku: &lt;a href="https://tonzone80days.herokuapp.com/"&gt;https://tonzone80days.herokuapp.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kudos to heroku.  I have a half build project running there, haven't
checked it in ages and boom it springs into life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some other pieces coming together that might make the bus
thing viable in the near future, just needs a bit of time applied to
it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that I found useful in the project was thinking in an 80 day
time horizon.  So I was curious about what date is 80 days before 10th
October 2015, the date for the start of the Bermuda $\pi$.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hitting &lt;em&gt;Home&lt;/em&gt; on the &lt;a href="https://tonzone80days.herokuapp.com/"&gt;https://tonzone80days.herokuapp.com/&lt;/a&gt; shows me this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jun 29, 2015 is today's date&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sep 17, 2015 is 80 days from today&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apr 10, 2015 was 80 days ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So time for a little python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing code_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="input"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;In [6]:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
    &lt;div class="input_area"&gt;
&lt;div class=" highlight hl-ipython3"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="c"&gt;# lets see what python says&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;datetime&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;bermuda_pi_start&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;datetime&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;date&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;2015&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;eighty_days_before_start&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;bermuda_pi_start&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;datetime&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;timedelta&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;days&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;80&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="nb"&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;eighty_days_before_start&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="output_wrapper"&gt;
&lt;div class="output"&gt;


&lt;div class="output_area"&gt;&lt;div class="prompt"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="output_subarea output_stream output_stdout output_text"&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;2015-07-22
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing code_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="input"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;In [ ]:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
    &lt;div class="input_area"&gt;
&lt;div class=" highlight hl-ipython3"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;So&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;things&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;need&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;get&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;started&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;on&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;July&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;22&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;nd&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;2015&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
$$2015^{{10}^2}$$
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h4 id="What's-this-*Number-$-e^{i\pi}$-thing-about?"&gt;What's this *Number $-e^{i\pi}$ thing about?&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#What's-this-*Number-%24-e%5E%7Bi%5Cpi%7D%24-thing-about?"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a wonderful equation in mathematics that links some of the key
constants from the world of mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is $\pi$, the ratio between a circle's diameter and its
circumference. $\pi$ turns up all the time in mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there is &lt;em&gt;e&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both $\pi$ and $e$ are transcendental, a special type of number,
although there are an infinite number of transendental numbers, when
they turn up in mathematics they tend to be important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there is 1.  The special number that you can multiply any other
number by and leave it unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there is 0.  The special number you can add to anything and leave it unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The equation is known as &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Euler%27s_identity"&gt;Euler's identity&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
$$ e^{i\pi} + 1 = 0 $$&lt;p&gt;As this would be the first Bermuda $\pi$ it would:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Bermuda-$\pi$-Number-1-=-$-e^{i\pi}$"&gt;Bermuda $\pi$ Number 1 = $-e^{i\pi}$&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html#Bermuda-%24%5Cpi%24-Number-1-=-%24-e%5E%7Bi%5Cpi%7D%24"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let's make it number one, every year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
</description><category>bermuda</category><category>chewstick</category><category>education</category><category>python</category><category>raspberry pi</category><guid>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/d-bermuda-pi.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 21:12:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Where's de bus</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/wheres-de-bus.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year's TLF students are considering creating an application to
give Bermuda's public transport users up to date information on where
the buses and ferries actually are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transit authorities that have made this data available have found a
number of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.actsoft.com/public-transportation-profits-from-gps-tracking/"&gt;benefits&lt;/a&gt; of bus tracking, including increased usage of
public transport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a thriving open source project, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://onebusaway.org/"&gt;One Bus Away&lt;/a&gt; which looks
like it could be used in the Bermuda environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A first step in getting the transport data into the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://developers.google.com/transit/gtfs/reference"&gt;General Transit
Feed Specification&lt;/a&gt; (GTFS) format.  This provides a flexible format
for transit data.  It is how you specify bus stop locations, routes
and timetables.  Once you have your data in this format there are a
number of projects that you can use to create a powerful transit
application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://onebusaway.org/"&gt;One Bus Away&lt;/a&gt; project is an open source project that is being
used in a number of US and Canadian cities.  It should be usable here
in Bermuda too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google provides good support for transit information and the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.dutchnews.nl/news/archives/2015/06/the-netherlands-debuts-new-google-public-transport-service/"&gt;Netherlands&lt;/a&gt; recently became the first country in the world to
provide full information via their service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst this support from Google is good to have, since many tourists
will be using google maps whilst visiting the island, there are
benefits to being in control of your own data and websites.  There are
restrictions on the use of Google maps and you are not in control of
future development when you use that platform.  Further, users may not
wish to share their location with Google due to privacy concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.openstreetmap.org/search?query=bermuda#map=12/32.2949/-64.7830"&gt;OpenStreetMap&lt;/a&gt; is an free and open project to make top quality
digital maps available.  The Bermuda map is quite excellent.  Further,
there is a good open source javascript library, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://leafletjs.com/"&gt;leaflet&lt;/a&gt; to create
interactive maps using OpenStreetMap data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few months back Open Bermuda started work on a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/openbermuda/wheres-de-bus"&gt;Where's de bus&lt;/a&gt;
project during a hackathon.  The challenge at that time was finding
out where the actual bus stops were.  It is hoped that it will be
possible to get this information and full bus and ferry timetables in
machine readable form from the Bermuda Transportation Board (BTB).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the small size of Bermuda and its transit network it would also
be possible to crowd-source the data for a transit application.  If
live GPS data is not avaialable from BTB an alternative would be to
create a mobile application that public transport users could run and
use to report bus locations as well as how full the bus currently is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are already some open source GPS tracking systems available such
as &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.opengts.org/"&gt;OpenGTS&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.traccar.org/"&gt;Traccar&lt;/a&gt; that might be usable here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bermuda</category><category>bus</category><category>ferry</category><category>open source</category><category>transit</category><guid>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/wheres-de-bus.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 14:14:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Sharon Wilson</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/sharon-wilson.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you visit Bermuda you will likely end up at Horseshoe Bay at some
point during your trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of the biggest and busiest of the South Shore beaches.
Whenever there is a long weekend things will be happening on Horseshoe
Bay, such as the annual Good Friday flying of kites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Horseshoe Bay you can walk along the coast, past a number of
smaller and quieter beaches and coves.  Often you will be able to find
a beach to yourself, with pink sands, turquoise water and tropical
fish swimming around the reefs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the top of the driveway that leads down to Horseshoe Bay you will
find Southampton Rangers football and cricket club.  On the weekend
you might be able to watch some cricket and get some refreshment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also a restaurant, Gulf Stream where you can get a bite to
eat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Less than a couple of hundred yards to the west you will find a small
side-road, Turtle Place.  This is where local artist Sharon Wilson
lives.  Her home is also her studio and her gallery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If she is open for visitors she usually puts out a &lt;em&gt;sandwich board&lt;/em&gt; at
the end of the road, sometimes with a couple of balloons attached.  In
that case, you are in luck.  She will welcome you to her home and let
you discover her art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a copy of a book she produced, here is the cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/SharonWilson/book_cover.jpg" src="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/galleries/SharonWilson/book_cover.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 400px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My cat seems to like the book too:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/Snowy/snowy_wilson.jpg" src="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/galleries/Snowy/snowy_wilson.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 400px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a story behind everything she paints.  She will tell you some
of those stories, but also let you find your own story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is another picture, it has a good story too:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/SharonWilson/father_and_daughter.jpg" src="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/galleries/SharonWilson/father_and_daughter.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 400px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>art</category><category>bermuda</category><guid>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/sharon-wilson.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2015 15:40:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bermuda 3 Bahamas 0</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/bermuda-3-bahamas-0.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This afternoon Bermuda were playing Bahamas in a World Cup qualifier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the second leg, but Bermuda, led by Nahki Wells, were already
5-0 win in the Bahamas last Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This game hadn't been generally broadcast in Bermuda.  But we had seen
highlights, and the first many of us knew about the game was via a
banner that was put out on the TV station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a long suffering supporter of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sheffield_United_F.C."&gt;Mighty Blades&lt;/a&gt; I have rarely
been in the position of being able to go to a game, already 5-0 up.  I
have also never been to a World Cup game before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So today we set off early to the game on the moped.  The game was a
sell out, parking was likely to be tricky.  In any case, the build up
to the game would likely be fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was cold.  Not Canada cold, but Bermuda cold.  Cloudy and damp,
windy and looked like it could rain any minute.  The rain held off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The build up to the game was fun too.  Many in the crowd knew one or
more of the players well.  There was excitement that we would see a
few goals, and a slight fear that maybe things could unravel.  And
there were Gombeys :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bermuda did dominate the game from start to finish.  The goalkeeper,
Fredrick Hall, was substited at half-time.  I am guessing that he was
frozen, as the ball boys had all had a lot more work to do.  It was
a good time to give his back-up a chance to play, and he at least had
some saves to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nahki Wells won a penalty, then crashed the resulting kick against the
cross-bar.  This was close to half-time, Bermuda had already had 5-6
really good chances, but the ball didn't want to go in the net.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier Wells had been fouled, about 30 yards out and needed treatment
from the physio.  He was then made to leave the field, and was not
able to be there for the free-kick that required the treatment.
Broken rules?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Justi Donawa had what looked like a painful injury to his foot, and
had to be replaced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second half was more of the same, but Bermuda were increasingly
getting the feeling that it was going to end 0-0.  The players felt it
and the crowd too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then Nahki Wells broke through and this time made no mistake, 1-0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this point every time Bermuda went forward, and that was
frequently, they looked like scoring.  The game ended 3-0.  The Gombey
Warriors will play Guatemala, away on the 8th of June, at home on the
16th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two last things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is a very young Bermuda team.  I heard the average age is
just 21.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Bahamas also have a young team.  They played a good game today,
the game flowed, there were lots of entertaining moments.  It can't
have been easy travelling away already 5-0 down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a great afternoon, two teams, refs and the crowd all played
their part.  Looking forward to the next games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bermuda</category><category>football</category><category>sufc</category><guid>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/bermuda-3-bahamas-0.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2015 22:34:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bermudaful Day</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/bermudaful-day.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks back I had my sons and their partners visiting from
Canada.  They were having difficulty understanding why I am thinking
it was so cold here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've lived in many places, but including hard Ottawa winters, but
never felt as cold as Bermuda the last few weeks.  It is all
perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had good times while they were here, below is just one of those
days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pink-and-blue-limo"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pink and blue limo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'd decided to go to Spittal Pond.  As we are down the west end of
the island, that means 2 buses, or &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/the-pink-and-blue-limo.rst"&gt;the pink and blue limo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were in luck, the number 7 bus pulled up just as we reached the
stop.  A sunny day, so the views along South Shore were spectacular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were soon in town and just had a bit of time between buses to look
at Victoria Park and the web of ropes holding up trees that have been
lifted back up since the hurricanes knocked them over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onto the number 1 bus and another beautiful journey.  You are higher
up on the bus, and see so a lot more.  Plus it stops every now and
again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="spittal-pond"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Spittal Pond&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/SpittalPond/20150221_132114.jpg" src="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/galleries/SpittalPond/20150221_132114.jpg" style="width: 400px; height: 300px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have liked Spittal Pond for a lot of years.  It is a place in
Bermuda where you can really feel in a natural environment.
Spectactular views and lots to explore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also a place that changes through the seasons, so there is
always something new to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the first time I had been since the hurricanes.  There wasn't
much sign of them on this walk.  Just a fiew views that didn't used to
exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we were treated to a sunny day without much wind.  The ocean
always looks better in the sun.  It lights up the clarity of the water
and the pink sand beneath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The path leads down to some rocks where in a few places there are
actually steps cut out to make it a little easier to clamber over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the waters edge there were a couple of large parrot fish, bobbing
around as the waves were breaking against the rocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/SpittalPond/20150221_140921.jpg" src="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/galleries/SpittalPond/20150221_140921.jpg" style="width: 400px; height: 300px;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="portuguese-rock"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Portuguese Rock&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We took the little detour up to a rocky cliff overlooking the ocean.
Here there is a brass plate that is a cast of an inscription that was
found on the rock here.  It has the date 1543 and some other marks
that have been interpretted as "R. P." standing for Rex Portugaline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1543 is nearly 70 years before the island was settled, indicating that
there is more to the early history of this island than we are every
likely to discover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/SpittalPond/20150221_133042.jpg" src="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/galleries/SpittalPond/20150221_133042.jpg" style="width: 400px; height: 300px;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-farm-on-mcgalls-hill"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The farm on McGalls Hill&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once back at the road we decided to walk over the hill, past St Mark's
church and down McGall's Hill to the Northrock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part way down the hill we stopped to look at a small banana
plantation.  The farmer, Henry, and his wife, Theresa, were there
looking after the land and invited us down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Henry delighted in telling us just what is invoved in growing
bananas.  He also showed us onions, giant cloves of garlic and new
potatoes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They had such patience in showing how all the different plants
thrived.  Henry also told us about the fruit salad tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citrus fruit used to be a big thing in Bermuda.  If you visit the
island ask an older Bermudian about the citrus and they will tell you
Bermuda used to have some of the best citrus fruit you can find.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Henry explained that you can even grow fruit salad trees here: a
single tree that grows lemons, limes, oranges and grapefruit, all as a
result of grafting buts from different fruits onto a wild lemon base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, it was a great day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bermuda</category><category>gardening</category><category>Spittal Pond</category><guid>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/bermudaful-day.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 03:35:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Pink and Blue Limo</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/the-pink-and-blue-limo.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I first met &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Acegirl"&gt;ace-girl&lt;/a&gt; I was living in Ottawa.  One day she was
heading out into town on one of her missions.  I asked if she wanted
me to run her wherever she was going in the car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to confess, I don't really enjoy driving around Ottawa.  In
winter, when it is -25C outside then the car is a nice option to
have.  But I know I will spend a chunk of time stuck in traffic.
Plus, Ottawa is a grid system, there are traffic lights every block.
But, if ace-girl is running late then again the car can be handy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This day, she just responded, "Don't worry, I will just take the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.showbus.com/galcanada/octranspo.htm"&gt;Red and White Limo&lt;/a&gt;."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regular readers of this blog (if there are any! -- note to self, look
into google analytics) will know that I have a bit of a thing about
red and white, entirely due to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sheffield_United_F.C."&gt;Red and White Wizards&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my ears pricked up at the mention of red and white.  I was a little
concerned &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Acegirl"&gt;ace-girl&lt;/a&gt; seemed to be planning to take the limo to get where
she wanted.  Really, I would much rather run her there in the car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She quickly put my out of my misery.  The buses in Ottawa are red and
white, so &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Acegirl"&gt;ace-girl&lt;/a&gt; just referred to them as the red and white limo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have always liked the bus.  I grew up in Sheffield, UK at a time
when the bus service was quite excellent.  Being under 16 I could go
anywhere in town for just 2 new pence.  Adults had to pay the princely
sum of 10 new pence.  I would walk down to the bottom of our road and
a bus would always turn up within 10 minutes or so.  No need to check
the timetable: the buses were often 5 minutes or so off schedule, but
they were so regular that it didn't matter.  Sheffield buses were
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bus-and-coach-photos.com/picture/number3844.asp"&gt;Brown and Cream Limos&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not really my favourite colour scheme, red and white would have been
better, but then the blue and white half of the city might never have
taken a bus.  In any case, these things looked like giant ice-cream
sandwiches: a block of vanilla ice cream sandwiched between two
wafers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ride into town was always fun.  I would sit upstairs, preferably
at the front where you could see everything.  My journey was down
Abbeydale Road.  It felt like you could literally find anything you
wanted on Abbeydale Road.  Looking out of the bus I would always
notice new things.  There was the cycle shop that had a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Penny-farthing"&gt;penny
farthing&lt;/a&gt; mounted above the shop window.   A bit further down there
was Bardwell's electronics store.  This was like a little hardware
store only it sold electronic components:  resistors, capacitors and
these new fangled things called transistors.  Oh, and you could still
get valves there too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well move on 30 or so years and I am now in Bermuda with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Acegirl"&gt;ace-girl&lt;/a&gt;.
Nowadays she takes the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bermuda-online.org/bermudabus.jpg"&gt;Pink and Blue Limo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For anyone who enjoys buses, the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bermuda-online.org/bermudabus.jpg"&gt;Pink and Blue Limo&lt;/a&gt; has to be one
of the best bus experiences in the world.  First of all, the buses are
pink and blue.  Pink to match the sand on the beaches, blue to match
the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bus stops are marked by pink or blue poles.  Pink means the bus is
heading in to town, blue means it is heading away from town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am lucky, I live at the top of a hill between South Shore and Middle
Road.  I can walk down to South Shore and take the 7, or I can go to
Middle Road and take the 8.  There is a bus every half hour, happily
at my point in the island the buses are off cut by 15 minutes, the
result is average waiting time should be less than 10 minutes most of
the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have a moped.  This is a great way to get around the island,
but on occasion I head into town and end up having a couple of beers.
One such occasion was last Wednesday.  The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sheffield_United_F.C."&gt;Red and White Wizards&lt;/a&gt;
were playing Tottenham Hotspur in the first leg of the League Cup
semi-final.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Blades are two divisions below Spurs.  Just getting to this semi
was quite an achievement.  I headed in to town with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Acegirl"&gt;ace-girl&lt;/a&gt; to
watch the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can expect, for such a major fixture the bar was packed out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/Blades/packed_out_at_the_hood.jpg" src="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/galleries/Blades/packed_out_at_the_hood.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 400px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was fearing the worst.  The Blades have actually been doing really
well in the cups since &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nigel_Clough"&gt;Nigel Clough&lt;/a&gt; took over as manager.  But
after years of following the Blades I know not to get my hopes up.  I
really just hoped that the game wouldn't be over in 20 minutes with us
3-0 down and the prospect of a pointless game at Bramall Lane the
following week.  In fact, first half the blades looked in control,
even had a couple of half chances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The longer the game went on, the more I dared to hope.  Spurs did get
a penalty, which they scored, but the game finished 1-0.  As this is
two legs, the blades are just 1-0 down at half-time with the second
leg due to be played in front of a sell-out crowd at the Lane.
Tomorrow could be fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, suffice to say, riding home on the bike was not an option.  We
left the bike with one of the people working in the bar.  His bike was
off the road due to a scary accident, happily he just had a bit of
road rash and some bruises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day I took the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bermuda-online.org/bermudabus.jpg"&gt;Pink and Blue Limo&lt;/a&gt; in to town to collect
the bike.  I walked down to the 7, but was sat on the wall admiring
the view and looking for my ticket when the bus sailed past.  Not the
driver's fault, I wasn't at the actual stop.  Fortunately, I had time
to walk over the hill, getting there just in time to admire the view
before the 8 turned up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bermuda bus etiquette is quite complex.  The buses are smaller than
normal buses and only single decker, mainly because the roads here are
pretty narrow.  If you are on the bus you wait until it has come to a
stop before getting up from your seat to get off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The school children always give up their seat to older people.
Everyone greets the driver as they get on the bus.  Usually, there are
a bunch of regulars on the bus.  It is Bermuda, everyone knows
everyone and you see people catching up on news as they encounter
friends and relatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always like to get a seat by the window.  On the number 7 the views
of the South Shore beaches are breathtaking.  On the number 8 you are
inland for much of the journey, but it is never dull.  You
will get glimpses of the ocean, but also see lots of the wonderful
coloured houses and of course all the plants and trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the hurricanes Gonzalo and Fay, back in October there has been
lots more to look at.  First, there was all the damage to the trees as
well as some property damage.  Within a couple of days everything was
pretty much running as normal, but everywhere you looked there were
people helping clean up.  Either soldiers in the regiment, those
working for the government as well as many proud Bermudians working
together to get the island back on its feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the hurricanes took out a lot of trees, so now you can see things
you never knew were there.  The older Bermudians just smile, they have
seen it before, after Fabian or Emily or Felix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journey is a good time to think, to slow down, experience
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vbVyE6hZjCU"&gt;another world that is Bermuda&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am writing this post today in part because the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bermuda-online.org/bermudabus.jpg"&gt;Pink and Blue Limo&lt;/a&gt;
is off the road.  Unfortunately, the government here is short of
money.  As a result, they have been trying to reduce the wage bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is coming at a time when the island is full of excitement having
won the right to host the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.americascup.com/"&gt;America's Cup&lt;/a&gt; in 2017.  There is a lot of
work to do to get the island ready for this.  But the government is
broke.  And to deal with that they made an agreement with the unions
to cut wages in return for days of &lt;em&gt;furlough&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know the ins-and-outs of it all, but the hope was this would
be a temporary measure and that after a year or so the budget would
begin to balance and hours would be restored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This now doesn't look like happening and so the last two days there
have been peaceful demonstrations in town in protest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is hoping that all parties will get around the table and work out
a solution that works for all of Bermuda and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Acegirl"&gt;ace-girl&lt;/a&gt; can get back
to her &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bermuda-online.org/bermudabus.jpg"&gt;Pink and Blue Limo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and if the blades could somehow pull off a miracle tomorrow, that
would also be good ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bermuda</category><category>bus</category><category>ottawa</category><category>sufc</category><guid>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/the-pink-and-blue-limo.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 18:57:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>I met Bill's Gates and got the t-shirt</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/i-met-bills-gates-and-got-the-t-shirt.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those who know me probably think that Bill Gates is not exactly on my
top ten list of people I would like to meet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been an free and open software enthusiast for longer than I care
to remember.  Let's just say that over the years Bill hasn't exactly
been a friend of open source.  To be fair, it pretty much threatened
to destroy his rather lucrative business model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To some extent it has.  Bill has moved on, so has Steve "linux is a
cancer" Balmer.  Microsoft is making more and more code available as
open source.  I would guess they have realised that if you want to be
relevant in today's software world you need your stuff to run on
linux, or at least play nicely with that platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a lot going on in the tech world, it isn't clear how it is
all going to pan out.  But free and open source is stronger than
ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night, my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Acegirl"&gt;ace-girl&lt;/a&gt; and I wandered down the hill to the local
hostelry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/the-music-from-uncle.html"&gt;blogged&lt;/a&gt; a few weeks back, Saturday there is a DJ at this place
and it is often a fun night.  We were planning to meet another friend
who had just got back to the island.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived and things were still quiet.  They were showing some
highlights from the FA Cup on the TV.  I love the FA Cup, always have
done.  It is when the lower league teams get a chance to show what
they can do against higher clubs.  Yesterday was a great day for the
underdogs.  Bradford City, also known as the &lt;em&gt;Bantams&lt;/em&gt; (curiously,
google in their soccer info used the name &lt;em&gt;Bantams&lt;/em&gt; rather than
Bradford City.  It was odd, because every other club was listed by
their more formal name.  It was Sheffield United, not the Blades
playing at Preston.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were quite a few people having dinner at the place and 2-3 were
celebrating birthdays.  DJ Uncle was doing his round of the room,
figuring out his audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around this time a guy walked by wearing a t-shirt and a silver tie,
all sparkles and glitter, obviously top quality as it was ready-tied
and held around his neck by a piece of elastic.   I saw the words,
"Bill's Gates" on his t-shirt.   My curiousity was peaked and we got
talking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It soon became clear it was the guy's birthday.  He introduced himself
as Bill Gates (or it might have been Bill's Gates).  There may have
been some alcohol involved, so details are a little blurry.  But the
gist was he was founder member of "BFBC".  The F is along the same
lines as the f in swfiua.  So it was "Bill's F* Boat Club".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly, this was my chance to be photographed with the man himself:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/Gates/Me%20with%20Bill's%20Gates.jpg" src="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/galleries/Gates/Me%20with%20Bill's%20Gates.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 400px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can report that Bill was a fine upstanding character and was even
kind enough to give me one of his t-shirts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/Gates/i_got_the_t_shirt.jpg" src="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/galleries/Gates/i_got_the_t_shirt.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 400px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now in case you haven't heard Bermuda has been chosen as the venue for
the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.americascup.com/en/news/131_Bermuda-is-the-home-of-the-2017-America-s-Cup.html"&gt;2017 America's Cup&lt;/a&gt;.  There is quite a bit of excitement about
the island due to this.  Maybe BFBC will enter the race :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, Uncle played &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=inS9gAgSENE"&gt;Happy Birthday&lt;/a&gt; for Bill and the others with
birthdays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been on a bit of a Springsteen kick that last week or so,
something to do with starting to learn some tunes from my "Bruce
Springsteen easy guitar":&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/Springsteen/Springsteen.jpg" src="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/galleries/Springsteen/Springsteen.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 400px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ace girl asked Uncle if he would play some.  And in light of the giant
killings in the FA Cup and with the hope of more to come from the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sheffield_United_F.C."&gt;Red
and White Wizards&lt;/a&gt; it was appropriate that he should choose &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6vQpW9XRiyM"&gt;Glory Days&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks Bill and everyone who helped make last night a fun time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bermuda</category><category>blades</category><category>linux</category><category>music</category><guid>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/i-met-bills-gates-and-got-the-t-shirt.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2015 22:22:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Music from UNCLE</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/the-music-from-uncle.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am lucky enough to live in a wonderful part of the world.  &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vbVyE6hZjCU"&gt;Bermuda
is another world&lt;/a&gt;.  It really is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A tiny island of just 60,000 people, a place with a complex history.
There are a lot of wonderful people here.  There are also some cool
things starting to happen here such as &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://code441.com"&gt;code441&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://wearebermuda.com/"&gt;wearebermuda&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is Christmas time.  The last Saturday before Christmas and there
are parties everywhere.  Many of them are company parties.  You know
the thing, you sort of have to go along.  With luck you'll get to sit
with some of the people at work you actually like.  As the night goes
on, if you are lucky, you will find some like-minded people to spend
time with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, no office party for me.  So, we went to a local bar.  There
is a DJ every Saturday night at this place.  The dance floor is always
packed, for a simple reason: he knows his crowd.  And he always walks
around before he starts, plans his work and works his plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night there must have been 60 cars parked in the area.  The place
was packed.  Everyone was having a good time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now only in Bermuda could a DJ start the evening with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wDC7NeVfc30"&gt;My God is
Awesome&lt;/a&gt;, follow it up with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9T4WB2zfmps"&gt;Silent Night&lt;/a&gt; and already have his
audience tapping their feet and getting into the mood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd never heard &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wDC7NeVfc30"&gt;My God is Awesome&lt;/a&gt; before.  Actually, I am sure I
must of heard it, just hadn't really listend.  And I only really
listened this time because it reminded me of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://awesome.naquadah.org/"&gt;Awesome window
manager&lt;/a&gt;  I've been using awesome the last few weeks and it has had a
huge impact on the way I use my computer.   And I am only scratching
the surface of what it can do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this was followed up with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xlVxEAUqWU0"&gt;You can't hurry love&lt;/a&gt;, an old version
by the Supremes.  Another special song for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there was &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vdB-8eLEW8g"&gt;One Love&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JFMtBibwrgY"&gt;Electric Slide&lt;/a&gt;, complete with line
dancing.  Bermudian line dancing has to be seen to be appreciated.
Last night was typical.  A mixture of regulars to the place and those
just there for the party.  Everyone having a good time
together. There were a lot of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y6Sxv-sUYtM"&gt;Happy&lt;/a&gt; people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My music tastes are a bit weird.  I pretty much follow the crowd.  And
my guitar music.  I have been (very slowly) learning to play over the
past few years.  I have a few books with tabs, most of them have the
word &lt;em&gt;easy&lt;/em&gt; in their titles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would pick a song and try the patience of those around me by playing
it over and over again, badly.  I would look at the tabs of some and
think, no way I can play that.  But now I am starting to get a little
better and a little more adventurous.  I am noticing songs that have
been there for years ready for me to play.  Song of the moment is the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YZo88P1Ie94"&gt;The Joker&lt;/a&gt;.  Like all good songs, there is lots of scope for
changing the lyrics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
I'm a picker,
I'm a grinder,
I'm a lover,
I'm a sinner,
I play my music in the sun
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grinder not grinner, in tribute to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pTXjp2bf1vo"&gt;Sheffield Grinder&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And seeing as I have a bit of a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://git-scm.com/"&gt;git&lt;/a&gt; obsession:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
I'm a puller,
I'm a merger,
I'm a midnight coder,
I get my checkouts from github.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks Uncle, old stuff still works.  Sometimes it works way better
than the new stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>awesome</category><category>bermuda</category><category>music</category><guid>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/the-music-from-uncle.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 20:01:33 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>