<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Around the world in 80 days (bermuda bus ottawa sufc)</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/</link><description></description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" rel="self" href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/categories/bermuda-bus-ottawa-sufc.xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 16:15:50 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The Pink and Blue Limo</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/the-pink-and-blue-limo.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I first met &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Acegirl"&gt;ace-girl&lt;/a&gt; I was living in Ottawa.  One day she was
heading out into town on one of her missions.  I asked if she wanted
me to run her wherever she was going in the car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to confess, I don't really enjoy driving around Ottawa.  In
winter, when it is -25C outside then the car is a nice option to
have.  But I know I will spend a chunk of time stuck in traffic.
Plus, Ottawa is a grid system, there are traffic lights every block.
But, if ace-girl is running late then again the car can be handy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This day, she just responded, "Don't worry, I will just take the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.showbus.com/galcanada/octranspo.htm"&gt;Red and White Limo&lt;/a&gt;."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regular readers of this blog (if there are any! -- note to self, look
into google analytics) will know that I have a bit of a thing about
red and white, entirely due to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sheffield_United_F.C."&gt;Red and White Wizards&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my ears pricked up at the mention of red and white.  I was a little
concerned &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Acegirl"&gt;ace-girl&lt;/a&gt; seemed to be planning to take the limo to get where
she wanted.  Really, I would much rather run her there in the car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She quickly put my out of my misery.  The buses in Ottawa are red and
white, so &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Acegirl"&gt;ace-girl&lt;/a&gt; just referred to them as the red and white limo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have always liked the bus.  I grew up in Sheffield, UK at a time
when the bus service was quite excellent.  Being under 16 I could go
anywhere in town for just 2 new pence.  Adults had to pay the princely
sum of 10 new pence.  I would walk down to the bottom of our road and
a bus would always turn up within 10 minutes or so.  No need to check
the timetable: the buses were often 5 minutes or so off schedule, but
they were so regular that it didn't matter.  Sheffield buses were
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bus-and-coach-photos.com/picture/number3844.asp"&gt;Brown and Cream Limos&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not really my favourite colour scheme, red and white would have been
better, but then the blue and white half of the city might never have
taken a bus.  In any case, these things looked like giant ice-cream
sandwiches: a block of vanilla ice cream sandwiched between two
wafers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ride into town was always fun.  I would sit upstairs, preferably
at the front where you could see everything.  My journey was down
Abbeydale Road.  It felt like you could literally find anything you
wanted on Abbeydale Road.  Looking out of the bus I would always
notice new things.  There was the cycle shop that had a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Penny-farthing"&gt;penny
farthing&lt;/a&gt; mounted above the shop window.   A bit further down there
was Bardwell's electronics store.  This was like a little hardware
store only it sold electronic components:  resistors, capacitors and
these new fangled things called transistors.  Oh, and you could still
get valves there too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well move on 30 or so years and I am now in Bermuda with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Acegirl"&gt;ace-girl&lt;/a&gt;.
Nowadays she takes the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bermuda-online.org/bermudabus.jpg"&gt;Pink and Blue Limo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For anyone who enjoys buses, the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bermuda-online.org/bermudabus.jpg"&gt;Pink and Blue Limo&lt;/a&gt; has to be one
of the best bus experiences in the world.  First of all, the buses are
pink and blue.  Pink to match the sand on the beaches, blue to match
the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bus stops are marked by pink or blue poles.  Pink means the bus is
heading in to town, blue means it is heading away from town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am lucky, I live at the top of a hill between South Shore and Middle
Road.  I can walk down to South Shore and take the 7, or I can go to
Middle Road and take the 8.  There is a bus every half hour, happily
at my point in the island the buses are off cut by 15 minutes, the
result is average waiting time should be less than 10 minutes most of
the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have a moped.  This is a great way to get around the island,
but on occasion I head into town and end up having a couple of beers.
One such occasion was last Wednesday.  The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sheffield_United_F.C."&gt;Red and White Wizards&lt;/a&gt;
were playing Tottenham Hotspur in the first leg of the League Cup
semi-final.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Blades are two divisions below Spurs.  Just getting to this semi
was quite an achievement.  I headed in to town with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Acegirl"&gt;ace-girl&lt;/a&gt; to
watch the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can expect, for such a major fixture the bar was packed out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/Blades/packed_out_at_the_hood.jpg" src="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/galleries/Blades/packed_out_at_the_hood.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 400px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was fearing the worst.  The Blades have actually been doing really
well in the cups since &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nigel_Clough"&gt;Nigel Clough&lt;/a&gt; took over as manager.  But
after years of following the Blades I know not to get my hopes up.  I
really just hoped that the game wouldn't be over in 20 minutes with us
3-0 down and the prospect of a pointless game at Bramall Lane the
following week.  In fact, first half the blades looked in control,
even had a couple of half chances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The longer the game went on, the more I dared to hope.  Spurs did get
a penalty, which they scored, but the game finished 1-0.  As this is
two legs, the blades are just 1-0 down at half-time with the second
leg due to be played in front of a sell-out crowd at the Lane.
Tomorrow could be fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, suffice to say, riding home on the bike was not an option.  We
left the bike with one of the people working in the bar.  His bike was
off the road due to a scary accident, happily he just had a bit of
road rash and some bruises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day I took the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bermuda-online.org/bermudabus.jpg"&gt;Pink and Blue Limo&lt;/a&gt; in to town to collect
the bike.  I walked down to the 7, but was sat on the wall admiring
the view and looking for my ticket when the bus sailed past.  Not the
driver's fault, I wasn't at the actual stop.  Fortunately, I had time
to walk over the hill, getting there just in time to admire the view
before the 8 turned up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bermuda bus etiquette is quite complex.  The buses are smaller than
normal buses and only single decker, mainly because the roads here are
pretty narrow.  If you are on the bus you wait until it has come to a
stop before getting up from your seat to get off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The school children always give up their seat to older people.
Everyone greets the driver as they get on the bus.  Usually, there are
a bunch of regulars on the bus.  It is Bermuda, everyone knows
everyone and you see people catching up on news as they encounter
friends and relatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always like to get a seat by the window.  On the number 7 the views
of the South Shore beaches are breathtaking.  On the number 8 you are
inland for much of the journey, but it is never dull.  You
will get glimpses of the ocean, but also see lots of the wonderful
coloured houses and of course all the plants and trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the hurricanes Gonzalo and Fay, back in October there has been
lots more to look at.  First, there was all the damage to the trees as
well as some property damage.  Within a couple of days everything was
pretty much running as normal, but everywhere you looked there were
people helping clean up.  Either soldiers in the regiment, those
working for the government as well as many proud Bermudians working
together to get the island back on its feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the hurricanes took out a lot of trees, so now you can see things
you never knew were there.  The older Bermudians just smile, they have
seen it before, after Fabian or Emily or Felix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journey is a good time to think, to slow down, experience
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vbVyE6hZjCU"&gt;another world that is Bermuda&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am writing this post today in part because the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bermuda-online.org/bermudabus.jpg"&gt;Pink and Blue Limo&lt;/a&gt;
is off the road.  Unfortunately, the government here is short of
money.  As a result, they have been trying to reduce the wage bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is coming at a time when the island is full of excitement having
won the right to host the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.americascup.com/"&gt;America's Cup&lt;/a&gt; in 2017.  There is a lot of
work to do to get the island ready for this.  But the government is
broke.  And to deal with that they made an agreement with the unions
to cut wages in return for days of &lt;em&gt;furlough&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know the ins-and-outs of it all, but the hope was this would
be a temporary measure and that after a year or so the budget would
begin to balance and hours would be restored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This now doesn't look like happening and so the last two days there
have been peaceful demonstrations in town in protest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is hoping that all parties will get around the table and work out
a solution that works for all of Bermuda and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Acegirl"&gt;ace-girl&lt;/a&gt; can get back
to her &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bermuda-online.org/bermudabus.jpg"&gt;Pink and Blue Limo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and if the blades could somehow pull off a miracle tomorrow, that
would also be good ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bermuda bus ottawa sufc</category><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/the-pink-and-blue-limo.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 18:57:42 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>