<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Around the world in 80 days (kindling python github)</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/categories/kindling-python-github.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 15:15:29 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Dancing in the dark</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/dancing-in-the-dark.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;So ten days to go until this project is supposed to be up and running.
Now, this is a software project, just something I have been doing
mostly for my own amusement, but it has a deadline and I am starting
to hear that whooshing sound that deadlines make as the come by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am 70 days in, so what do I have?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a simple &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Create,_read,_update_and_delete"&gt;CRUD&lt;/a&gt; api built in &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.djangoproject.com/"&gt;django&lt;/a&gt;.  It comes with data
migrations and code generators that mean adding new models should
require very little coding.  I have the api documented using
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/marcgibbons/django-rest-swagger"&gt;django rest swagger&lt;/a&gt;.  And I can manipulate tables using the
standard django admin interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also taken a look at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/tomwalker/django_quiz/"&gt;django quiz&lt;/a&gt; and it looks like it will
do a good job for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, so far no proper front end.  As far as the front end is
concerned I am &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UoPwqDW5750"&gt;Dancing in the Dark&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had two hurricanes here in Bermuda back in October.  It is winter
now.  Actually, a beautiful day today, 21C, sunny, few clouds and
beautiful blue oceans.  I just rode out of town on the bus.  Must be
one of the best bus rides in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, come evening, the sun disappears and a chill descends as the
dampness comes out of the walls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of wood around the island, branches broken by the
storms, whole trees knocked over.  In many cases, all the branches
have been cut off trees and the stumps set back up, green shoots of
recovery are starting to sprout from these stumps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, I have been gathering wood for fires most nights.  It
reminds me of happy days on scout camps way back when.  Summer camps
with the scouts were the best.  We would cook all week on an open
fire.  Between us, and guided by &lt;em&gt;Skip&lt;/em&gt;, we would figure out how to
light fires, how to get a good fire going and then let it die down a
little for cooking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing you learn right from the start is, &lt;em&gt;you can't start a fire
without a spark&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that is where &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://nedbatchelder.com//blog/201501/kindling_projects_page.html"&gt;kindling&lt;/a&gt; comes in. As I trim the bigger branches
to get logs for the fires the smaller twigs drop to the floor.  Once I
have logs you can gather up a bundle of smaller twigs.  This is the
kindling.  This is what lights the fire.  The tiny pieces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, today I am setting out on a little kindling project.  I want to
add a little box to the &lt;em&gt;Around the world in 80 days&lt;/em&gt; site with
today's date and a couple of other labels showing 80 days from now and
80 days before today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I could do this very quickly with django templates given the code
I already have.  But, I want to try &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://angularjs.org/"&gt;angular.js&lt;/a&gt;.  That way I will
have a new tool I can play with.  If it isn't working for me, then
maybe it will end up like the bow-saw that I find less fun to use than
the small hand axe, still useful, but not the tool I like to use most
of the time.  Or maybe, it will turn out to be a new and better hand
axe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, time to light the blue touch paper and stand well back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>kindling python github</category><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/dancing-in-the-dark.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 17:25:29 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>