<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Around the world in 80 days (linux)</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/categories/linux.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 18:47:38 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Pi Day at Chewstick</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/pi-day-at-chewstick.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This Saturday the date is 3.14.15, March 14th, '15.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;March 14th has become known as &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.piday.org/"&gt;Pi Day&lt;/a&gt;, on account of the fact that
the first three digits of the mathematical constant pi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year it is extra special, since the next two digits are 15, which
corresponds to the year.  After that, the next five digits of pi are
9:26:53.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To mark the occasion &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.chewstick.org/"&gt;Chewstick&lt;/a&gt; at the new premises on 81 Front St
is hosting a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.raspberrypi.org/pi-day-is-around-the-corner/"&gt;Raspberry Pi Day&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A raspberry pi is a $30 computer (Raspberry Pi) that runs off a phone
charger. We will be making videos of people performing, playing games
etc, so bring your camera, SD card, instruments to contribute your
content as we build a Raspberry Pi media centre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/RaspberryPi/raspberry.jpg" src="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/galleries/RaspberryPi/raspberry.jpg" style="width: 400px; height: 300px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will also have a retro games console running on a pi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan is to start the event at 9:26:53am and run with it until
9:26:53pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have three working raspberry pi's and some SD cards that can be used
to host the operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have one pi running the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://kodi.tv/"&gt;Kodi&lt;/a&gt; media centre that I hope to add some
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.chewstick.org/"&gt;Chewstick&lt;/a&gt; and Bermuda content to.  The image below shows Kodi
displaying the Bermuda weather.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/RaspberryPi/weather_pi.jpg" src="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/galleries/RaspberryPi/weather_pi.jpg" style="width: 400px; height: 300px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have another pi running a retro games console and a third running
the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.raspbian.org/"&gt;Raspian&lt;/a&gt; operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no need to bring anything but yourself to the event, but if
you do have raspberry pi's or related hardware it would be good to
bring them along too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All going well, we will also have actual pies to eat too :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information see this &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1563187683958954/"&gt;facebook&lt;/a&gt; posting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>chewstick</category><category>linux</category><category>raspberry pi</category><guid>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/pi-day-at-chewstick.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 15:14:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>I met Bill's Gates and got the t-shirt</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/i-met-bills-gates-and-got-the-t-shirt.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those who know me probably think that Bill Gates is not exactly on my
top ten list of people I would like to meet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been an free and open software enthusiast for longer than I care
to remember.  Let's just say that over the years Bill hasn't exactly
been a friend of open source.  To be fair, it pretty much threatened
to destroy his rather lucrative business model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To some extent it has.  Bill has moved on, so has Steve "linux is a
cancer" Balmer.  Microsoft is making more and more code available as
open source.  I would guess they have realised that if you want to be
relevant in today's software world you need your stuff to run on
linux, or at least play nicely with that platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a lot going on in the tech world, it isn't clear how it is
all going to pan out.  But free and open source is stronger than
ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night, my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Acegirl"&gt;ace-girl&lt;/a&gt; and I wandered down the hill to the local
hostelry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/the-music-from-uncle.html"&gt;blogged&lt;/a&gt; a few weeks back, Saturday there is a DJ at this place
and it is often a fun night.  We were planning to meet another friend
who had just got back to the island.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived and things were still quiet.  They were showing some
highlights from the FA Cup on the TV.  I love the FA Cup, always have
done.  It is when the lower league teams get a chance to show what
they can do against higher clubs.  Yesterday was a great day for the
underdogs.  Bradford City, also known as the &lt;em&gt;Bantams&lt;/em&gt; (curiously,
google in their soccer info used the name &lt;em&gt;Bantams&lt;/em&gt; rather than
Bradford City.  It was odd, because every other club was listed by
their more formal name.  It was Sheffield United, not the Blades
playing at Preston.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were quite a few people having dinner at the place and 2-3 were
celebrating birthdays.  DJ Uncle was doing his round of the room,
figuring out his audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around this time a guy walked by wearing a t-shirt and a silver tie,
all sparkles and glitter, obviously top quality as it was ready-tied
and held around his neck by a piece of elastic.   I saw the words,
"Bill's Gates" on his t-shirt.   My curiousity was peaked and we got
talking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It soon became clear it was the guy's birthday.  He introduced himself
as Bill Gates (or it might have been Bill's Gates).  There may have
been some alcohol involved, so details are a little blurry.  But the
gist was he was founder member of "BFBC".  The F is along the same
lines as the f in swfiua.  So it was "Bill's F* Boat Club".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly, this was my chance to be photographed with the man himself:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/Gates/Me%20with%20Bill's%20Gates.jpg" src="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/galleries/Gates/Me%20with%20Bill's%20Gates.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 400px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can report that Bill was a fine upstanding character and was even
kind enough to give me one of his t-shirts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/Gates/i_got_the_t_shirt.jpg" src="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/galleries/Gates/i_got_the_t_shirt.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 400px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now in case you haven't heard Bermuda has been chosen as the venue for
the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.americascup.com/en/news/131_Bermuda-is-the-home-of-the-2017-America-s-Cup.html"&gt;2017 America's Cup&lt;/a&gt;.  There is quite a bit of excitement about
the island due to this.  Maybe BFBC will enter the race :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, Uncle played &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=inS9gAgSENE"&gt;Happy Birthday&lt;/a&gt; for Bill and the others with
birthdays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been on a bit of a Springsteen kick that last week or so,
something to do with starting to learn some tunes from my "Bruce
Springsteen easy guitar":&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/Springsteen/Springsteen.jpg" src="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/galleries/Springsteen/Springsteen.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 400px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ace girl asked Uncle if he would play some.  And in light of the giant
killings in the FA Cup and with the hope of more to come from the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sheffield_United_F.C."&gt;Red
and White Wizards&lt;/a&gt; it was appropriate that he should choose &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6vQpW9XRiyM"&gt;Glory Days&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks Bill and everyone who helped make last night a fun time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bermuda</category><category>blades</category><category>linux</category><category>music</category><guid>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/i-met-bills-gates-and-got-the-t-shirt.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2015 22:22:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Adventures in distro land..</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/adventures-in-distro-land.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We had a friend over the other evening.  I have a home full of half
working tech.  Stuff that really could do something, given enough
time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of my techy stuff has been neglected for a few years, so it is
suffering both bit and hardware rot.  So a good part of last night was
spent exploring why stuff wasn't working, in between finding a few
gems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So today, I had a few things I wanted to look into:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;why wasn't the server with the music on responding,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;installing a fedora iso onto a usb and seeing what it is like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That server with the music; well that thing won't even boot off a USB
key; though you can change a bucket load of things in the BIOS.  And
at one point it did seem like it would boot over the network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next stop, fedora install guide kindly gives the incantation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
dd if=fedora*.iso of=/dev/sdx  (x in my case was b)
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I booted up a laptop (the one with the battery that lasts 30
seconds) off the USB and fedora booted.  I did not have time to have a
good look around, but it seemed snappier and easier to use than the
Ubuntu desktop on the machine, more like the &lt;cite&gt;awesome wm&lt;/cite&gt; experience.
I will definitely take a nother look at this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to the music.  I resurrected an old mythtv box and tried to put
fedora on it.  I couldn't get it to install on the old myth box.  It
may have had something to do with some network issues that were going
on at the time.  Also possible there was some issue with this boxes
USB, it was an old machine, so might have old firmware.  Or the USB
isn't an innocent little USB.  But I digress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I tried arch.  This was like being beamed back to 1997.  It was fun
for a while, but then I typed the wrong thing and lost the internet
connection, which was what I needed to get the software to fix the
internet connection.  I did Ctrl-D out of the &lt;em&gt;chroot&lt;/em&gt; and if I'd been
awake when I booted back into it I might have skipped the second
install.  I gave up at the bootloader bit.  I know, I was nearly there :(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I might have to go back to arch one day when I have lots of time on my
hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So more rabbit holes.  Eventually, led to Debian.  By now the dining
table is buried under cables.  The IP over powerline is up and running
again and 2-3 boxes are in the pile marked broken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Debian install was been a joy, apart from the sporadic (or rather
repeated) interruptions to anything needing internet bandwidth (a
problem anywhere with expensive or unreliable bandwidth).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suspect I am biassed because over the years I have spent more time
with Debian based systems.  First with debian and then indirectly via
Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked Ubuntu primarily for its python packaging.  Ubuntu still is a
fantastic distribution for python.  As an interface for the sort of
programming I like to do it is becoming less responsive, or at least
that is my feeling.  Also, I am feeling myself further removed from
the hardware and the software configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, python packaging has come a long way.  With PyPi and
pip install the linux distro no longer matters so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Debian doesn't seem to have changed much in philosophy.  Most of what
I learnt back in the day still applies.  It led me through the install
with just enough information to make an informed decision about the
questions.  It guided pretty well, hinting which way I should go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of now I am yet to actually get it serving up the music, so this
will most likely not be the last distro related posting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>linux</category><guid>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/adventures-in-distro-land.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 00:19:11 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>