<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Around the world in 80 days (music)</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/categories/music.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 18:47:36 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>I met Bill's Gates and got the t-shirt</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/i-met-bills-gates-and-got-the-t-shirt.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those who know me probably think that Bill Gates is not exactly on my
top ten list of people I would like to meet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been an free and open software enthusiast for longer than I care
to remember.  Let's just say that over the years Bill hasn't exactly
been a friend of open source.  To be fair, it pretty much threatened
to destroy his rather lucrative business model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To some extent it has.  Bill has moved on, so has Steve "linux is a
cancer" Balmer.  Microsoft is making more and more code available as
open source.  I would guess they have realised that if you want to be
relevant in today's software world you need your stuff to run on
linux, or at least play nicely with that platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a lot going on in the tech world, it isn't clear how it is
all going to pan out.  But free and open source is stronger than
ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night, my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Acegirl"&gt;ace-girl&lt;/a&gt; and I wandered down the hill to the local
hostelry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/the-music-from-uncle.html"&gt;blogged&lt;/a&gt; a few weeks back, Saturday there is a DJ at this place
and it is often a fun night.  We were planning to meet another friend
who had just got back to the island.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived and things were still quiet.  They were showing some
highlights from the FA Cup on the TV.  I love the FA Cup, always have
done.  It is when the lower league teams get a chance to show what
they can do against higher clubs.  Yesterday was a great day for the
underdogs.  Bradford City, also known as the &lt;em&gt;Bantams&lt;/em&gt; (curiously,
google in their soccer info used the name &lt;em&gt;Bantams&lt;/em&gt; rather than
Bradford City.  It was odd, because every other club was listed by
their more formal name.  It was Sheffield United, not the Blades
playing at Preston.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were quite a few people having dinner at the place and 2-3 were
celebrating birthdays.  DJ Uncle was doing his round of the room,
figuring out his audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around this time a guy walked by wearing a t-shirt and a silver tie,
all sparkles and glitter, obviously top quality as it was ready-tied
and held around his neck by a piece of elastic.   I saw the words,
"Bill's Gates" on his t-shirt.   My curiousity was peaked and we got
talking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It soon became clear it was the guy's birthday.  He introduced himself
as Bill Gates (or it might have been Bill's Gates).  There may have
been some alcohol involved, so details are a little blurry.  But the
gist was he was founder member of "BFBC".  The F is along the same
lines as the f in swfiua.  So it was "Bill's F* Boat Club".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly, this was my chance to be photographed with the man himself:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/Gates/Me%20with%20Bill's%20Gates.jpg" src="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/galleries/Gates/Me%20with%20Bill's%20Gates.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 400px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can report that Bill was a fine upstanding character and was even
kind enough to give me one of his t-shirts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/Gates/i_got_the_t_shirt.jpg" src="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/galleries/Gates/i_got_the_t_shirt.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 400px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now in case you haven't heard Bermuda has been chosen as the venue for
the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.americascup.com/en/news/131_Bermuda-is-the-home-of-the-2017-America-s-Cup.html"&gt;2017 America's Cup&lt;/a&gt;.  There is quite a bit of excitement about
the island due to this.  Maybe BFBC will enter the race :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, Uncle played &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=inS9gAgSENE"&gt;Happy Birthday&lt;/a&gt; for Bill and the others with
birthdays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been on a bit of a Springsteen kick that last week or so,
something to do with starting to learn some tunes from my "Bruce
Springsteen easy guitar":&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="../galleries/Springsteen/Springsteen.jpg" src="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/galleries/Springsteen/Springsteen.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 400px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ace girl asked Uncle if he would play some.  And in light of the giant
killings in the FA Cup and with the hope of more to come from the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sheffield_United_F.C."&gt;Red
and White Wizards&lt;/a&gt; it was appropriate that he should choose &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6vQpW9XRiyM"&gt;Glory Days&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks Bill and everyone who helped make last night a fun time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bermuda</category><category>blades</category><category>linux</category><category>music</category><guid>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/i-met-bills-gates-and-got-the-t-shirt.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2015 22:22:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Music from UNCLE</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/the-music-from-uncle.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am lucky enough to live in a wonderful part of the world.  &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vbVyE6hZjCU"&gt;Bermuda
is another world&lt;/a&gt;.  It really is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A tiny island of just 60,000 people, a place with a complex history.
There are a lot of wonderful people here.  There are also some cool
things starting to happen here such as &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://code441.com"&gt;code441&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://wearebermuda.com/"&gt;wearebermuda&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is Christmas time.  The last Saturday before Christmas and there
are parties everywhere.  Many of them are company parties.  You know
the thing, you sort of have to go along.  With luck you'll get to sit
with some of the people at work you actually like.  As the night goes
on, if you are lucky, you will find some like-minded people to spend
time with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, no office party for me.  So, we went to a local bar.  There
is a DJ every Saturday night at this place.  The dance floor is always
packed, for a simple reason: he knows his crowd.  And he always walks
around before he starts, plans his work and works his plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night there must have been 60 cars parked in the area.  The place
was packed.  Everyone was having a good time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now only in Bermuda could a DJ start the evening with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wDC7NeVfc30"&gt;My God is
Awesome&lt;/a&gt;, follow it up with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9T4WB2zfmps"&gt;Silent Night&lt;/a&gt; and already have his
audience tapping their feet and getting into the mood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd never heard &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wDC7NeVfc30"&gt;My God is Awesome&lt;/a&gt; before.  Actually, I am sure I
must of heard it, just hadn't really listend.  And I only really
listened this time because it reminded me of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://awesome.naquadah.org/"&gt;Awesome window
manager&lt;/a&gt;  I've been using awesome the last few weeks and it has had a
huge impact on the way I use my computer.   And I am only scratching
the surface of what it can do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this was followed up with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xlVxEAUqWU0"&gt;You can't hurry love&lt;/a&gt;, an old version
by the Supremes.  Another special song for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there was &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vdB-8eLEW8g"&gt;One Love&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JFMtBibwrgY"&gt;Electric Slide&lt;/a&gt;, complete with line
dancing.  Bermudian line dancing has to be seen to be appreciated.
Last night was typical.  A mixture of regulars to the place and those
just there for the party.  Everyone having a good time
together. There were a lot of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y6Sxv-sUYtM"&gt;Happy&lt;/a&gt; people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My music tastes are a bit weird.  I pretty much follow the crowd.  And
my guitar music.  I have been (very slowly) learning to play over the
past few years.  I have a few books with tabs, most of them have the
word &lt;em&gt;easy&lt;/em&gt; in their titles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would pick a song and try the patience of those around me by playing
it over and over again, badly.  I would look at the tabs of some and
think, no way I can play that.  But now I am starting to get a little
better and a little more adventurous.  I am noticing songs that have
been there for years ready for me to play.  Song of the moment is the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YZo88P1Ie94"&gt;The Joker&lt;/a&gt;.  Like all good songs, there is lots of scope for
changing the lyrics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
I'm a picker,
I'm a grinder,
I'm a lover,
I'm a sinner,
I play my music in the sun
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grinder not grinner, in tribute to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pTXjp2bf1vo"&gt;Sheffield Grinder&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And seeing as I have a bit of a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://git-scm.com/"&gt;git&lt;/a&gt; obsession:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
I'm a puller,
I'm a merger,
I'm a midnight coder,
I get my checkouts from github.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks Uncle, old stuff still works.  Sometimes it works way better
than the new stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>awesome</category><category>bermuda</category><category>music</category><guid>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/the-music-from-uncle.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 20:01:33 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>