<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Around the world in 80 days (sufc sens)</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/categories/sufc-sens.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 18:47:38 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Blades and Sens results correlated?</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/blades-and-sens-results-correlated.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div tabindex="-1" id="notebook" class="border-box-sizing"&gt;
    &lt;div class="container" id="notebook-container"&gt;

&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have felt for a while that when the Blades win, the Sens also seem
to do better.  When the Blades lose, the Sens don't do so well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My guess is this is mostly just perspective, but I follow both teams.
Blades, or Sheffield United, are hoping to get a place in the League 1
play-offs.  The Sens, or Ottawa Senators, are trying to get into the
Stanley Playoffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you'd asked me at the start of the year, I would have thought being
about where we are was a distinct possibility.  I still felt we might
push into the top two.  That would get us up to the Championship
automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sens on the other hand appeared to be going nowhere.  Until the
inevitable sacking of the coach to be replaced by Dave Cameron, who
was the assistant up to that point.  And for a while nothing changed,
but then a new goalie was brought in, due to injuries.  Since then
they have been on a run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last few games have been just like watching the Blades.  The
Blades never (well almost never) do it the easy way.  So it is always
a season of maybe, just waiting for the point where it all unravels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this Sens run has been different.  They are already way beyond
what anyone could have hoped for a few months back.  But now they are
tantalisingly close to a playoffs, with a team that is playing well
and having fun.  But like the Blades, they've been doing it the hard
way.  3-0 leads disappearing, coming from behind to go on and win in
over-time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Getting-some-data"&gt;Getting some data&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/blades-and-sens-results-correlated.html#Getting-some-data"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, there has been a lot going on and my guess is that anything
that might be in the data will be better explained by major changes such
as of coaching staff or players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So first problem, getting the data.  I am planning to just get this season's results for both teams and extract the days when they both played, then take a look at how the results lined up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Yesterday's-games"&gt;Yesterday's games&lt;a class="anchor-link" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/blades-and-sens-results-correlated.html#Yesterday's-games"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The mighty Blades had a key game against local rivals Doncaster.  As
per usual, they did things the hard way, coming from behind twice to
end up winners 3-2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is two big wins over local rivals in a matter of days.  The
Blades are now firmly in the playoff positions, one more win from the
last three games might be all that is needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another local side, Chesterfield, are looming large.  It feels like
they will play a part in the rest of our season.  I grew up on the
Chesterfield side of Sheffield, almost equidistant from the two
grounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the Senators were at home to the Pittsburgh Penguins last
night, in what really was a must win game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was also fan appreciation night.  Within 10 seconds of the start
they were 1-0 down.  By 5 minutes in they were 2-0 down and by the end
of the first period it was 3-0.  Oh dear.  Sid Crosby on form and the
young Sens not firing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second period was a different story.  Sens put the Penguins under
pressure, but nothing finding the net, until 5 minutes from the end of
the period.  Pageau managed to sneak one in off one of the Penguin's
skates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;30 seconds into the third period they got a second.  Two minutes from
time they equalised and then Mark Stone fired in the winner in
overtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that is what I call a fan appreciation night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and Blades and Sens both win on the same night, so that hypothesis
is proven ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
</description><category>sufc sens</category><guid>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/blades-and-sens-results-correlated.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 21:48:37 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>