<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Around the world in 80 days (sufc football bermuda)</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://swfiua.github.io/80days/categories/sufc-football-bermuda.xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 14:14:39 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Bermuda 3 Bahamas 0</title><link>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/bermuda-3-bahamas-0.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This afternoon Bermuda were playing Bahamas in a World Cup qualifier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the second leg, but Bermuda, led by Nahki Wells, were already
5-0 win in the Bahamas last Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This game hadn't been generally broadcast in Bermuda.  But we had seen
highlights, and the first many of us knew about the game was via a
banner that was put out on the TV station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a long suffering supporter of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sheffield_United_F.C."&gt;Mighty Blades&lt;/a&gt; I have rarely
been in the position of being able to go to a game, already 5-0 up.  I
have also never been to a World Cup game before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So today we set off early to the game on the moped.  The game was a
sell out, parking was likely to be tricky.  In any case, the build up
to the game would likely be fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was cold.  Not Canada cold, but Bermuda cold.  Cloudy and damp,
windy and looked like it could rain any minute.  The rain held off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The build up to the game was fun too.  Many in the crowd knew one or
more of the players well.  There was excitement that we would see a
few goals, and a slight fear that maybe things could unravel.  And
there were Gombeys :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bermuda did dominate the game from start to finish.  The goalkeeper,
Fredrick Hall, was substited at half-time.  I am guessing that he was
frozen, as the ball boys had all had a lot more work to do.  It was
a good time to give his back-up a chance to play, and he at least had
some saves to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nahki Wells won a penalty, then crashed the resulting kick against the
cross-bar.  This was close to half-time, Bermuda had already had 5-6
really good chances, but the ball didn't want to go in the net.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier Wells had been fouled, about 30 yards out and needed treatment
from the physio.  He was then made to leave the field, and was not
able to be there for the free-kick that required the treatment.
Broken rules?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Justi Donawa had what looked like a painful injury to his foot, and
had to be replaced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second half was more of the same, but Bermuda were increasingly
getting the feeling that it was going to end 0-0.  The players felt it
and the crowd too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then Nahki Wells broke through and this time made no mistake, 1-0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this point every time Bermuda went forward, and that was
frequently, they looked like scoring.  The game ended 3-0.  The Gombey
Warriors will play Guatemala, away on the 8th of June, at home on the
16th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two last things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is a very young Bermuda team.  I heard the average age is
just 21.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Bahamas also have a young team.  They played a good game today,
the game flowed, there were lots of entertaining moments.  It can't
have been easy travelling away already 5-0 down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a great afternoon, two teams, refs and the crowd all played
their part.  Looking forward to the next games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- title: links --&gt;
&lt;!-- slug: references --&gt;
&lt;!-- date: 2014-11-13 14:08:31 UTC --&gt;
&lt;!-- tags: --&gt;
&lt;!-- link: --&gt;
&lt;!-- description: links to include in all posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- type: text --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>sufc football bermuda</category><guid>http://swfiua.github.io/80days/posts/bermuda-3-bahamas-0.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2015 22:34:42 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>