<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Around the world in 80 days (swindon)</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/</link><description></description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" rel="self" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/categories/swindon.xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 18:46:46 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Magic Roundabouts and Geese</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/magic-roundabouts-and-geese.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Growing up as children we would watch The Magic Roundabout on the BBC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a five minute children's program with a carousel, Zebedee,
Dougal the dog and Dylan the rabbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each episode ended with Zebedee saying, "Time for bed", before
springing off, literally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we got older we might watch a bit of the news that followed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="roundabouts-around-the-world"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Roundabouts around the world&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around the world, traffic rules vary quite a bit.  Here are some
examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="france"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;France&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In France roundabouts used to be much less common than in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The early traffic rule was essentially, "priorite a la droite".  This
rule dated back to horses and carriages and mostly they could see each
other coming for a good way, it was simple to slow down and give way
to those from one side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another key rule, is which side of the road to drive on.  The French,
like most of continental Europe, drive on the right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looked at from above, the French go anti-clockwise around
roundabouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when they arrive at one, those already on the roundabout give way
to new arrivals, coming from the right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This works well with light traffic.  With heavy draffic, things can
fall apart: once the roundabout is full of cars nobody can go
anywhere, although if you are just taking the first right then you'll
probably be ok.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="arc-de-triomphe"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Arc de Triomphe&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now this is more like The Magic Roundabout.  I have no idea what the
rules are.   Rumour has it that insurance companies exclude any
accident that happens here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="british-isles"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;British Isles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here they drive on the left and go clockwise round roundabouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give way to those already on the roundabout.  Those already on can
keep going, those arriving have to wait for it to be safe to enter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, like the French you are giving way to those on the right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, it can work well it depends on the traffic volume and pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="swindon"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Swindon&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swindon actually has a Magic Roundabout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a crazy construction of five roundabouts with another roundabout
inside them all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UK rules apply, so once you get on the thing it is like a
roller-coaster, just go with the flow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the accidents happen, people are usually moving pretty slowly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="north-america"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;North America&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roundabouts used to be far less common in North America.  Four-way
stops are the order of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You arrive at the junction and stop.  If no-one else is there then you
can proceed, others arriving after you should give way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now this can lead to the &lt;em&gt;Canadian stand-off&lt;/em&gt;.   You arrive at a
roundabout just as someone else arrives.  There then follows an
elaborate dance where you both just sit there waiting for the other to
go first, often accompanied by hand-gestures.   Dead-lock is not
uncommon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="ottawa"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Ottawa&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a roundabout near the Experimental Farm that itself seems to
be a wonderful experiment in mixing British and French roundabout
rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in the day it was probably a four way stop, a simple cross-roads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's pretend there is a north-south (NS) road crossing east-west (EW)
and the NS is the bigger road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are travelling NS or SN, you can pretent your are French and
drive straight on to the roundabout.  Those coming from an EW
direction will give way to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are turning left, then you will have to give way to traffic
entering on the NS road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now if you arrive on the EW road you have to give way to traffic
already on the roundabout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is a complicated mixture of giving way to the left or right
depending on where you are on the roundabout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="going-backwards-round-the-magic-roundabout"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Going backwards round the magic roundabout&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* please don't try this *&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traffic arriving from east (or west) could do a Pierre Trudeau, behind
the Queen pirouette, turning 180 degrees to enter the roundabout
backwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this way, the &lt;em&gt;give way to traffic on your right&lt;/em&gt; rule ensures the
traffic that you need to giver way to is always coming from your right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once on the roundabout another pirouette should be done, having done
this, again give way to traffic entering from the North/South road,
which is again on your right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also ensures if you exit on this route you are facing the right
way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If continuing around the roundabout, another pirouette should be
performed after passing the north/south road.  Hence, you will again
be going backwards on the magic roundabout.   With your right side to
the centre of the roundabout there is no need to give way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was much younger my mother one night announced she felt a
little typsy.  As a curious child I asked what that was like.  She
said, "it is like I am going backwards on the magic roundabout".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like I said, don't try this on the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="johnny-barnes"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Johnny Barnes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Hamilton, Bermuda there are several roundabouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there is one special one.  It is known as The Johnny Barnes
roundabout and has its own magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is indeed magic.  Every weekday, between 5am and 10am you will see
Johnny Barnes.  He has been waving to traffic and dispensing love
at the roundabout since retiring from the Bus company.  He is now in
his 90's.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bermuda has its own road rules.  Mostly following the British.  But
the horn only really gets used to say &lt;em&gt;hi&lt;/em&gt; to friends and cousins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you see a friend trying to get out of a small side road you might
well follow the "priorite a la droite" rule and wave for them to go
ahead of you, even though you have right of way.  The roads are
narrow, the speed limit is 20 mph and a little give and take makes it
a better place for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if you are new to the island, watch out for vehicles stopping to let
people out of tiny driveways and side roads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-about-the-geese"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What about the geese?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week the Mighty Blades played Swindon.  Those brave fans that
made the journey down to Swindon went there knowing they would have to
negotiate the Magic Roundabout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being Blades fans, they were probably expecting the worst and a heavy
defeat.  I believe all the fans got through the roundabout unscathed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the game, well the new manager, Nigel Adkins, played a
motivational video before the game.  Google "geese sufc" and you
should find it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It explains how geese are able to travel 70% further by flying in a V
formation.  How one goose will lead and when tired drop back into the
formation and let another take the lead.d&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a goose is tiring and struggling, two other strong geese will drop
down to the ocean with the struggler and stay with it until it either
dies or makes a recovery.  They will then fly together to rejoin the
flock, or tag onto another flock following behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="magic-roundabouts-and-mother-geese"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Magic Roundabouts and Mother Geese&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was younger, my mum was my Magic Roundabout.  She would watch
the world circling around her and find ways to change the paths of
those that needed to be on a different path, or gently put together
those that would benefit from each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I now have another Magic Roundabout in my life.  Mum's are magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bermuda</category><category>blades</category><category>france</category><category>ottawa</category><category>roundabouts</category><category>sufc</category><category>swindon</category><guid>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/magic-roundabouts-and-geese.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 14:54:08 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>