<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Around the world in 80 days (weather)</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/categories/weather.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 14:40:07 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Fred Update</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/fred-update.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fred formed way in the east of the Atlantic.  I believe it was already
a hurricane going over the Cape Verde islands.  I was shown pictures
today of seas damaging a pier.  I have not heard too much more about
damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Six years ago, Fred formed around the same area a little further
south, but did not intensify as fast.  It did become a hurricane, then
dissipated as it curled, for a short while was heading easterly, then
got pushed back westward.  By this time it had fallen apart and it
did not get organised again, but the remnants of the storm tracked a
good way across the Atlantic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the discussion of Fred, it is likely to be pulled apart in
the short term.  Then the track forecasts give a range of
possibilities, including heading westward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Latest (5AM AST, 1st September) forecast discussion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.nhc.noaa.gov/text/refresh/MIATCDAT1+shtml/010849.shtml"&gt;http://www.nhc.noaa.gov/text/refresh/MIATCDAT1+shtml/010849.shtml&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These discussions tend to be very helpful in gauging how much
confidence the forecasters about the forecasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, both track and intensity forecasts can be pretty accurate
out to 24 hours or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paragraph from the discussion has a lot of information in it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Fred is expected to move between west-northwest and northwest for
the next 72 hours as a mid-level ridge to the north of the cyclone
gradually builds westward. After that time, a turn toward the
north-northwest and north is forecast due to a deep-layer trough
currently over eastern Canada that is expected to dig
southeastward over the central Atlantic and erode the ridge. The
NHC model guidance is in decent agreement on this developing
pattern change.  However, there are significant differences in the
model solutions with the HWRF, GFS, and GFDL models keeping Fred
stronger and making the northward turn sooner, whereas the weaker
solution models like the UKMET and ECMWF take a weaker and more
vertically shallow cyclone farther west before turning it
northward.  The official forecast track is a little south of the
previous advisory track, mainly due to the more southerly initial
position, and follows a blend of the weaker UKMET and ECMWF
solutions.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end, we learn the current forecast track is further south than
the previous advisory.  The discussion notes this is mostly because
Fred did not move as far north as expected over the previous period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disagreements in models are usually informative, often indicating
there is more uncertainty in the forecast.  Sometimes the forecasters
have good understanding of why the models are disagreeing, different
models have different strengths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="bermuda-weather"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bermuda Weather&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://weather.bm/images/surfaceAnalysis/Latest/Atlantic.gif"&gt;http://weather.bm/images/surfaceAnalysis/Latest/Atlantic.gif&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="wikipedia"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hurricane_Fred_%282015%29"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hurricane_Fred_%282015%29&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hurricane_Fred_%282009%29"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hurricane_Fred_%282009%29&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="national-hurricane-centre"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;National Hurricane Centre&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://weather.bm/images/surfaceAnalysis/Latest/Atlantic.gif"&gt;http://weather.bm/images/surfaceAnalysis/Latest/Atlantic.gif&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014</category><category>2015</category><category>fred</category><category>hurricane</category><category>weather</category><guid>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/fred-update.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:41:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Erika, Andrew, Danny and Fred</title><link>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/erika-andrew-danny-and-fred.html</link><dc:creator>Johnny Gill</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last few weeks the Atlantic hurricane season has got more active.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Danny never really got started, was blown apart by sheer, but no doubt
spawned a lot of thunderstorms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flooding from Erika has resulted in numerous deaths in Domincan
Republic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erika has fallen apart, but again there will be a lot of thunderstorms
along its path.  There is a lot of moisture in the atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="erika"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Erika&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early forecasts had the most likely track heading over Hispanola, Then
curving, but likely being blown apart by sheer from strong upper
atmosphere winds related to El Nino.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is in fact very close to what actually has happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="track-forecast"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Track forecast&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weather models started to suggest the storm would curve more
northerly.  This all involves really complex systems that stretch over
thousands of miles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the models most likely path was more northerly, and that might take
it on a path to hit Florida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At one point the most likely track was heading all up the east coast
of Florida, without making landfall.  If it had held together it might
of intensified over hot water with low windsheer and been a major
storm at landfall in the Carolinas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this period there was always the possibility of heading
over Hispanola, but it wasn't the most likely path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="andrew"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Andrew&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew formed in a similar season to 2015 with a high El Nino.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took a more northerly track, steered north of the Caribbean, then
turned straight into Florida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think a comparison of Andrew and Erika, Danny too, would be
interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="fred"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fred&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hurricane names run on a six year cycle.  So, there are six lists,
that repeat every six years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a storm becomes significant in some way, usually the more intense
and damaging storms that hit land, the name gets &lt;em&gt;retired&lt;/em&gt; from the
list and is forever associated with that storm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, we have Fred.  Now for me, Fred means Fiery Fred Trueman,
Yorkshire and England fast bolwer.  I never saw him play, but often
heard him commentating on test matches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So some day we will see a Fiery Fred storm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A storm named Fred has just formed.  Like Erika, there is a fair
amount of uncertainty on what path it takes and how intense it will
get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="more-information"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;More information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael Johnston has also been blogging about the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://bermudaweather.wordpress.com/2015/08/30/active-tropics/"&gt;recent storms&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>hurricane</category><category>weather</category><guid>http://openbermuda.github.io/80days/posts/erika-andrew-danny-and-fred.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2015 21:39:48 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>